Welcome back to Try Laravel.  In this section, we're going to talk
about views, or what you, the viewer, sees.
Now back at our application stack diagram, let's talk about the next
piece of the puzzle, the views layer.  The views layer is where we
decide how to display our information back to the browser.
From here, we'll set up our templates and layouts that allow us to
format our data with HTML and CSS and a template syntax in Laravel called Blade.
Our views will be in the Resources folder of our project and then in a
folder called views.
Here we'll create a set of folders and files that can be used from
within our application.  Any view specific to a model should live in
their own folder under the views folder.  In this case, we have a view
that's specific to the markets table, so we have a markets folder and
then a view underneath it called show.blade.php.
Blade is the template language that's built into Laravel.
In order to use the Blade syntax and PHP code blocks, we'll have to
name our files with the extension .blade.php.
In this case, it's show.blade.php, which we're going to use to look at
a single market.  Here you can see a standard HTML file at the
beginning and then some new syntax.  If we want to echo information to
the screen, we'll use a set of opening curly braces and then end that
echo with the closing curly braces.  @php is how we start a simple
PHP-only block, and then we would end it with @endphp.
Notice that here we're making a call to our model and find of the ID
of 3, so this page wants to show the ID of 3.
And then we're using the Blade syntax to echo the market name,
the market city, and then an anchor tag to create a link and show the market website.
With no styles, we can see how this page will look rendered to the browser.
Now if we want to show all markets, we're going to create a new file
named index.blade.php and then change the content.
Here you can see inside of our @php tags we're changing it to Market
and a call to all to give us a collection of markets.
Then we're using looping constructs @foreach ($markets as $markets) so
that we can loop through each of the markets in the collection and
show a link to the website of that market.
If you notice, we have some repeated code between our show.blade.php
file and our index.blade.php file, which is our framing HTML.
We'll want to clean up our code as much as possible to dry up our
code, or don't repeat yourself.  Blade helps us do just that by giving
us the ability to create layouts.  In this case, we want to keep our
HTML markup header and the footer the same throughout the project and
just change the content.  We can do that by creating a file called
app.blade.php and placing it in a folder named layouts inside of our views folder.
Then we can define areas for each of our custom views to modify by
defining an @yield tag with the name of the section.
Here I'm calling that section main.  Then, inside of our
index.blade.php file, we can remove all but the content we need for
that page and place a few new items at the top.
The first is the @extends command to tell us that this file is the
extension of the layouts.app file.  The layouts.app string can also be
looked at as a folder, or a slash, in the file path.
Next, we're going to define the section we want to modify with the
@section tag and the string argument of the section name main.
Then at the end of all of our content, or custom code,
we'll close that section with @endsection.
Each new file we create will have an @extends and @section inside of
it so we don't have to repeat our framing HTML code.
In this section, we've learned about creating views.
We've learned about the Blade template syntax and using Blade to
create layouts so that we can dry up our code.
Now it's time for you to take some challenges, and I'll see you in the next level.
Blah, blah, blah, blah.
Or we can (gibberish).
We're getting a (noises).
Once we find a record.