Welcome back to Try Laravel.  In this section, we're going to talk
about routing, or controlling our traffic.
The final layer in our application stack is routing.
Routing is the director of traffic for our entire application.
It sees the URL that comes in from the request and decides where to
send that request in the application based on what we place in our routes file.
The routes file lives in the routes folder at the root of our
application, and any web-based routes will happen in web.php.
Let's go over some simple examples.  The first thing we'll do is use a
new class called Route followed by a static method get.
Get is directly related to the get HTTP method, so as you might
expect, we could also use the post method here.
In this case, we will use get followed by two arguments.
The first argument will be the URL that we're trying to match.
If we use forward slash, we'll be looking for the root path,
or in most cases, the home page, with no other URL information.
The second argument is a callback, or a function to run if this URL is matched.
In this example, I'm using a closure, or anonymous function,
to return a string of Hello World.  The Route class will return this
as an HTTP response with the body of Hello World.
We can also accept arguments in the URL.  The next example,
let's use the URL pattern of market/ followed by the ID as the argument.
To specify an argument, we will use the open and closing curly braces
surrounding the name of our argument.  Then, in our closure,
we'll pass through that same name as an argument variable,
then return in the closure a string containing that ID.
Since we're using controllers, we'll need to pass URL's specific
methods in each controller.  We can do this by sending a string as the
second argument instead of a closure.  This way we're able to handle
the logic from our route in the controller instead of our route's file.
We reference the method in the controller by writing a string
containing the class of the controller, followed by the at sign,
and then the method name.  Let's walk through the examples of a normal
RESTful CRUD routing list.  Many of our get request URLs you have seen
in the first lesson, such as the markets/create to make a new market.
That form will need to post to the markets URL, and we will direct it
to the store method inside of the markets controllers.
Another is when we want to find a specific market by market ID.
Here we use a wildcard to pass the market ID to the show action in our controller.
In the first example, if we were to hit markets/create, that would
direct a get request to the MarketController@create method.
In the second example, if we were to hit markets/3, it would pass
through the ID of 3 to the markets controller show method.
We will also want to edit specific markets.
Here we can add /edit after the market and map that market wildcard to
our edit action inside of the MarketController.
If we want to delete an item, we'll set up a delete route that maps to
the destroy action on the same controller using an ID wildcard.
Laravel makes creating all of these routes even easier for us by
giving us a route method called resource.  Resource routing expects
that a URL pattern will always relate to a specific controller and related model.
This is why naming has been so important to us.
Here, instead of defining each route individually, now we can just use
Route::resource followed by our URL pattern base, which is markets,
and then the controller name with no method specified.
With this single line of code, we now have all of the following routes.
In this section, we've learned about routing with closures,
CRUD routing, and resource routing with models and controllers.
Now it's time for you to take some challenges, and I'll see you in the wrap-up video.
Framework, vlah.
Lara (noises).
Notice we have some ch.
Call our vule, vule.  Is that like zool?