Welcome back.  In this section, we're going to learn about CRUD,
which is really the basics of any database-backed application is to
create, read, update, and delete.
Eloquent helps us create a CRUD-based application very simply.
Let's look at how we accomplish each of these starting with create.
To create a market using the single attribute method, we'll create a
Market object named $m by using the new operator followed by the class name Market.
Then we'll set the property using the object operator followed by name
and set it equal to Winter Garden Market.  Then, to write the entry to
the database, we'll use the save method on the $m Market object.
If we want to create an entry in our database with multiple attributes
such as you might have with submitting a form, we want to use the mass
assignment method of creation.  Here we set up an array with key value
pairs where the key is the property we want to set followed by its intended value.
Normally, this would be handled by the submission of a form,
and it would come back to us in the format of an array.
Then we pass this array to the create method on the class of Market.
Notice we used a static method with the two colon symbols.
This way we do not have to create a new object each time.
Like we did in the previous section, if we want to read data of a
single item, we'll use the method find followed by the ID of the item
we wish to retrieve.  We can also gather all items in the database
with the all method.  If we need to gather information using some
custom constraints, we can us the where method followed by two arguments.
The first argument is the column we want to test against,
and the second is the value we want to find.
Then we'll run that query by sending the get method.
In this query that you see here, we're gathering all markets where the
city is equal to Orlando.  We can get very detailed with our queries.
Here we're using the same Orlando city constraint, and then ordering
the results by the name descending in alphabetical order,
and then taking only the first five of those results.
Here is an example of the results var dumped to the screen.
To update a single item, first we would use the find command just like
before and pass an ID to get the item we'd like to update.
Then we can set the property name to a new value, then run the save
method to write that new data to the database.
We can also update multiple values at the same time by using an array
with key value pairs of the items that we want to change.
In this case, we're going to change the name and the website.
Then we pass this data to the fill method on the $m Market object.
Once we find a record, we can also delete it with the delete method.
If we want to, we can do this in one line and call the static destroy
method with the argument of the ID we want to destroy.
We can also pass an array of IDs to the same destroy static method,
and all of them will be deleted.
Just as a CRUD overview, we can create, read, update, or delete market
data very simply using Eloquent.
In this section, we've learned about Laravel and CRUD,
which is create, read, update, and delete.
We've also learned about mass assignment when creating or updating records.
Now it's time for you to take some challenges, and I'll see you in the next level.