Lettuce head to the farm and get deep into the CRUD.
No need to be alarmed — the data's cleaner than the mud.
We'll pep up our app, yes we will.  It's going to be real swell,
so swell, so swell.  Learning MVC is a snap when you're using Laravel.
Welcome back to Try Laravel.  In this section, we're going to learn
about controllers, or the middle man of our application.
The next section in our application stack happens just before the model.
It's called the controller layer.  Controllers handle our logic.
It will help us pull data from the model and then call our view while
passing along all of the information that we just got from our database.
To define a new controller, we'll need to create a controller named
the same as the model followed by the name Controller in camel case.
Then inside of that controller file we'll extend Larvel's existing Controller class.
These controllers will exist in the app/Http/Controllers folders.
Here are file will be named MarketController.php.
For each route, we'll need a public method, or action.
The index method, or action, will be used to list all of our markets.
We'll make a call to the Market model using the all method returning a
collection of results from the database.  We'll need to send this data
to a view.  We can accomplish this by using the view helper method in Laravel.
The first argument is our view.  Here we're going to the views folder
by default, then the markets folder, and then the index.blade.php file
that we created in the last level.  This second argument will then
pass the collection markets to the view by adding an array with the
key of markets.
Now that we have the model call in the controller, we don't need to
create the markets collection here in the view, so we can remove it.
Since we've passed along the markets from the controller to the view,
everything else will remain the same.
To show a single market within the same controller, we can create a
different method named show, this time with an argument for the single Market item.
Laravel automatically binds the Market object to the ID that's in the
URL so we don't have to run any queries.  If no market is found,
it will generate a 404 for us.  Then our view is the same,
but we're now calling the show template and passing through the
argument key as Market instead of markets.
Again, we just remove the logic that queries the model,
and everything else just keeps working as expected.
In this section, we've learned about controllers for logic,
we've learned about using methods to render views, and how to remove
our logic from our views.  Now it's time to take some challenges,
and I'll see you in the next section.