Lettuce head to the farm and get deep into the CRUD.
No need to be alarmed — the data's cleaner than the mud.
We'll pep up our app, yes we will.  It's going to be real swell,
so swell, so swell.  Learning MVC is a snap when you're using Laravel.
Hello, I'm Hampton Paulk, and welcome to Try Laravel.
We're going to learn about the Laravel framework.
Before we begin, let's take a moment to talk about some prerequisites
for the course.  It will be very helpful to you as you progress
through this course to have a good understanding of the basics of the
PHP language, including some knowledge of object-oriented PHP and
basic database knowledge.  If you'd like to learn these basics or just
have a refresher, please play our Try PHP, Close Encounters With PHP,
and Try SQL courses here at Code School.
Now that we know what we need to get started, let's learn a little bit about Laravel.
Laravel is an open source web framework built in PHP.
It was first released in 2011 by Taylor Otwell and has been heavily
developed ever since.  The current version sits, at the time of this
recording, in version 5.4.  Laravel helps you build web applications
by using the MVC, or Model-View-Controller, architecture pattern.
Laravel also helps us work with databases easily using a mapper called Eloquent.
There's so much to learn, so let's dive in.
To best understand the basics of Laravel, we'll be walking through a
simple database-backed application.  In our example, we'll be working
with a listing of local farmers markets.  We'll be able to list all
markets, or all farms,
create new markets,
view details about each market,
and edit or delete our existing markets.  With these few pages,
we're able to fully manage a database of farms and markets using Laravel.
Just like a spreadsheet, a database will have a table name, some rows,
and some columns just like this example you see here.
In our case, we'll have the name of a market, the website of that
market, and the city that it's located in.
Each item in the row will also have an ID, or the numerical
identification of the location of each market's data.
To work efficiently with data, Laravel has a data type called a collection.
A collection, put simply, is a PHP array with lots of extra functionality.
To create a collection, we could use a helper function called collect,
and then inside that function we'll pass an array as an argument.
This array can be simple as in the first example, or it can be an
array of arrays with key value pairs.  Just like in our data table,
here commas help us separate out rows and columns.
Instead of calling data by requesting a numerically indexed key,
we can use built-in methods to the collection class.
Here we're using first to get the first item in the collection or last
to get the last item of the collection.
What if we only want the name from a larger and more complex collection?
We can use the method fetch followed by the key that we want to fetch.
This will return to us an array of all data associated with that key
for each item.
To retrieve information from our database is our first real challenge.
We want to request an item from our database with the ID of 3 and get
a collection back containing the data for that single entry in the database.
We could always write SQL queries to get the data we want, or we can
accomplish this common task by using the Eloquent ORM.
Eloquent is built for Laravel to help us work with the data in our
database using simple language methods instead of long database query strings.
Here we can access that third record by calling a static method.
Notice the two colons named find and passing it the argument of the ID
of the item we want data on.  In this case, number 3.
The class that we called the method on is Market.
Market is directly tied to the name of our table markets.
By default in Laravel, we'll have an uppercase singular class that
matches the lowercase plural name in the database.
For example, if our table was lowercase markets plural,
our class would be uppercase Market singular.
Once we request the data with the find method, we'll get back a
collection containing the market's information.
Now we can use it like an array, or we can use each key as a property
and access it using the object operator.
So far in this section, we've learned about the Laravel framework,
Laravel's collection class, and reading information from the database
using Laravel's Eloquent.
Now it's time for you to play around with Laravel in the challenges.
Have fun.