Lettuce head to the farm and get deep into the CRUD.
No need to be alarmed — the data's cleaner than the mud.
We'll pep up our app, yes we will.  It's going to be real swell,
so swell, so swell.  Learning MVC is a snap when you're using Laravel.
Welcome back to Try Laravel.  In this section, we're going to talk
about models, or how we interact with our data.
Let's talk about our application stack.  The Laravel framework helps
us separate our logic into four simple areas handling each of the
steps from the moment a user arrives at our URL until we return a
response back to them.  The first of these that we're going to look at
is the model.
The model is where we place our logic on where and how we're going to
interact with our data store.  When we're retrieving information from
the database, like in the last level, we were using the model class in Eloquent.
Let's look at that again now.  The class Market is in a file named
Market.php, and the class extends or inherits from the Eloquent Model class.
And with no other code in the Market.php file, we have tied our class
Market to the markets table in our database.
When we query Market find of 3, we're sending a query to the database
to give us the data in the markets table where the ID is equal to 3.
Let's say we need to make a longer query that only includes the
markets from Orlando, and we need to sort them by the market name in descending order.
If we need to run this query more than a couple times, we should find
a way to make this code cleaner, so how can we do this?
Laravel gives us this ability in the use of local scopes.
We can create custom local scopes by creating a method named scope in
lowercase followed by the uppercase scope name.
Here we're calling it scopeOrlando.  Inside of this new method,
scopeOrlando, we'll simply return the query that we had in the previous slide.
When we need to run this query, we can just make a static call to the
scope name without the word scope.  Here it's just orlando followed by
the get method to run the query to get our custom results.
In this section, you've learned about creating models with Laravel's
Eloquent in order to communicate with our database.
You've also learned about local scopes in Eloquent to help us with
longer more complicated queries that you might need to run more often.
Now it's time for you to take some challenges, and I'll see you in the next section.