Gather all the elements to learn Elixir with our guidance.  Functional programs you will code,
turning the knowledge into gold.  Become a master mixer as you stir it all up with Elixir.
You're watching Mixing It Up With Elixir.  I'm Carlos Sosa and in this level we'll learn about tuples.
A tuple is a data structure used for working with ordered collections of elements, typically used
as return values from functions.  We use curly braces to represent them.
This is an example of a valid tuple with three elements, first one is an atom, functional.
Second is a string, elixir, and third is an integer, 2012.  Tuples can hold many elements for many different types,
but we typically work with two element tuples where the first element is an atom, like these two.
Here we have a tuple with the ok atom as the first element and a string, some content, as the second element.
And then with a tuple with the error atom as the first element and another atom as the second element,
enoent, representing an error for unknown file, something we'll typically run into multiple times when writing
Elixir programs.
One way to read elements from tuples is using pattern matching.
In this example we have a tuple with the atom ok and the string some content on the right.
Then on the left we have another tuple, but with two variables, status and content.
Using the match operator or the equal sign, we can pattern match the ok atom with the status variable
in the string, some content, with the variable content.  A similar match happens in the second example,
first we successfully matched the two error atoms on both sides of the match operator.
Then we matched the variable, message, with a string some error occurred.
Now that we're familiar with the structure of tuples and how to read values from them, let's look at a
more practical example using tuples and functions.  In this example we'll use the File.read function
from Elixir's standard library.  This function reads the content of a given file from the local file system.
What we get back as a return value is a tuple with two elements, an atom representing the status of the operation
and either the content of the file or the error type that prevented the operation from taking place.
So when we call it with a valid file, we get back a tuple with the ok atom and the content as the second argument.
If we try pattern matching the same ok atom on a call to File.read with a file that does not exist, then
we'll run into a MatchError like this.  For a correct match to occur here, we would need to use an error atom,
like this.  But in reality we won't know whether a file exists until we run our program.
So let's see how we can make this operation a bit more dynamic.
Tuples can be used as function arguments and pattern matched against values passed in during function calls.
Let's look at this example.
Here we have a module account and a parse_file function with two clauses.
The first clause expects a tuple with the first element being the ok atom.
This matches the result of a successful file read operation and the contents of the file are assigned
to the variable content.  The second clause expects a tuple with the first element being the error atom.
This one matches an unsuccessful file read operation and the error type is assigned to the variable error.
Now let's run this code and see what happens.  We'll call File.read, giving it an existing file,
transactions.csv.  We'll pipe the result of this function call to our newly created Account.parse file function.
Remember how the pipe operator works?  In this case the return value from the call to File.read will become
the first and only argument to Account.parse file.  The result tuple matches the first clause with the ok atom
and we see a list of transactions printed to the console.  Now when we run this code, giving File.read
a file path that does not exist, the return value will be a tuple with the error atom as its first element.
This matches the second clause of the parse_file function and we see the message Error parsing file printed
to the console.  Notice, however, that above the message we also see a warning saying that the error variable
is not being used.  Now warnings will not stop our programs from running, but it's best that we tackle them
as soon as possible to prevent future issues from happening.
To remove this warning we can use the underscore character.  This character is used to explicitly ignore
unused values and avoid compiler warnings.  Now our program simply prints the message Error parsing file
and we have no compiler warnings.
And that's it for this first section.  Now it's you turn to practice some tuples in the challenges.