You're watching Mixing It Up With Elixir.  I'm Carlos Sosa and in this last section we'll learn how to work
with third party dependencies in mix projects.
We want to add a new functionality to our project.  This involves converting and amount from euro to dollar.
We'll create a new function called from euro to dollar and once we're done, here's how we use it.
We'll run the mix run command with a -e option, then we'll pass it to the code to be evaluated and we want to
see the dollar amount printed to the console.  Under the hood, here's what's going to happen.
First we invoke mix run from the console, which will compile and run the Elixir code.
During the code execution we'll access an external web service API to fetch the currency rates.
We'll get a JSON response back, parse it and perform the conversion.
Lastly, we print the result to the console.  Now this might seem complicated, but we'll break it down
into multiple steps.  Let's see how we can do this.
The new function from euro to dollar takes a single argument and it's part of the conversion module,
which itself is a submodule of Budget.  We need to manually create both the budget directory and the
conversion.ex file.
In order to make the API call we'll need two dependencies, one for making the web service call and another one
for parsing the JSON response back.  Now let's see how we can add these dependencies to our project.
To declare dependencies we use the mix.exs file.  The deps function inside this file returns a list of tuples
with the names and versions of the dependencies we need.  In this example we have two tuples, one for the
httpoison library, the HTTP client, and one for the poison client, the JSON parser.
As we can see, the first element of each tuple is the name of the library as an atom.
The second element of the tuple is the version of the library following the semantic versioning format.
Once that is done, we now need to install these dependencies.  To do that, we go back the console
and run the command mix deps.get.  This command fetches the dependencies from a remote repository
and installs them locally under the deps directory.
Here we are back to our function.  We create the URL variable and give it the URL of the remote server
that we'll use to fetch the rates from.  Then we'll call the httpoison.get function with this URL,
as part of a case statement.  For this statement we'll give it two patterns to test against.
One will match successful responses, a tuple with the ok atom as its first element and an empty variable
response as the second element.  The other pattern will match unsuccessful responses, a tuple with the error atom
as its first element and an underscore as the second element, meaning we want to ignore it.
For successful responses we'll pass the response itself to the parse function, then we'll pipe the result
of that to the convert function, which also takes the initial amount as argument and returns the final amount
converted to dollar.  For unsuccessful responses, we'll simply print the message Error fetching rates.
Let's move on to the parse function now.
On the signature of the parse function, we can use pattern matching to read the body of the response
that's passed as an argument.  A successful response from httpoison will be a map with the status_code key
set to 200, so we match on that, and then match on the body with the variable json_response.
Inside the function we use the poison library to parse JSON to an Elixir tuple and return that from the
parse function.  Notice we're using defp here to define the function, and this means it's a private function
and it's not meant to be called from outside this module.  Now before we move over to the convert function,
let's take a look at the parsing that's happening from another angle.
The response we get back from the currency rates web service is a JSON response, basically pure text.
And it looks like this here at the top.  We send that to the parse function, which converts JSON
to an Elixir tuple that looks like this here at the bottom.  As you can see, it's a tuple with two elements,
the first one is the atom ok and the second one is a list of maps.
Each map contains the keys currency and rate, which we'll use next.
This entire tuple is the value that will be piped to the convert function and used as its first argument.
The convert function grabs the list of rates using pattern matching.
Remember the first element of the tuple is okay.  So that's a successful match.
Then we match the list of rates with the variable rates.  Inside the function, we'll call a new function
called fine_euro with a list of rates and the return value from that function should be the rate that we want,
in this case for euro.  We assign that to the rate variable and lastly we perform the conversion.
Now let's look at the find_euro function, which is actually my favorite part of this code.
The find euro function needs to loop through all the rates that were returned by the server and find the one
for euro.  But remember, there are no loops in Elixir, but instead there is recursion and pattern matching.
We'll define three clauses for the find_euro function.  First one is a success case, it splits the list
and finds a successful match when the first element from the list of maps is a map with the currency key
set to euro.  When this happens we assign the rate to the rate variable and simply return that from the function.
If the first clause doesn’t match and there are still maps remaining on the list, then the second clause
will match.  We can ignore the first map on the list using the underscore character since we know for a fact
it doesn’t have a currency set to euro and instead focus on the remaining maps on the list assigned
to the tail variable.  Using this variable we call find_euro again and this is where the recursion happens.
We'll keep calling this function until we either reach the end of the list or until we find a match.
If we do end up reaching the end of the list, it will match on the third clause.
We don’t expect to ever get a list of rates where euro is not present, so if that happens, we'll consider it
a critical situation and raise an error, No rate found for Euro.
And that is all of our code.  Let's run it now.
We'll use mix run -e, giving it Budget.Conversion.from_euro_to_dollar and the number 15 and we'll pipe
the result to IO.puts.  We can see the program properly prints the converted rate to the console.
Now if for some reason the remote server is down and we run our program, we can see it properly prints
the message, Error fetching rates.
We've reached the end of this level and the end of the course.  However, there are still some challenges left
for you to do.  Once you're done with them we'll see you back in the wrap up video.
Unknown, representing a none, a none!
Operation blah.
Explicitly blah.
That we were in blah.
State, we could.
Boom.
Break it down for you, hit you with some knowledge.
Challenges left, so go ahead and do them.