Gather all the elements to learn Elixir with our guidance.  Functional programs you will code,
turning the knowledge into gold.  Become a master mixer as you stir it all up with Elixir.
You're watching Mixing It Up With Elixir.  I'm Carlos Sosa and in this level we'll learn how to work
with lists and recursion.
We know we can use pattern matching and lists to read individual elements, like this.
Here we create a list with three elements, three strings, Elixir, JavaScript, and Ruby, and then assign this list
to a new variable called languages.  We then use pattern matching here on the left side of the equal sign
to read individual elements from the languages variable.  Elixir is assigned to first, JavaScript to second,
and Ruby to third.  However, when we start with lists with more elements, we'll find out pattern matching alone
cannot help us.
We need a way to access the first element and then all remaining elements from the list at once.
To do that we use the cons operator.
The cons operator splits a list into two parts, head, which is the first element, and then tail, which is
a list with all remaining elements from the original list.  In this example the variable head is the string Elixir
and tail is a new list with the strings JavaScript and Ruby.  If all we want is the first element from a list,
like in the second example, we can store the string Elixir on the variable head and use the cons operator
to split the rest of the list and then ignore the remaining elements with the underscore character to avoid
compiler warnings.
The cons operator can also be used in function pattern matching.
Let's look at the following example.  Here we have a language module with a print_list function.
This function takes a list as an argument, using pattern matching we split the list into head, the first element,
and tail, the new list with the remaining elements.  When we call this function passing it a list with
three strings, it prints the following - Head: Elixir and Tail: JavaScriptRuby.
One thing that might come as a surprise for developers new to functional programming is that there are no
for loops in Elixir.  That's right, there are no for loops.
We've learned how to use the cons operator to split a list into an element in a new list, an output code
like this on the left.  But what if we wanted to print each individual element, like here on the right?
How can we do that without using a for loop?  The answer is recursion.
Recursive functions are functions that perform operations and then invoke themselves again.
This is what a recursive version of our previous code looks like, it's composed of two clauses of the print_list
function.  The first clause is matched when we call it with a nonempty list, it prints the first element
from the list assigned to the head variable and then invokes itself again with the remaining elements
assigned to the tail variable.  It repeats this process until we run out of elements and the tail variable
is assigned an empty list.  When this happens the next call to print_list matches the second clause of the function,
which returns nothing and does not invoke itself again.  That's when the program is done.
All recursive functions involve the following two cases or two clauses,
the first one is the base case, also called the terminating scenario, which is the last step where the function
does not invoke itself.  In this example, it's the clause where it print_list takes an empty list as an argument
and does nothing.  The second case is the recursive case.  This is where some computation happens, in our example
where we print the element to the console and then our function invokes itself again by calling print_list
with the remaining elements of the list assigned to the tail variable.
Recursion can be a little hard to understand.  So let's look at it at a different way, using some visuals
to understand what's going on behind the scenes.
Here we have a list with three elements, three blue circles.  The first time we call the print_list function,
the first blue circle in the list becomes the red circle and the remaining two circles are grouped under
a new list.  The red circle is spread into the console and the two remaining blue circles are used as
arguments to the second call to print_list.  Once this function is called, the first circle of the list
becomes the red circle and the remaining blue circle becomes the single element of the new list.
Then, the red circle is printed to the console and the list with the single blue circle is used as argument
to the next call to print_list.  Then the only remaining circle of the list becomes the red circle
and it's printed to the console.  We call print_list one last time passing it an empty list, this call
matches the second clause of the print_list function, expecting an empty list as the argument.
This clause does nothing and the execution finishes.
This is recursion behind the scenes and that's how we can write loops in Elixir using a combination of the
cons operator, pattern matching and recursion.
Now we can go back and invoke print_list with a list with three elements, three strings, Elixir, JavaScript,
and Ruby and we can see them printed to the console.
We've reached the end of this level, now it's your turn to practice some lists and recursion in the challenges.