You're watching Mixing It Up With Elixir.  I'm Carlos Sosa and in this section we'll learn about control flow
using the cond statement.
Let's write a new function to transfer money between accounts.  This new function will be part of the
Account module and will be called transfer_amount.  It will take three arguments, the origin account,
the destination account, and the amount to be transferred.  Upon a successful transfer the function returns
a tuple with the ok atom and the transferred amount.  If the transfer is not successful, say due to an invalid
amount, then what we get back is a tuple with the error atom and a string describing the error.
Let's see how we might implement this function.
Here's the function definition.  We have our Account module and the transfer_amount function with three
arguments, from_account, to_account, and amount.  Now before we perform the actual transfer with the
perform_transfer function that's defined elsewhere in the module, we have to perform a validation.
This validation depends on the amount that's being transferred and the hour of the day that this operation
is taking place.  The first thing we do in the function is grab the hour of the day.
We do that by using the DateTime module from Elixir's standard library calling DateTime.utc_now.hour
returns the current hour of the day in utc, a standard and agreed upon time zone across the world.
We assign this value to the hour of the day variable and pass that, along with the amount, to the
valid_transfer function.  If this function returns false, then the exclamation point negates the value
and the if block is run, returning the tuple with an error atom and the string Invalid Transfer.
Otherwise in case the transfer is valid, then we'll invoke the perform_transfer function, which we won't
be going into details, but just know it's there.
The logic for the valid_transfer function is as follows.  If it's morning time, before noon, then we can
transfer up to, but no more than $5000.  In the afternoon, until before 6pm, we can transfer no more than $1000.
In the evening after 6pm we can transfer no more than $300.  Let's see how we can implement this in Elixir.
We could implement this using multiple nested if statements and, I know, we've just learned that it's not
ideal, but let's see how that might look anyway.
Here we first check if hourOfDay is less than 12.  If so, we see if amount is less than or equal to 5000
and return the result.  Then on the else block we check if hourOfDay is less than 18 or 6pm and if so
check if the amount is less than or equal to 1000 and return.  Lastly, if hourOfDay is greater than 18,
or 6pm, we check if amount is less than or equal to 300 and return.
This is valid code, but as we've learned before, it's hard to read and complicated to maintain.
Let's see how we can rewrite this using the cond statement.
The cond statement checks multiple conditions and finds the first one that evaluates to true.
Here's that same code refactored to use the cond statement.  Inside the do en bloc, each line has a condition
to be evaluated on the left of the arrow.  The first condition that returns true will have its right hand side
evaluated and returned as the result of the enclosing function, in this case, the valid_transfer function.
In this example the cond statement has three lines, the first two check hourOfDay against the numbers 12 and 18.
The third line has a true value hardcoded and this acts as a catch all in case none of the previous conditions
are evaluated to true.  It is a good practice to have a hard coded true condition as the last line like this
because the cond statement will raise an error in case none of the conditions are met.
Our function is now complete and with the proper validations in place.
We run two transfers, 150.50 and 980 and they complete with success.
But if we try and transfer 1500 in the afternoon we'll see the error message for an Invalid Transfer.
Now you before you move on to the challenges, here's a quick summary to help understand the differences
between the case and the cond statements.  We use case for matching on multiple patterns.
Here in this first example the tuple is ok and content and error and type Aurelia the two patterns we're testing
against.  We use cond for checking multiple conditions.  Here in the second example the first condition
is when hourOfDay is less than 12.  The second condition is when it's less than 18.
And the third condition will always evaluate to true and will be run when the first two conditions are not met.
This is the end of this level.  Now it's your turn to practice some cond statements in the challenges.