You're watching Mixing It Up With Elixir.  I'm Carlos Sosa and in this section we'll learn about
keyword lists and default values.
Say we have an existing balance function from the account module and this function prints an amount based on
a list of transactions given as an argument, like this.  We run Account.balance, giving it some transactions,
and it prints the message Balance: 200, for example.  Now what if we want to pass formatting options
to allow us to work with different currencies, like currency names, like dollars, euros and pounds,
and also their corresponding symbols?  Ideally what we want is for the balance function to take options
in addition to the list of transactions.  This way we could add more flexibility to our function without
hard coding all the different possibilities.
To do this we use something called a keyword list.  A keyword list is a list of two-value tuples, typically used
as the last argument to functions representing options that we can pass to them, which is exactly what we need.
This is what it looks like when using a keyword list on a function call.
In this first example, we give the currency option the value dollar and the symbol option the dollar sign.
This syntax might look a bit weird at first without the square brackets and curly braces, but this is just
a shortcut Elixir gives us to write cleaner code.  Behind the scenes it is the same thing as writing two tuples
with the brackets and braces like we see on the second line.
To read values from keyword lists, we can use the square brackets notation.
Let's see what that looks like in our balance function.
First thing we do is add a second argument to our function and call it options.
This variable will receive the formatting options in the form of a keyword list.
Then from inside the function, we refer to the options variable and pass the name of the key we want to
read the value from inside square brackets, like this.  This first line returns the value for the currency key
and we assign it to a new variable named currency.  On the following line we do the same thing to read
the value for the symbol key and assign it to a new variable symbol.
We get the balance from the transactions using the calculate_balance function defined elsewhere in this module
in which we won't worry about for now.  We store the result in the variable balance.
Finally, we use currency, symbol, and balance to compose the final string, using string interpolation.
Our code is now ready to accept formatting options.  So if we call it with currency set to euros and the
symbol set to the euros symbol, we can see it prints the expected message to the console.
However, as it is, we must pass options to the balance function.
If we try calling it with just a list of transactions, we'll run into an error like this, UndefinedFunctionError.
Elixir is basically trying to find a balance function that takes a single argument, but instead it can only
find one that takes two arguments.
To fix this we'll set a default value for the options variable, which will be used when we call this function
with just the first argument.  The double backslash symbol is used to define a default value, which in this case
will be an empty list.  If we run the code as it, you won't raise errors anymore, but notice it's now missing
the options.  No values are being returned when reading the currency and symbol keys.
To fix this, we'll use the logical or operator, represented by the double pipe.
This operator can be used to return a default value when the value to the left of the operator is evaluated to false,
or in this example, when a key is not present.  So now the first line inside the balance function can be
interpreted as return the value assigned to the currency key or if this key is not present and no value is returned,
then return the string dollar, whichever value is returned is assigned to the currency variable.
The same thing happens on the second line when reading the value for the symbol key.
In both cases, if the left side of the double pipe does not return a value, then we return the value
on the right side.  Now when we call the Account.balance function again with just a list of transactions,
it uses the proper defaults for the options argument and the default value for each one of the keys.
Keyword lists are widely used in Elixir for passing optional values to functions.
One popular library that uses keyword lists as part of its API, it's called Ecto, a library used for working
with databases.  Here's an example of code using Ecto to build a query.
The where options here are keyword lists and the Elixir code above is translated to the SQL Select statement below.
And that's it for this section.  Now it's your turn to play around with keyword lists and default values in the challenges.