Gather all the elements to learn Elixir with our guidance.  Functional programs you will code,
turning the knowledge into gold.  Become a master mixer as you stir it all up with Elixir.
Welcome to Mixing It Up With Elixir.  I'm Carlos Sosa and in this first level we'll learn about anonymous functions.
We say that in Elixir functions are first-class citizens, but what does that mean?
Well it means a couple of different things, but most importantly these two.
It means functions can be assigned to variables.  We can create them anonymously and then bind them to variables
so they can be invoked later.  Functions can be passed around as arguments to other functions, just like
we're used to doing with other data types like strings and numbers.
This allows for some really cool techniques found in many real world Elixir applications.
Let's take a look.
First, here's what we already know about functions in Elixir.  The functions we've worked with so far
have a name, like in this example max_balance, and belong to an enclosing module, like Account.
In order to call them, we use the module name followed by a dot followed by the function name.
Any arguments are passed inside of parenthesis.  When we run this code we can see it prints Max: 500.
Unlike named functions, anonymous functions have no name and no module.
To create them we use a new syntax we haven’t seen before, the fn arrow syntax.
In this first example we create an anonymous function that expects one argument, amount.
Remember, Elixir is a dynamic language, so we don’t have to declare the data type for this argument or
for the return value of this function.  After the arrow we define the function body.
It's a string, Max:, followed by the argument passed to the anonymous function.
We finish the definition with the end keyword.  Anonymous functions can be assigned to variables, so we assign
it to a new variable called max_balance.  In order to invoke anonymous functions, we must use the dot parenthesis
syntax.  Here's what that looks like.  We use the name of the variable that our function is assigned to,
in this case max_balance, followed by a dot and then the parenthesis.
In this example we're passing 500 as the argument.  When we run this code we can see it prints Max: 500.
Because we've stated that this function expects an argument, every time we call it we must pass this argument,
otherwise we'll run into an error like this, BadArityError.
One way we can use anonymous functions in Elixir is to decouple logic around performing a task from the logic
for the task itself.  In this example we have a run_transaction function.
This function takes arguments and it's responsible for running a given transaction.
We could make it so the logic for each type of transaction, like deposit and withdrawal, is passed an argument
in the form of a function so that the run_transaction function is decoupled from the logic for individual
transaction.  Decoupled code leads to fine grain systems where logic for each part of the system is silo'd
and independent from other parts.  Now that we understand the reason, let's see how we can implement
the run_transaction function.
Here we have our Account module and the definition for the run_transaction function, expecting three arguments,
balance, amount, and transaction.  Balance and amount will be numbers.
Transaction will be a function, but as we can see, it looks just like any other argument.
There's nothing special about it in our function definition.  First thing we do inside run_transaction
is check to see if the balance is less than or equal to 0, and if it is we must not allow any transaction
to be performed.  So we write an if statement and use the balance variable to check if it's less than
or equal to 0.  If so, we'll return a string, Cannot perform any transaction, and then be done with the function.
Otherwise, we call the function stored in the transaction variable, giving it two arguments, balance and amount.
Here the if statement represents the logic around performing the transaction, which is decoupled from the
logic for performing the actual transaction.  Now let's see how we can implement our different transactions.
We'll create one anonymous function for each transaction.  Both will take two arguments, balance and amount.
The first one adds balance to amount and we assign it to the deposit variable.
The second one subtracts amount from balance and we assign it to the withdraw variable.
We've learned that we can pass anonymous functions around as arguments, just like we do with other data types.
So if we call Account.run_transaction with 1000 and 20 as the first 2 arguments and then give the function
assigned to the withdrawal variable as the third argument, we'll see 980 printed to the console, the subtraction
of amount from balance.  And if we call run_transaction with the same 1000 and 20 as the first 2 arguments,
but give it deposit as the third argument, we can see it prints 1020, the addition of balance and account.
Lastly, if we try running this function with balance 0, it will not perform the function given as the third argument
and will instead print the message Cannot perform any transaction, as expected.
Similar to named functions, anonymous functions can also be split into multiple clauses using pattern matching.
In this example we create an anonymous function with two clauses, both take balance and amount as the
first two arguments, but one takes the deposit atom as the third argument and the other takes the withdrawal
atom as the third argument.  Notice that when defining multiple clauses for an anonymous function, the
arrow sign goes after the argument list and not immediately after the fn keyword.
We assign our anonymous function to a new variable called account_transaction and call it just like before
with the dot paren syntax, calling it with a deposit atom matches the first clause and returns the sum
of 100 and 40, 140, calling it with the withdrawal atom matches the second clause and returns the subtraction
of 40 from 100, which is 60.
Because anonymous functions are widely used in Elixir, there's a shorthand for writing them using the
ampersand operator.  Here's our function from earlier which takes two arguments and adds them together.
This same function can be written using the ampersand operator, like this.
We use ampersand followed by parenthesis.  This turns the expression inside the parenthesis into a function.
Then we reference each argument with the ampersand operator again, followed by the number of the argument,
in this example ampersand 1 represents the first argument and ampersand 2 represents the second argument.
Just like the longer version, the short version can also be assigned to a variable and passed around
as an argument to other functions.  So if we call run_transaction giving it the deposit variable as the
third argument, we can see in parens the expected result.
This shorthand version of anonymous functions can also be found used inline as arguments to other functions.
In this example we're not even assigning the function to a variable, but instead just inlining the body
of the function as the third argument to run_transaction.  Running this gives us the same result as before,
the sum of 1000 and 20, 1020.  Here's another example of the shorthand inline version of anonymous functions.
This one using enum.map from Elixir's standard library.  This function takes two arguments and returns a new list.
The first argument to the map function is a list of elements and the second argument is a function that will be
called with each one of the elements from the first argument.  The function we are defining inline here
multiplies its argument by 2 and the result of calling Enum.map is a list with each one of these elements
from the first argument multiplied by 2, so 2, 4, 6, and 8.
That's it for this first level.  Now it's your turn to practice anonymous functions in the challenges.