You're watching Mixing It Up With Elixir.  I'm Carlos Sosa and in this section we'll learn about maps.
In Elixir we use maps when we want to work with a collection of key-value pairs, commonly used to represent
a structure with named fields, like in this example.  Say we want to create a representation of a person
with name and age, we use curly braces with a percent sign to create a map and then each entry is composed of
a key and a value.  Here we have a map with two entries, name set to Brooke, and age set to 42.
To read values from a map, we can use the fetch function from the map module, available in Elixir's
standard library.  Now there are two version of this function, so let's check it out.
Map.fetch takes a map as the first argument and a key as the second argument and returns a tuple
when the key is present.  In this first example we fetch the name key from the map and what we get back
is a tuple with the atom ok and the value Brooke.  Now if we try and fetch a key that's not part of the map,
what we get back is a single atom, error.  There's another way to call Map.fetch, which includes an
exclamation point at the end.  So calling it with the person map and the name key as the argument,
what we get back is the string Brooke.  Now if the key is not present, Elixir raises an error like this one,
saying the key is not found in the map used as argument.  So notice the subtle difference, in the first version
where the key is present it returns a tuple, when the key is not present it returns an atom.
In the second version, when the key is present, it returns just the value, but if the key is not present,
it raises an error.
Another way that we can read from maps in Elixir is using, wait for it, pattern matching.
Here we have the same person map on the first line.  On the second line we use the person variable
on the right hand side and on the left hand side we define a map with the keys name and age and use
variables for the values.  This will cause the values for name and age on the right hand side to be matched
against the empty variables on the left hand side.  If we print the name variable, we can see Brooke
printed to the console.  But here's that warning again, age is unused.
Now we could replace the age variable with an underscore character, but if all we want to read from this map
is the name key, there's something else we can do.
Unlike tuples, with maps we can pattern match on only the portions that we're interested in.
So let's get rid of the warning, we'll use a map with just the name key.
We'll run this code again and we can see the string Brooke and no warnings this time.
Remember only maps support partial match, so if we try writing a similar code by using tuples, we'll run
into an error like this.
Maps support some pretty advanced pattern matching techniques, allowing us to match some keys that are
deeply nested within their structure.  In this example we've expanded our first map to include a key
for address.  The value for this key is itself another map with keys for city and state.
If we wanted to read just the state, we could do something like this.
Here on the left hand side we write just the portion of the map that's necessary to get to the stage key.
Notice we're not using the name key nor the city key from inside the address.
When we run this code we can see it properly prints the value for state.
If this is the first time that you're seeing maps and keyword lists, then you're probably questioning
when to use each.  This is a common question when learning Elixir, so here's a quick rule of thumb
that can help us determine which one to use.
We should use keyword lists when we want to pass optional values to functions, like we did with the
Account.balance function.  And we should use maps when we need a simple and efficient key value storage,
like we did to represent a person with name and age.
It's end of this level.  Now it's your turn to play with maps in the challenges.