Gather all the elements to learn Elixir with our guidance.  Functional programs you will code,
turning the knowledge into gold.  Become a master mixer as you stir it all up with Elixir.
You're watching Mixing It Up With Elixir.  I'm Carlos Sosa and in this section we'll learn about control flow
with the case statement.
Here we have a function list_transactions from the Account module.
This function takes a file name as argument and lists its transactions.
From inside the function we call File.read and use pattern matching to assign the return value to the result
and content variables.  Now unlike our previous example where we used two function clauses to determine
whether the file.read operation was successful, in this one we're using an if statement and checking
the result variable against the ok atom and the error atom.  This code works, but notice how we repeat
the variables result and content twice and how we have nested if statements.
This is a code smell, it can make our programs hard to evolve and complicated to maintain.
Whenever we find ourselves used nested if statements like this, then it's time to refactor and instead use
the case statement.
The case statement tests a value against a set of patterns, here's how it works.
The new variable result assigned to from the call to File.read is the value to be tested.
Inside the do en bloc, we'll list the patterns we want to test against, the ok atom representing a successful
operation and then error atom representing an unsuccessful operation.
After each pattern we use the arrow sign and to the right of it we have the code that should be run
for each pattern.  The first one will return the string Content: followed by the content of the file
that was just read from.  And the second one will return the string Error: followed by the error that
prevented the file.read operation from taking place, also assigned to the content variable.
This version is better than using nested ifs, but notice one thing here.
Using the result variable as the test value for the case statement is also leading to the use of the same
variable name for the content of the file and for the error.  Here on the second line we have the error type
and not the contents of the file.  So the variable name here is sort of misleading.
Let's see how we can fix that.
Turns out the case statement accepts tuples for both the test values and for the patterns to be tested against
and this gives us the flexibility we need to name variables.  So instead of assigning to temporary variables,
we'll move the call to file.read over and use its return value as the new test value.
Then we'll use tuples for each one of the patterns that we want to test against.
First one matches the ok atom first and assigns the content to the content variable.
And the second one matches the error atom first and assigns the error type to the type variable, a much more meaningful name.
Now when we run our code, passing a file, transactions.dsv, the case statement finds a match on the first
tuple and we see the list of transactions printed to the console.
When we run it with a file that does not exist, then the case statement finds a match on the second tuple
and prints the error type to the console, enoent.
The case statement allows extra conditions to be specified with a guard clause.
Let's see what that looks like by adding a new pattern to the top of the list.
The new pattern will be for a successful file.read operation with the first atom being ok, but we want this one
to be matched only when the file is greater than 10 bytes.  To do this we use the byte_size function.
This function is build into Elixir, which is why we can call it without an enclosing module.
If there's a match with the first pattern and the guard clause returns true, then we'll print the string
Content: but instead of printing the list of transactions, we'll print parenthesis with these three dots.
We run our code again, passing it a file with a long list of transactions.
It matches on the first pattern and prints the new message to the screen.
This is the end of this first section.  Now it's your turn to practice the case statement on the challenges.