Gather all the elements to learn Elixir with our guidance.  Functional programs you will code,
turning the knowledge into gold.  Become a master mixer as you stir it all up with Elixir.
You're watching Mixing It Up With Elixir.  I'm Carlos Sosa and in this section we'll learn how to use
the mix tool to run tasks and keep our elixir projects organized.
Keeping a well organized project and adopting a standard for project organization can help in many ways.
Here are three major benefits.  First, it makes it easier for us developers to navigate project files.
We can find existing files easier and spend little time figuring out where to place newly created files.
It facilitates collaboration from other developers on the team by allowing conversations to revolve around
the core logic of the application rather than on naming conventions, directory structure, and what not.
And having a standard structure across different Elixir projects facilitates onboarding new members to the team.
Being already familiar with the structure of the project, new members can start being productive in little time.
Elixir ships with a tool called Mix, a build tool which provides tasks for compiling, running, testing Elixir
projects, managing third party dependencies and more.  To create a new Elixir project using Mix, we run
mix new from the command line followed by the name of the project.
Mix will create a new directory with an initial set of files and subdirectories, just enough to get started
with a well structured Elixir project.  Now let's go ahead and implement a simple function on our newly created project.
We'll define a new function called current_balance, part of the Budget module.
This module was created for us by the mix new command.  The name of the module and the file name where it lives,
under the lib folder, were inferred by the argument given to the mix new command.
The current_balance function takes two arguments, initial and spending, and returns the subtraction of spending from initial.
To run this function from the command line we can use the mix run command.
The -e option tells mix run to evaluate a given code in the context of the application.
We run this command, passing it the call to Budget.current_balance with two arguments, 100 and 20, and then
piping the result to IO.puts.  We see the result printed to the console, 80.
Notice that before the actual result, there's a message saying compiling 1 file.
Now this compilation from Elixir's source code to bytecode is also part of the mix run command.
Here's what this command does.  First it compiles the application generating bytecode.
Next it loads the generated bytecode into the Erlang Virtual Machine.
Then it detects the -e option and evaluates the argument given to it an Elixir code.
Now the files that we've worked with so far have all been .exs.
So what is up with this .ex type file?
Both .ex and .exs file extensions are treated the same way, the difference is intention.
.ex files generate production artifacts in the form of beam files.
Examples include core logic modules found under the lib subdirectory.
.exs files do not generate production artifacts and are used for scripting, like in configuration files and test files.
Mix new and mix run are just the tip of the iceberg.  There are many other tasks available right out of the box.
To see the list of all available tasks we can use the mix help command.
That's it for this first section.  Now it's your turn to mix things up in the challenges.