Lettuce head to the farm
and get deep into the CRUD
No need to be alarmed—
our data's cleaner than the mud.
We'll pep up our app, yes we will, it's gonna be real swell.
So swell, so swell.
Learning MVC is a snap when you're using Laravel.
Welcome back to From Form to Table with Laravel.
This level is all about setting up our database.
To set up our database, we're going to need to configure the database
connection information, create our actual database with MySQL,
and then run our migration to set up our table and columns.
To create our database, we'll use the MySQL command line tool or CLI.
If you don't have MySQL installed on your machine, you can go to the
link below to get directions on how to install a local development copy.
Start by typing mysql -u, and then the username, which is root,
and then -p to signal that you want to use a password for access.
Enter your root user password for MySQL, and then press Enter.
This will place you inside of the MySQL monitor.
Then we're going to run the command create database market followed by
a semicolon.  This instructs MySQL to create a database named market.
Once we've done this, we can type exit to exit the CLI.
Now that our database has been created, we'll need to configure
Laravel to use the market database.  We'll accomplish this by using a
.env or environment file.  Our .env file can be found in the root
folder of our project, and it already has some configurations set up
for us by default.  We'll need to change the database field to reflect
our database name, which is market.  We'll also need to enter our
user, root, and our password.  In this case, it's also password.
Laravel will now read this file when running our local development
server using Artisan.
The last step in configuring the database is to run our migrations
for the markets table.  We can accomplish this by using Artisan and
running the command migrate with no arguments.
This will run all migrations waiting to be run.
Once the migration is run, you should get a success message.
To verify that our migrations ran, we can go back to our MySQL
monitor or CLI.  Once you log in to the monitor, you can run the
command use market followed by a semicolon.
This command will set the monitor to run all queries against the markets table.
Now we can run the command show tables followed by a semicolon,
and all tables in the market will be listed.
You should see a markets table, as well as a migrations table
that helps keep track of all migrations made to the database.
As a review, we've configured our database inside of Laravel by using
a .env file.  We've created a database in the MySQL monitor.
Then we ran all migrations on the newly setup database.
Now it's time to do some challenges, and I'll see you in the next section.