Welcome back!  Let's talk about pagination and validation inside of Laravel.
Let's say we have 100 markets.  Listing out all 100 markets on one
page can be a bit messy.  So we want to separate them into pages or
paginate our results.  We also want to work on validation or how we
can verify precreation that our form fields contain the correct kind of data.
Let's see how we can do this.  We're going to want to modify our index
action query and sort our results.  We want to add pagination to our
index action, add pagination links on our index template.
We want to add validation key value pairs for each input.
And we want to add some error displays if the validation fails.
To paginate in Laravel is really quite simple.
All we need to do is change out our call to all in the index action
and use the orderBy clause, which will return all results ordered by
name and then, in this case, ascending by using the asc as the second argument.
Then we'll chain a new method called paginate at the end of that call
with the argument of how many markets we want to show in each page.
Here I'm using nine so that eventually we can do three rows of three each.
Then we return the view just as before.
Now our page will only show the first nine markets.
In order to get a link to the next page, we need to add a call to the
$markets object and then a method called links.
Once we add styles, the output of the links method will look something like this.
Validation in Laravel is also very straightforward.
In our store function before we run the create method,
using the keyword this and a call to validate, we can validate our
input before it ever stores to the database.
The validate method takes two arguments.  The first is the $request
object, which will contain the form data.  The second argument is an
array of rules where the key is the field we're validating from the
for, and the value is a string of rules that must be applied
successfully to the data in the field.  Let's look at the name ruleset.
The validation rule string is a set of rules separated by the pipe character.
Each one of these rules is required.  The first is the required rule,
which means that something must be present in the field of name.
The second is that it must be unique on the markets table,
which means we can't have a name that also is the same of another name
in the markets table.  Last, we have a max of 255 characters.
So that means no really long market names.
For the website and city, we're only requiring them.
But it would be a good idea to add a bit more validation to this in
a real-world application.  If all the rules pass, the market will be
created, and the redirect will run as expected.
If it fails, it will drop out of the method and then just redirect
back to the form with errors.
In order to display these and any validation errors, we're going to
need to update our view.  Instead of updating the form itself to
display the errors, we'll add them to our layout.
This way we only have to do it once for the entire application.
There's a global variable in Laravel called $errors, which is the
collection of errors.  We need to check if the count of the errors
is greater than 0 before we begin looping.
Then we loop through all the errors with the $errors object operator
to all method, and then print each error as a single message.
One other neat feature that you can use is a rule called bail.
Bail will exit out of our validation routine on any errors on any
field in order.  This way, if there's an error on the name,
it'll display just the error for name and then exit the validation.
This way we can speed up our application.  It may not seem like much,
but when you have 20 fields on a form, it makes a big difference.
Let's review what we've learned in this section.
We've modified our index action query and sorted our results.
We've added pagination to our index action.
We've added pagination links to our index template.
We've added validation key value pairs for each input.
We've added error display if the validation fails.
And we used bail to exit on the first error for each input.
Now it's time for you to do some challenges, and I'll see you in the next level.
I smiled there.  Just a little smile.
We have no idea what's going on.  We do now, but we ---.
(Singing)
Tinker example ---.