Welcome back.  Let's work with a new tool, Artisan Tinker.
Artisan Tinker is a command line interface to our application and
all of our code.  To start Tinker, you're going to want to open up a
command line and type php artisan tinker, and then press Enter.
You should see something similar to the following, and the prompt
should be three right arrows or three greater-than symbols.
Next, you're going to want to type the following:  App, which is our
top-level namespace for the application, and then a backslash,
and then the Market with a capital M.  Follow that with two colon
symbols so that we can run a static class method.
All of that followed by an open and close set of parentheses.
You should see that the following result is an empty collection
because we don't have any markets in our table.
However, this does tell us that we do have a good connection to our
database with our application.
Using Tinker, we're going to create a new market entry.
This will allow us to see how to structure our data, as well as what
commands to use on the class to store data.
We'll begin by creating a variable named $data and setting its value
to an array with key value pair for each of our table columns.
Our columns or keys are name, city, and website, and we'll set the
values equal to Orlando Farmers Market as the name, Orlando as the
city, and orlandomarket.com as the website.
When you press Enter, you'll see the value of the new array.
Finally, we need to create a new entry.  We can do this by calling
App\Market and then the static method of create.
Then pass our $data array variable as the argument.
If we do this now, we're going to get an error,
MassAssignmentException on the name.  What this is telling us is that
our database is protected from assigning multiple key values at the
same time for the Market model.  This is a security feature that's
meant to keep things such as ID and timestamps or maybe user roles
depending on the model from being assigned from an outside source
such as a form.
In order to fix the MassAssignmentException, we're going to need to
allow specific fields to be mass assigned.
For our application, we're going to want the name, the city,
and the website fields to be created or updated through mass
assignment using the protected model property named $fillable.
$Fillable accepts an array of column names for the model that we will
allow to be filled through mass assignment.
Now switching back over to our Tinker console, we can run the last
command of create again.  This time you'll get back a Market object
with all of our new values that were in the $data array from the previous steps.
Still in Tinker, we can run our command to query all markets in the database.
This time we'll get back a collection with one result--an App\Market
object with our new data.
Congrats!  You've created your first database market entry.
Let's review what we've done to get here.  We've used Artisan Tinker
to tie into our application and create some new data.
Then to solve for mass assignment issues, we've allowed our city,
website, and name columns to be assigned using the $fillable property.
Now it's time for you to do some challenges, and I'll see you in the next level.
This will run all migrations right ---.
Using Tinker, we will create a new market entry.
Our columns, whoa, forgot the speed there.