Welcome back!  Now that we have a relationship, let's make it work
with a form.
To make our relationship work better, we'll use a form.
We can do this by creating an update method to add the markets to the
farm, creating a form for updating our farms, us the form to associate
markets to the farm, and then keep these associations in sync through our controller.
Our first step is to modify the existing edit action.
Here we're querying for a farm, but we'll need to add a query to get
the markets too.
We can do this by calling Get followed by a call to pluck.
With pluck, we can just query for specific values or columns in the table.
Here we want only name and ID, and then we'll sort them by name.
This way our markets variable is a collection of market names as the
value, and the ID of that market as a key.
Then we'll return the same view call but modify it a bit to now
include our markets.  We're using a new function called compact.
In this case, compact and a string of farm, string of markets,
is a shorthand way of writing an array with a key of farm with a
value of $farm, and then a key of markets with a value of $markets.
Next, we'll head into our edit.blade.php file.
Here we'll have a route helper calling the update function to update
an existing farm.  The difference between this form and the create
form is that we're sending along a custom method called patch.
This let's Laravel know that we want to update an existing object.
Then in this form, we want to loop through all the markets.
Remember that our keys are the ID of the market, and the value is
just the market name.  Next, we'll create an input as a checkbox
where the value is the ID of the market.  We set the name of the
checkbox to market with two square brackets like an array so that each
ID that's checked will be sent back to the form as an array of IDs
into the $request object so that we can process it in the update action.
Now that we have a way to send the checked markets back to the
request, we need a way to check the ones that are already associated.
The way to do this is with a ternary if statement.
We want to run a test first, and that test is to see if the $farm
object markets related IDs contains the ID that we're currently
looping through on the foreach.  If it is true or the ID is contained,
then it will print the text checked.  Otherwise, it will print nothing.
This way the box will already be checked if the market ID is already
associated with the farm.
Let's look at the ternary if statement a bit closer.
The if statement is separated into three parts.
The first part is the test or what would normally be inside the
parentheses following the if keyword.  Here we want to test that a is
equal to the integer 1.  The second part is what we want the value
or result to be if the test evaluates to true.
Here we're setting a string to say a is equal to 1.
The second part is what we want if the value or result of the test
evaluates to false, which is to say that a is not equal to 1.
This way we can write simple code to check our checkbox if the market
in the loop is already related to our farm.
In the future, we might want to write a helper function for this
as we'll need it again for the market's CRUD.
Next, let's modify the update method on the farms controller.
Here's the default for just farms.  We would get the request and then
pass it through to the update method on the $farm, then redirect to
the farms page.  In between these two, we'll need to process our new
market's relationship data.
To process our new relationships, we need to make a call to $farm
object operator markets method, and then a new method called sync.
Here we'll pass the $request object and a call to the markets
property, which if you recall will be an array of market IDs that are checked.
Now that we've come to the end of the project, let's do a video
walkthrough of the CRUD process for our markets and farms.
So here's a quick walkthrough of what we've done in this course.
As you can see if we go to the main URL, it will give us our listing of markets.
This is due to our routing table, our root route being a /markets route.
So this will give us a listing of all of our markets.
From here, we can click on an individual market.
As you can see it'll go to the URL markets and then /3.
That will give us a market with the ID of 3.
From here we can also edit, see the Edit button here.
We can edit, which will give you the option of a form to change anything.
So we can do Downtown Market and then do plural.
We can do the URL as well, downtownsorlando, and hit Update.
This is going to submit a patch
or a request to change that.  And as you can see when we come back to
our listing at /markets, you'll see Downtown Markets.
The other thing we can do is to go markets/create and create
our own new market.  So you can see we have some placeholders here.
And as we start typing, we will replace this.
So this is a New Market and then New City and then newmarket.com and hit Create.
As you can see, it says that New Market was created.
And you'll see right here, New Market.  So we can click on it,
and this will have an ID of 11.  If we don't want this market any
longer, we can simply hit the Delete key and delete the market.
And that will be the full walkthrough of our system.
Thanks for playing the From Form to Table with Laravel course.
Let's do some challenges, and I'll see you in the wrap-up video.
Add ---.
My stomach's going ---.
(Laughing)
Sorry.