Lettuce head to the farm
and get deep into the CRUD
No need to be alarmed—
our data's cleaner than the mud.
We'll pep up our app, yes we will, it's gonna be real swell.
So swell, so swell.
Learning MVC is a snap when you're using Laravel.
Hi!  I'm Hampton Paulk.  Welcome to From Form to Table with Laravel.
In this level, we'll be working with the Laravel installation and the
setup of a new project.
In this first section, we're going to download the Laravel installer
using Composer, create a new application called Market, start up a
local server, and review Laravel's CLI or command line interface.
The first step is to download the latest version of the Laravel
installer with Composer.  We're going to install it globally to our
system so that we can create a new application.
Begin by navigating to the folder you want to keep the project in.
I'll be creating it in the Home folder, but you can create the
application wherever you like.  Next, we'll want to run the following
command:  composer global require, followed by the installer vendor
and package, which is laravel/installer.  This may take a little time.
But once it's complete, you will find something similar to the following.
Now that our installer is ready, we can run the command laravel new,
followed by the name of our app, which I will call market.
Once this command runs, you'll be back to the prompt.
In order to change directory to our market, we'll use the CD,
or change directory, command followed by the folder that was just
created, which is market.  Once we're in the folder, we can test the
installation by running the local server.  Type the following command:
php artisan serve.  The server will take over the terminal,
so when you're wanting to exit the server, press the Ctrl+C keys to
terminate the server.  While the server is running, you can visit
127.0.0.1:8000, which is telling us we're visiting the local host at port 8000.
Once you navigate to the URL, localhost:8000 or 127.0.0.1:8000,
you should see the following page.  This simple splash page will
give you a link to the documentation and other helpful sites.
Our next step will be to create a model so that we can interact
with our database through our application.
We'll do this by using Laravel's Artisan command line interface.
We will use the make command to create a model and at the same time
create a migration, which will help us manage our database table row
and column structure.  We'll talk more on this in a few.
All of the following items will be done from our terminal.
To start, we'll type php artisan, and the help make:model.
You can use help without a command, or you can place help in front of
any command to get information about that command.
Here we can see that the command takes some optional arguments and
one required field for the name of the model we want to create.
If we want to create a migration to go along with our model,
we can pass the -m flag as our option.
Now we can run php artisan make:model -m, and the singular
capitalized model name of Market.  This will create our Market and a migration.
Using Laravel's standard naming, it will call our table markets,
which is the lowercase plural of our model name.
Here's what our new model looks like out of the box.
It's under the namespace App, and we're extending the Eloquent\Model
class so that we get all the awesome functionality of the Eloquent ORM.
Now all we need to do is configure our database.
We do that with migrations.
Our migration file will be in the database parent folder and then in
the migrations folder.  You'll see the name create_markets_table
prefaced by the date and timestamp that it was created.
Our migration files allow us to version control our database and
tightly control what each table contains.
By default, the markets table will be created with an
auto-incrementing ID and timestamps for created and modified times.
We'll need to extend this a bit to include our own fields.
To begin with, we'll add a column of a string type and call it name.
This will be the name of our farmer's market.
We'll also want this name to be unique so that no two entries can
have the same market name.  Then we'll add two more columns of the
same string type, one for the city and one for the website.
In this level, we've learned about installing Laravel's installer with
Composer, using Laravel's installer to create a new application.
We've learned about Artisan serve to create a local web server.
And we've learned how to create a model with migrations.
Now it's time for you to do some challenges, and I'll see you in the next level.
That was terrible.  It was like I just swallowed localhost.
(Laughing)
We're going to drop the base, the database.
Photo of our ---.