Lettuce head to the farm
and get deep into the CRUD
No need to be alarmed—
our data's cleaner than the mud.
We'll pep up our app, yes we will, it's gonna be real swell.
So swell, so swell.
Learning MVC is a snap when you're using Laravel.
Welcome back!  In this level, we're going to talk about relationships.
Now that we have our Market system mostly build out, let's take a look
at adding some farms.  We'll need to do a few things to add farms to our markets.
We'll need to look at creating farms in the same kind of CRUD that we
did for markets.  We need to establish relationships between the farms
and the markets.  Then we'll want to create a pivot table in the
database to create associations between each of the tables.
Let's start by building out the Farm.  We need to create a Farm model using Artisan.
We want to create the migration with the same fields as our Market.
We want to create a Farm controller, and we want to create the index,
show, create, and save methods on the controller.
Once you create the Farm, it should have the following methods--index,
show, create, and save.
In Laravel, there are several different types of relationships.
The most simple is the one to one, like an employee should have one job title.
Another is the one to many, such as a blog post will have many comments.
Our relationship is very bidirectional.  Markets can have many farms,
and farms can belong to many different markets.
This is called a many to many relationship.
In a many to many relationship, we'll have to use a pivot table.
A pivot table keeps track of the farm_id and its related market_id,
and it works to help us in both directions.
As you can see in this example, Thomas Farms has an ID of 1.
And in the farm_market table, the ID 1 is associated to a market_id of 4.
So that way the Farm with an ID of 1, Thomas Farms, is related to the
market_id 4 or the Cair Paravel Market.
In order to create a pivot table, we'll need to create another migration file.
This time using Artisan, we'll run the command make:migration and give
it a very descriptive name.  Then using the option --create,
we can pass the name of our pivot table, which is farm_market.
This will create our migration file with a couple of fields.
Next, we're going to open the file and add some more columns.
Notice here that the table name must be a combination of both tables
in alphabetical order, which means it's farm_market.
If you name this market_farm, it would not work.
Also, this code for timestamps is pre-generated by Artisan.
We'll need to open this file and add some more.
We will need a column for farm_id and for market_id.
These will both be unsigned integers and will be used as indexes for queries.
Then we'll need to create a foreign key for the farm_id referencing
the ID field on the farms table.  So that way on delete of that entry,
it will cascade and delete the pivot table entries.
We'll repeat this process for market_id and the markets table,
and we're ready to run our migration.
Once the migration is run, we need to now extend our Farm and Market
models to include a reference to the other.
Looking at Market, it will now have a method called farms.
This will return a belongsToMany relationship with the App\Farm model.
And then we'll also want to keep track of timestamps.
Though this is not required, it can be nice to have and does not cause
much of a performance load.
Let's jump back into Artisan Tinker and learn how to use our newfound relationships.
To start, we'll need a market.  Let's use Eloquent to grab the first
market in the database table.  We do this with a call to the first
method on the Market class and then store it for later in the object
variable $market.  We can immediately call $market with an object
operator to the farms method to see what we get.
A call to $market farms will return as we might expect a BelongsToMany relationship.
If we try and get the first object in that collection, it will return null.
Looks like we need to grow this relationship.
To start, we'll grab a farm.  Let's query again for the first and
store it in the $farm object variable.
Now to store the farm in the market, we run the following--$market
object operator calls to the farms method, and then object operator
to save, but then pass the $farm object as the argument.
Now if we run $market farms and count, we'll get a value of 1.
If we do the other direction, $farm markets count, we should get the same.
Now we have a farm associated with a market.
Let's take a look back at this section.  We've created a Farm model
and some generic CRUD methods.  We've established a relationship
between farms and markets.  We've created a pivot table for database
associations, and we used Tinker to search and associate a farm to
a market in both directions.
Now it's time to work on some challenges, and I'll see you in the next section.