Lettuce head to the farm
and get deep into the CRUD
No need to be alarmed—
our data's cleaner than the mud.
We'll pep up our app, yes we will, it's gonna be real swell.
So swell, so swell.
Learning MVC is a snap when you're using Laravel.
Welcome back!  In this level, let's work with controllers and views.
In order to get our Market app up and running, we'll need to display
a list of all the markets.  But to do that, we're going to need to get
our controllers, routing, and views all set up.
In this level, we'll create our controller, create RESTful methods for
CRUD, or Create/Read/Update/Delete, connect our routes to the
controller through the routing file.  Then we'll set up our view by
querying all the markets and passing that along to a view from within the controller.
We'll need to create that view and use Blade to loop through all the results.
In order to create our controller, we'll need to go back to our
Artisan command line tool.  Once we're in the terminal, we'll need to
run the following command--php artisan help make:controller.
By using help before our command, we'll see the documentation on the
command, and we're able to look at some of our options.
Here, the argument that's required is the name of the controller.
But we can also pass the option of -m and the model name to create a
resource controller for that model.
In our case, we're going to want to pass the market model to the
command to generate the MarketController.
To do this, we'll run the same command as before without the word
help and then follow that with a -m and the name of the model, Market.
And for the name, we'll use MarketController in CamelCase.
Once you press Enter, you will have created the MarketController.
If we open the controller that was just created located at
app/Http/Controllers and the name MarketController.php, we'll see our
new resource controller.  By passing the -m flag,
it automatically created our index, show, create, save, and destroy
methods for us with the expected arguments, such as the response and
request objects and our models.
In order to link our URLs to our controller, we'll need to work on
our routes file in the routes directory and web.php.
We've looked at routes before in Try Laravel where we can link URLs to
anonymous functions to return data.  But in this case, we want to use
the resource route so that we can create all the routes needed to work
with a model resource.  Here we will add the Route class followed
by the resource method followed by two arguments.
The first argument is the name of the URL pattern to look for,
which is markets, then the controller name to route through.
Here it's MarketController.  Close that line with a semicolon,
and we now have access to all of these routes.
For example, if you navigate to the markets URL, it will be a GET
request that then directs to the MarketController and the index action.
We also have ones for create, which maps to the create action.
We also have a POST request to markets that allow us to store using
the MarketController and the store action.
You'll also see similar actions for the URLs for destroy, update,
show, and edit.
Another way to see all of our routes and at the same time check that
our routes file is providing all the correct routes is to use Artisan.
To see all the routes in the application, you'll run php artisan
route:list, and then press Enter.  Now you can see the method,
URL pattern, controller, and action pair, as well as the context of
each route in the application.
The first method that we'll be modifying is the index method,
which is used to display all of the markets in the application.
The first line of code inside the index action will be our call to
query the model for all markets and then store it in a collection named $markets.
Then we'll want to return a view.  We can do this by returning the
output of a view helper in Laravel.  The view helper will take two arguments.
The first is the template folder file name in dot notation.
Here we're using the markets folder and then the index.blade.php view,
which we'll create soon.  Then we'll pass an array of arguments to that view.
In this case, our only argument is the markets collection $markets.
We'll pass that with a key of markets.
The index view will be created in a new folder named markets under
the resource/views folder.  All new market-related views should be
created under this markets folder.  Our index file should be named
index.blade.php so that we can use the Blade template syntax.
Next, we'll need to create some basic HTML and then place an unordered
list tag set in the middle of our body.  Using Blade syntax,
we'll create a foreach loop and loop through all of our markets.
Start with the @ symbol, add foreach, and then in a set of
parentheses, you'll loop through all $markets as $market.
Then you'll close that loop with @endforeach.
Each time the loop runs, the data in $market will change to reflect
the item in the $markets collection.
Now let's create a link to each of the markets.
We can do this with a list item inside the foreach loop block,
and then each of the list items you'll add an anchor tag.
We can do this with a list item inside of the foreach loop block.
And in each of the list items, you'll add an anchor tag.
The anchor tag's value will be the name property of the market object.
We can access this with the Blade curly mustache syntax, and then the
name $market followed by the object operator, and then the property
name, which is name.
Now let's use the route helper and create the URL that we want to
link to for each of the markets.  We can do this again with the
mustache syntax and a call to the route helper.
The first argument will be the name of the route.
Remember, named routes are created for you when you use the resource
route type in the routes file.  The second argument is the object
itself, which Laravel will use to extract the ID of the market.
This command will create a string URL for you that will link to the
market by ID.
Let's review all that we've learned in this level.
We've learned how to create a controller using the php artisan CLI.
We've learned how to use the -m flag to generate a resource controller.
We've configured a resource route to map CRUD actions to our routes.
We've used the CLI to view all the routes in our application.
We've learned how to query our database for all markets.
We've passed the query results to a view for display.
We've created an index template using Blade.
We've looped through all of our markets with Blade.
And we've displayed a link to the market show page.
Now it's time for you to take some challenges, and I will see you in
the next level.