Lettuce head to the farm
and get deep into the CRUD
No need to be alarmed—
our data's cleaner than the mud.
We'll pep up our app, yes we will, it's gonna be real swell.
So swell, so swell.
Learning MVC is a snap when you're using Laravel.
Welcome back!  In this section, we'll be talking about layouts,
forms, and CSRF protection.
To continue and build out our CRUD for the markets model,
we'll need to do a little housekeeping.  We'll take this time to
create a layout for the app so that way we can DRY up our code,
where DRY means Don't Repeat Yourself.  Then we'll build out our
show method and template, build out our create and new methods,
and then code up a form to create some new markets.
Let's get started by creating a new folder named layouts in the
resources/views folder.  Then create a new field in that folder called app.blade.php.
From here let's move over all the framing HTML and body tags that we
used in our index template leaving behind the content itself.
Then where we want our content to appear, we'll place an @yield tag
with a single string argument of main to define our main content area.
This string can be called anything, and we can have several yield
tags in one layout.  In our example, we'll only need the one.
Now moving over to the index template, we can use a few commands in
Blade to extend our new layout file.  Using the @extends command,
we can add a string argument that calls our layouts folder and dot
our file name, which is app.  Then we can use a section block with
the @section and @endsection tags surrounding our content.
We'll pass the string of main to the @section tag to signify where
the content should be displayed on our layout file.
Next, using the same @extends and @section blocks, we'll want to
create a new file in the markets folder named show.blade.php.
This show file will be used to display the data from a single market,
which will be passed to this view as $market.
Knowing this, we can echo our three columns as properties of the $market object.
The name, city, and website should be displayed using the mustache
syntax and the object operator just as before on the index page.
Now that we have a show template, we need to pass some data to that
view using the controller.  Let's modify our show method, which has an
argument, typeset to be a $market object and stored in a variable named market.
Laravel will automatically find the $market object for us or return a
404 error if nothing is found all before we even make it into the
show action code.  Now that we are in the show action with a $market
object, all we need to do is pass that object off to our view helper.
The first argument is still pointing to the markets folder.
But now we want the show.blade.php file that we just created.
We will also pass the $market object with a key of market in the argument's array.
Now that we have a show, an index action, and templates, we need to
add the ability to create a new $market object.
Let's start with generating the form for creation.
In the controller, we will not need to work with the model at all.
We only need to pass a view helper to the markets.create template.
Let's create that now.
Now it's time to create our template for the create action in our controller.
We'll need to open up our form and use the route helper again to
create a URL to post to, as well as defining the method as post.
Then we'll need to add three fields--one for the Market Name,
one for the market city, and one for the market website--all as input fields.
Finally, we need to add our Submit button, close out our form,
and end our main section.
Now that we have a create action and a create temple, it's time to
build out the store action.  The store action is where the form
request is sent so we will be processing a $request object as the argument.
We will then pass the request collection with the method all as an
argument to the create method on our Market class.
We did this same thing in our Tinker example earlier in the course.
Here the request all will be the same as our $data array from Tinker.
Once we create the new object in the database, we'll want to return
a redirect to the markets URL using the redirect helper.
Our form is good and now creates a new market.
But we need to add a little security feature to complete the form.
We'll use a helper function called csrf_field inside of our form to
create a hidden input field for a token.  This token will help us
protect against cross-site request forgery.
Laravel will then process this token during the store action inside of
the request and make sure that the post did indeed come from within
our own application.
Let's review what we've done so far.  We've created a layout to DRY up our code.
We've created a show method and a template.
We've created our create and new methods.  We've coded a form in Blade
to create new markets.  And we've protected against cross-site request
forgery using a built-in Laravel helper.
Now it's time for you to take some challenges, and I'll see you in the next section.