Welcome back.  Now that you understand includes, let's move on to requires.
We're going to want to move our code out of the index.php file.
At first, this is going to be a way for us to keep our code clean.
We almost always end up with multiple files containing different bits
of PHP code.  This will help keep our code organized by using unique
meaningful file names, which will help us find and work on our code later.
Now we're going to create a new folder underneath our app directory.
We're going to call this folder source, or src.
Inside of this folder, we're going to create a new file named app.php.
This is where we're going to keep all of our code for the project
instead of in the index.php file.
Once our new file has been created, we're going to want to cut and
paste all of our code from the index.php file into our new app.php file.
One thing to notice is that files that contain only PHP, such as our
app.php file, and no HTML, we will not need a closing PHP tag.
We're essentially repeating the process that we did in the last
section by including our new app.php file inside of our index.php file
with one major difference.  The difference here is the use of the
require function instead of the include function.
They behave the same except if the file is missing or not found when
using an include statement, you'll get a warning.
If you use a require and the file is not found, it will throw a fatal error.
Let's take a closer look at the difference between these two.
We're going to force the error to happen by changing our name from
app.php to foo.php where foo.php does not exist in our source directory.
This will give us a fatal error, or a 500 error if we're in
production, and the page will not load.  Now to take a look at the
opposite behavior, let's change this require to an include.
Notice now the error has changed to a warning, and also you'll notice
that the HTML will still display underneath of our warnings.
Now inside the index.php file you can see that we have requires and includes.
The main PHP logic is required; however, the HTML, or the partials,
are only included.  From here on out, we'll only go back to the
index.php file if we need to include or require some new code.
Enjoy the challenges, and I'll see you soon.
Include.  What was that?
Oh, so close, so close.
Ekking on --- (Noises).
Ekking.  (Laughing).
Ekking the data screen bad.