We've got our eyes on the sky searching for PHP life.
We'll use POST requests to track extraterrestrial guests.
Validation and security will lock things down in a hurry.
We want to believe these Close Encounters with PHP.
Welcome back.  Right now we have a form where a user can submit data,
and then we just echo that data back to the screen.
Well, this can cause a lot of problems, so in this level we're going
to look at validating and securing that data.
From here on out, we're going to focus all of our efforts in regard to
code here inside of our app.php file.  Let's take a quick look of what
we have so far.  Right now we're checking that the SERVER
REQUEST_METHOD is set to POST, and then we're setting our POST
variables for date, email, and description to some variables.
Then we're just echoing those variables out the screen one at a time.
This can cause a lot of issues.
Echoing our data directly to the screen is a bad idea, especially without validation.
Most of the time we're not going to echo to the screen; we're going to
send it to a database.  If we were to store null values or empty
values to a database, that's going to wreak havoc on our system.
Not just null values, but invalid values can also cause trouble.
We want to make sure we have a valid data and a valid email when we
get our form submission.  We're also going to need to get rid of any
HTML or other code.  This is mostly for security, but also for formatting.
If any of these things go wrong, we want to redirect the user back to
our form and then provide some error messages for them.
For all of this, let's create a validation checklist.
That way we can step through each of the following items.
We want to make sure that our date exists, that our email exists,
that our description exists.  We want to remove any whitespace,
we want to sanitize our output, we want to validate our email,
and validate our date.  First, let's check to see if each of the items
has any data inside of them.  We can do that by using the empty
function in PHP.  We place a not operator, or an exclamation point,
in front of the empty keyword to make sure that it is not empty.
Now our echo statement inside of the if conditional will only run if
not empty evaluates to true.  So now we can check off that the date
exists on our checklist.  We don't want to output anything from our
form if any of the data is missing from our fields.
We'll accomplish this by adding more not empty conditionals and then
chain them together with the two ampersand, or the and operator,
inside of PHP.  Now we're able to check off that our email exists and
that our description exists.
Sometimes data can be submitted with some type of whitespace in front
of or behind the data.  We can solve for this by using the PHP trim function.
The trim function in PHP will remove any leading or trailing
whitespace from any variable or data that you put inside of the parentheses.
So now that we've done that, we can check off our next item on the list.
We've removed all the whitespace.
So far we've only been filtering input.  Now we're going to sanitize
some output by using HTML special characters.
This will remove any HTML markup or code from our form data,
but it will encode our greater than, question marks, or any other
special characters into HTML entities.  This way the text will look
like code, but will not be parsed by the HTML or PHP interpreters.
For example, if a user was to submit an h1 with ALIENS inside of it,
it would actually show the h1 tags and not render it.
When a user submits input, we're going to want to filter out any
information that we don't want before we would store it to a database.
Valid email is needed to send notifications, allow users to contact
each other, and perhaps as a login for an application.
And validates architecture needed for sorting and organizing our data.
When we output data to the browser, we want to sanitize that
information for security, as well as for consistency in the user experience.
Let's do some challenges, and when you return we'll tackle email and date validation.