Welcome back.  In this section, we're going to learn about prepackaged
bits of code known as libraries.
We have good validation so far, but it can be improved.
Let's take a look at some things that we might want.
So if one of our items is missing, we need to report that back to the user.
Same thing if the date is not formatted correctly.
Also, the email, if it's not valid, we want to report that it's
invalid to the user as well.  We can accomplish this with a PHP
library, or package.
A package is a collection of code that's meant to serve one purpose,
and you can use it anywhere in your code.  Packages are always open
source, which means that lots of developers can contribute,
and they can evolve the package very quickly.
PHP uses a package manager tool called Composer.
Composer is going to allow us to define all of the packages that we
need per project and then use those anywhere inside of our code.
Let's start by installing Composer.
To install Composer, we're going to need to spend some time in our terminal.
I'm going to be using Mac OS for these examples, but all the other
installation options are available at the link below.
We're going to be using the PHP CLI, or command line interface to PHP.
The first argument after php is -r, which runs PHP commands in the
terminal without the use of any PHP tags.  Our first command here will
download the installer and name it composer-setup.php.
The next command is going to validate that this is the correct
installer by comparing it against a hash.  Then we're going to run
composer-setup.php as a script.  Then, after the install,
we're going to run a command to unlink it or then delete the file from our system.
The last step after install is to move the composer.phar file,
or PHP single application file, to our user/local/bin folder and
rename it to just composer.
Now that Composer is installed, we can run it as a command in the terminal.
We're going to search for a package by running the composer search
command followed by a query string of validation.
You can see here that we have several results.
The one we want is respect/validation, which is the most awesome
validation engine ever created for PHP.
Now that we know the name of the package we want, we use another
command called require.  So just type composer require followed by respect/validation.
The require command is going to add the package to our composer.json
file and then install it.
The composer.json file is going to define for us what's needed inside
of the project.  All new packages added to the project will be
installed under the vendor directory in the root of our project.
The validation package will be in a respect folder.
The folders are related to the package name.
In this case, respect/validation will be under the respect folder and
then the validation folder.
Let's take a look at our composer.json file, which is defining what we
want as a package inside of our project.  Right now we only have one
requirement, which is the respect/validation package.
The caret symbol in front of our version number is a wildcard in
Composer to tell us that we're okay with the next significant release.
So far we only want a minimum of version 1.1.
However, these wildcards can be very powerful.
In this case where we're saying we want the next significant version
of the release, we're able to have any release up to but not including version 2.0.
We need a way to get our Composer packages into our application.
We can do this with autoloading.  Inside of our Vendor folder,
you'll notice that we have another file called autoload.php.
This file by itself is going to load all of our packages that are in
the Vendor folder and make them available inside of our project.
All the files that we're going to need for this project are in the
Respect folder, in the Validation folder, and then all the way down in
a library folder.  But using our autoload.php, we don't have to worry about it.
It will take care of all of that for us.
Let's take a closer look at the line where we've used the autoload file.
We're going to use a require statement followed by the magic constant
DIR, and then we're going to go back two directories to our vendor
folder autoload.php file.
This will be placed at the top of our app.php file on the first line
after the opening php block.  We can now use packages anywhere below,
including in our custom validation file.
We now have access to all the packages provided by Composer through autoloading.
However, we need a keyword that we haven't seen before called use.
Use will allow us to access our new Validation\Validator class.
By writing the code use Respect\Valication\Validator, we now have
access to the Validator class that's provided by Composer.
This is different from the include because we've already included all
the files by using the autoloader provided by Composer.
Here we want access to a single class inside the Respect\Validation library.
Now that we have access to the Respect\Validation\Validator class,
we'll use the new keyword to create a new object.
Here we create a variable called $v and then set it equal to new Validator.
New is a keyword that creates a new object based off of the Validator class.
This is all completely new to us, so let's use a var_dump to see
what's inside of this new $v object.
So it turns out that our $v is a Validator object with a protected set
of rules in an array.  So what can we do with this Validator object?
We can run validation commands with the validator to test against
custom sets of rules.  Each validator can have a unique name.
It can also have a template that allows us to customize error strings.
Now we can add some custom rules to our rules array on the Validator.
Let's take a quick look back over what we've learned in this section
on Composer and autoloading.  We know that Composer is a package
manager built for PHP.  We've used the command line interface to
search for packages and install them into our application.
We've got access to the package through the use of the autoload.php file.
We've learned about the use keyword to access a class through a
Namespace/ClassName pattern.  And we also have created a new validator
instance with the new keyword.
Let's jump in and do some challenges on Composer and autoloading.
Riffs some (Noises).
To help provide a base.  To help provide, provide.
We need a way.  We need we.  We need a way, we need a way, we need a
way, we need a way.  We need a way to get to packages in the com project.