We've got our eyes on the sky searching for PHP life.
We'll use POST requests to track extraterrestrial guests.
Validation and security will lock things down in a hurry.
We want to believe these Close Encounters with PHP.
Welcome back.  In this section, we're going to talk about refactoring
our code using some PHP standards.
A group of project representatives, known as the PHP-FIG,
get together and talk about the commonalities of their projects and
how they can better work together.  Part of this is providing
programming standards to work towards.  These are in the forms of
PSRs, or PHP Standards Recommendations.  As of now, there are 6
accepted PSRs and over 12 currently in review or draft form.
Here are the currently accepted ones.  Let's take a look at the first
two, PSR-1 and PSR-2.  To help provide a base to share code across
projects, PSR-1 shows us how to use tags, character encoding,
naming conventions, and side effects.  PSR-2 expands upon PSR-1 and
creates better readability across projects and between multiple developers.
Some examples of PSR-2 are the use of whitespace, how to use tabs and
line length limits, and class structures.  We'll get to all of this in
time, but for now let's focus on PSR-1 and our app.php file.
In the basic coding standard, or PSR-1, it recommends that files
should either declare symbols, such as functions, or cause side
effects, such as echoing output, but it should not do both.
Our file, app.php, currently does both, so we're going to need to
extract some of this code out and place it into another file.
We will start by creating a file for just our validation code and call it validation.php.
Create this file in your app/src folder.  Then we're going to move our
validate_date function that we've just created into our new validation.php file.
Again, this is a PHP only file, so it will not need a closing PHP bracket.
Next, we'll return to our app.php file and require our validation.php.
However, it's a little different this time.
Just like before, we used a require statement, but this time we used
something new called a magic constant.  PHP provides a large number of
predefined constants to any script that runs.
In this case, we're using __DIR__, which will return the directory of
the file that we're currently in.  Then we're concatenating this
output with the name of our file, or validation.php.
Now the validate_date function comes from a completely different file
using an absolute path.  More magic constants can be found in the PHP docs.
You can get to that through the link below.
In this section, we've taken a brief look at refactoring our code to
the PSRs, or PHP Standards Recommendations.
Let's review what we've looked at.  We now know that PSRs are
recommendations made by the PHP Framework Interop Group, or the PHP-FIG.
We've cleaned up our code using the PSR-1 basic coding standard and
learned how to use the magic constant of __DIR__.
Now it's time for you to do some challenges.