Welcome back.  In this section, we're going to go over email and date validation.
Let's take a look back through what we've accomplished so far on our
to do list.  We validated the existence of all three data types,
our email, our date, and our description.  We've also removed any
whitespace from any of the data, as well as escaped all HTML special
characters sanitizing our output for the description field.
So the only thing that remains is to validate that we have a date and an email.
As of right now, we can still submit our form with an invalid email.
Here I'm using hampton@codeschool without the .com as an invalid email.
We're going to want to validate this data against the current email address standards.
PHP makes this really easy for us.
Using another conditional combined with a PHP function, we can check
the validity of our email address.  Here we're using the filter_var
function, or filter a variable.  We combine this with a built-in
constant, FILTER_VALIDATE_EMAIL.  If the variable is valid against the
email constant, it will return true.  Then it will echo out our data.
Now that we've done this, we can check off the validate email to do item.
We want to validate our date as well.  Here you can see we're using a
relative date of last night.  However, this is invalid.
We also need to format the user submitted data on output so that all
dates will look the same to the users.
To check the date, we'll use a function named strtotime, or string to time.
This will convert almost any date into a UNIX timestamp.
We'll store the timestamp in a variable named time.
Let's take a look at this a bit closer.
The strtotime function is very powerful and allows for many different
types of relative date formats.  Let's take a look at a few.
Looking at the first example, we use the function strtotime.
Then we pass as an argument the string of today.
This is going to return midnight of the current day.
Strtotime of yesterday, as well as tomorrow will also return midnight,
but of the respective day.  You're also able to use more complex
relative dates, such as last Saturday of March 2010.
Other than relative dates, you can also use several different types of
known date formats.  All of these will be converted to timestamps,
which are measured from the seconds since the UNIX epic,
which is January 1, 1970 with a time of 00:00:00 GMT.
Now that we have a timestamp, we should convert this into a formatted date.
We can do this with the PHP date function.
The date function will convert a UNIX timestamp into a human readable
date using the format that you've provided in the first argument.
Just like our strtotime function, there are a lot of different options for date.
Let's take a look at those now.
In our first example, we're using the function date followed by two arguments.
The first argument is a string of m/d/Y.  The second argument is our timestamp.
In this example, we're going to be using a timestamp that equates to
March 14, 2015.  The first example is going to return the month and
the day, and both of them will have leading 0s, as well as a four digit year.
The second example is going to return the full month name, as well as
an ordinal suffix such as st, nd, or th, as well as the year.
You can also see a few more examples, including one using a constant,
the DATE_ATOM, which is used for MySQL.  You really don't have to
memorize all of these different formatting options.
These, and more, can be found in the PHP date docs, which you can get
to by the link below.
We really want to take this validation step further and make it more reusable.
We'll do this by creating a custom function.
A function is a reusable block of custom code that will allow you to
create and accept arguments, work with that data, and return data back
to the location from where the function was called.
In this example, we're creating a function to multiply two numbers and
then return that product.  We start by using function,
a keyword provided by PHP.  Immediately after that, we'll create a
name of the function.  Here we're using multiply.
We open and close some parentheses and then place any number of
arguments inside of those parentheses.  Here we're using value_1
separated by a comma, and then value_2.  Then we open and close some
curly brackets, and then anything we want to do with those two
arguments we do inside of those curly brackets.
Here we're setting a variable product equal to the product of value_1 and value_2.
Then, on the next line, we're returning the value of product.
This is a very simple example, but let's take a look at some results
from this function.  Here we have four examples of using the multiply function.
In the first example, we're doing multiply 5 times 7, the second one
42 to 0, so on and so forth.  Here you can see the results: 35, 0, 42,
and then 288.  No matter what combination of integers we feed to the
function, we're always going to get the product of those two values.
Now let's create a custom date validation function.
We'll start with the keyword function followed by the function name.
Here we're using validate_date.  Then we follow that up with a single
argument of date_string inside of the parentheses.
We're going to open and close some curly braces and then place our
existing date validation code inside of these braces.
Instead of echo, we're going to use return to send the data back to
the function call.  Finally, we're going to want to add an else
statement to pass an error string back if we don't get a valid date.
Then we'll use our new function in place of the code we just moved by
writing echo validate_date, which is the name of our function,
open and close parenthesis, and then inside of there we'll actually
pass our date string that's submitted by the user.
This is either going to return to us a string with the formatted date
or our error string.
Let's take a look at what we've learned in this section as a review
before your challenges.  We learned how to use the filter_var function
combined with a built-in constant for our email address, we used the
strtotime function combined with the date function to validate and
format our date, and we've also learned how to create and use a custom function.
Now, enjoy some challenges, and I'll see you on the other side.
Anything on the dang screen that I feel like putting in there, so you know, hey.
Leading (Noises).
(Noises).