We've got our eyes on the sky searching for PHP life.
We'll use POST requests to track extraterrestrial guests.
Validation and security will lock things down in a hurry.
We want to believe these Close Encounters with PHP.
Welcome back.  Let's move on to includes and requires.
Our index.php file is starting to get a little crowded, and this is
only for a small amount of code, so how can we better approach this problem?
We can start to clean and organize our code by relocating our header,
our footer, and our content sections.  We can take these new sections
called HTML blocks or partials and place them back into our index.php
file with a single line.  We can also include some compartmentalized
code, and we can add a new folder structure for our project.
Let's start by creating an app folder and a public folder both in the
root of your project and then move our index.php file into the public folder.
Then inside of our app folder we're going to create a new folder called views.
This is going to be used to hold all of our new HTML blocks or partial files.
Then you're going to need to create three new files inside of the
views folder, one for the content, one for the footer, and one for the header.
After all the files are created, we're going to need to cut each
section of code from our index.php file and paste it into our new files.
Here we're taking the header information from the index.php file and
placing it in the header.php file in our app/views folder.
Now we must include the file back into our index.php file.
Where we removed the code from our index.php file, we're going to
create a new code block, and inside of our code block we're going to
use a new PHP function or keyword called include.
We can add code from another location to be processed within our
index.php file using the include function.
Here we're including app/views/header.php.
If you notice, there are two dots and a slash before app.
This means we want to move back or look back one directory.
Since our index.php file is inside of our public folder,
we're going to want to move one directory back outside of the public
folder and then move into our app/views folder to access our header.php file.
We'll need to do the same for content.php by moving it from the
index.php file into our content.php file, then replacing the code
we've just removed from the index.php file with our include function
pointing to our new content.php file.
Then we'll apply the same process to our footer.php file.
Here is our new index.php file.  Much cleaner.
Now let's do some challenges.  When you come back, we'll move our PHP
code outside of the index.php file.