We've got our eyes on the sky searching for PHP life.
We'll use POST requests to track extraterrestrial guests.
Validation and security will lock things down in a hurry.
We want to believe these Close Encounters with PHP.
Welcome to Close Encounters with PHP.  I'm Hampton Paulk.
Let's take a look at what we're going to be covering in this course.
In level one, we're going to be looking at two different HTTP requests
with GET and POST.  In level two, we're going to cover includes and
requires within our code and when to use each of these.
In level three, we're going to look at writing some custom validation
and touch on form security.  In level four, we're going to cover
Composer, a package management tool for PHP.
Then, in level five, we'll install a validation package and use it to
validate our form input.
This course assumes you have introductory knowledge of HTML, CSS, and basic PHP.
Though they are not required, we highly advise that you take or have
taken Front-end Foundations and Front-end Formations, as well as the
Try PHP course.
In this course, we'll be creating a form to submit UFO sightings.
We're going to learn how to gather data from a form, validate that it
contains the data that we want, and then echo that data to the screen.
Let's get started by building a form and looking at some HTTP requests.
We are going to want to look at the first of two HTTP requests.
The GET request, which is the most commonly used request method,
has a few things that you should keep in mind.
First and foremost, the GET request is used to request data from a resource.
They also show the query strings and the values in the URL.
GET requests can be bookmarked, can be cached, and will remain in your history.
The main thing to keep in mind is that GET requests are only for retrieving data.
The best way for us to understand a GET request is to take a look at an example.
Whenever we want to pass a query var or a variable item from the URL
using a GET request, we can do it using the following pattern.
A question mark after the destination starts the query var callout.
State is the name of our query var to use within the request,
and California is the value of the query var state.
Looking at the URL after submission, we can see that the data is
exposed in the URL.  If we inspect the request we have just sent,
you can see that the Request Method is GET and the Query String
Parameters are state with a value of California.
Now that we know about the GET request, let's take a look at the next
most commonly used request method, the POST method.
Where the GET method is used mostly to request data, we use the POST
to send the data.  Keep in mind that POST data shows query names and
values only in the body of the request.  The POST requests are never
bookmarked, they're never cached, and they will not remain in your history.
Let's take a look at an example of this.
To use a POST request, we're going to want to build a form.
This form is going to have the action set to the page or file we want
to submit our data to.  In this case, it's state.php.
The default method for forms is get, but we want to set ours to post.
As you can see in the input, name equal to state is how we address the
data in the form so we are able to access it within the POST request.
Taking a look at this request, we can see that the Request Method is
now POST, and instead of a query string, we have Form Data.
Also, an important thing to take note of is that no data has been
exposed inside of our URL.
Now that you understand the basics of POST and GET, let's go take a few challenges.
And then when you come back, we'll start building something.