We've got our eyes on the sky searching for PHP life.
We'll use POST requests to track extraterrestrial guests.
Validation and security will lock things down in a hurry.
We want to believe these Close Encounters with PHP.
Welcome back.  Let's take a look at object-oriented validation using
the Validator class.
Let's take a look at our validation class a bit closer.
In the last section, we dumped the Validator object in $v.
We've created an object by using $v = new Validator.
New is a keyword that takes the class Validator and creates an object
based off of that class, or the Validator class.
You might be wondering what is a class?  A class is a way for us to
group our code together providing a blueprint for a single purpose.
These classes contain functions, variables, and constants.
Functions are now called methods, variables are called properties,
but the use is the same.  An object is an instance or a copy of the class.
We usually name objects just like we do variables, and classes can
have public or private properties.  Public items can be used anywhere,
whereas private items can only be used within the class.
To create an object, we've used the new keyword, which creates a
single instance of the Validator class.
Now that we have a validator object using the Validator class,
how can we use that in our code?  We want to replace the code inside
of our validate_date function using the Validator.
The first part of the conditional that we want to replace is to test
whether or not the date is empty or not.  We'll do that by using the
Validator class and then using a method on the Validator class called validate.
There's a lot going on here, so let's take closer look.
The first part of this is the Validator class, which is a class that
we required using the use statement above.
The two colon symbols allows us to access the class's methods and
properties without creating a new object.  This is called a static call.
NotEmpty is a method on the Validator class.
The Validator calls this a rule.  Just after the notEmpty method call,
we use another method called validate.  Validate tests our data,
in this case date_string, against our rule, which is notEmpty.
So here we're simply validating that date_string is notEmpty.
This single line of code will return true if it validates or false if
it does not.
So now we validated that our date is not empty, but how do we know
it's actually a date?  We can use another rule called date built into
the Validator class, which will allow us to see if it's any number of date formats.
All of these together would make for a very long conditional
statement, so how can we improve this?
Respect/Validation allows us to chain all of our rules together before
we call the validate method.  We can do this using a hyphen and a
greater than symbol.  Together, this little arrow symbol is called the object operator.
So here you can see we've chained together notEmpty to date before we
call the method validate.  This is great, but what else can we do?
Well,
we can take all of our rules such as notEmpty and date and chain them
together and place them in a custom validator variable.
That way we can just call the variable followed by the method validate
and our data to use inside of a conditional statement.
Let's see how this looks inside of our existing function.
Inside of our validate_date function we create our validator,
and then we use it inside of our conditional statement with the validate method.
Another great feature of the validator date rule is that we can
require a custom format from the user by placing it as an argument
inside of our date rule.  We can use any format we want from the PHP
date function, which we've gone over in a previous section.
In this example, we're using the format of day followed by the two
digit month followed by a four digit year.
All dates entered into the form will have to match this format.
As a final step, if it fails, we're going to return a message to the
user requiring that it be in a specific format.
So here we'll just use an else statement to do this.
Let's take a look back of what we've gone over in this section in
regards to the Validator class.  We've learned how to create an object
using the new keyword.  We've also used our Validator class and some
of its methods as rules.  Some of those rules, such as the notEmpty or
date rule we've learned to use, as well as chaining rules with the object operator.
We've learned how to store custom validators inside of a variable and
then using those custom validators inside conditionals.
Now it's time for you to do some challenges, and I'll see you soon.