Welcome back.  Now that you know about requests and forms,
let's build something and work with our form data.
Let's take a moment to revisit the form that we're going to use.
We're going to be gathering three bits of data for our UFO sightings.
We're going to be gathering the date of the sighting,
an email address of the person reporting the sighting,
and then a nice block of descriptive text describing the sighting.
We're also going to need an area for errors or messages just in case
our form is submitted with incorrect information.
Looking at our form in code, we can see that our action will submit
back to the page that we're on, or index.php.
You could also leave this blank and it will submit to the same page
that the form exists on, but we're going to define it here for clarity.
So as you can see we have three different inputs with matching labels,
two inputs are text labels, one for date and one for email,
and the other one is a text area, or a block of text, for our description.
Inspecting our form data, we can see that we have a date, an email,
and a description all being submitted, but how do we access this data?
In PHP, we have some variables known as super global variables,
one of which contains the POST data.  To access, we will use $_POST in all caps.
Now, let's var dump this to the browser and view the output.
Once we dump the form data to the screen, you can see that the POST
super global gives us an array.
In this case the array has three keys, date, email, and desc,
each of them with string data that corresponds to each of our inputs
from the form.  Now that we know that the POST data is in the array,
we can echo these values just like any other associative array.
We'll do this by placing the string key inside the square brackets
next to the array variable.
However, when we refresh our page without submitting the form,
we get some errors.  This is because we're trying to access the POST
array items before we have submitted the form.
In this case, it's telling us that the POST with the key of date does not exist.
We need to use a conditional to make sure that our POST data exists
and is not empty.  We're going to do this by using another super
global variable from PHP called SERVER.  The SERVER is going to give
us information about the server request.
In this case, we use an array key of REQUEST_METHOD on the SERVER
super global variable, and make sure that it's set equivalent to POST.
If this evaluates to true, then we know we have a POST request and we
can try to access our POST data.  These values could still not exist
and throw an error, but using validation later on, we'll make sure
that they exist before we echo them to the screen.
Let's tidy up the code a little bit and take a look at the results.
We'll transfer the data into some variables to use in a formatted string.
Here you can see our data with the new formatted strings,
but before we continue, let's jump in and do some challenges.
Welcome to  --- ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Blah.  (Inaudible)