Welcome back.  In this section, we're going to learn about another
method of if/else called try/catch.
Right now we're returning messages or errors to the user by using an if/else statement.
But objects, such as our validator objects, have something called
exceptions, and exceptions can have messages.
Exceptions are thrown when an error occurs inside of our Validator class.
We can't use an if/else statement to catch these validation errors.
Instead, we'll have to use a new conditional block in PHP called the try/catch block.
We'll start with the keyword try followed by curly brackets.
Inside of these brackets we're going to add our code.
If this code fails and throws an exception, we want to catch it.
We'll catch it by using the keyword catch followed by an open and
close parenthesis with the class Exception followed by $e inside of the parentheses.
What this is is a PHP class called Exception, and then we're assigning
this exception to a variable called $e.  Inside of the catch brackets
we're going to want to do something useful with this $e object,
which is of the Exception type.
Where Exception is built into PHP, the Validator class has some custom exceptions.
We'll need to bring those into our code with another use statement.
Here's our existing code, but now it uses a try/catch statement
instead of the if/else.  It's going to catch our custom exception
provided by the validation package.  We'll start with using our custom
date_validator followed by the method assert.
Where validate returned true or false, assert will fail using our custom exception.
The next different bit of this code is the NestedValidationException
set to $e, which will be thrown if our custom validator fails.
So let's say it fails.  We'll dump that to the screen and see what it looks like.
As you can see, we've dumped another object.
In this case, it's the NestedValidationException object.
Let's take a look at what's inside of this object.
Inside of the protected name property, you can see we have submitted
the string someday, which clearly is not a valid date.
You can also see that the rules that it was compared against are below
in the rules array.  One is our rule for the date, and the other is
the rule for notEmpty.
Now that we know we have the Exception object, how can we use this to
provide the messages back to our users?
Our NestedValidationException has a method called getMessages that
will return some useful information to us.
Let's submit the same invalid date of someday and see what comes back.
Here we've dumped out an array, so getMessages is returning to us an array type.
Inside of the array is a string with a message about the failed validation.
We could just print the error out, but it's better to return our array
of errors so somewhere else in the program can choose how to print the errors out.
Here is an example of one method for displaying our errors.
We're using a variable called value and setting it equal to the output
of our validate_date function and passing through our date data from the form.
This is either going to return a date or an array of errors.
We can use a PHP function called is_array and pass value to that function.
This is going to return a true if it's an array or false if it's anything else.
We know that an error will come back as an array, but our correct data
will come back as a string.  So we put this inside of an if statement,
and we can cycle through that array using the foreach loop.
Otherwise, we'll just echo out that value to the screen.
Let's look at a better approach to all of this using Respect\Validation.
We're no longer going to need our validation file as we don't need our
custom function any longer, so now we can just use the app file.
We simply remove the require to our validation.php file as we're not
going to need it any longer.  Then we move the two use statements from
the validation.php file over to our app.php file.
Then, using the same try/catch statement, we'll simply add our
date_validator, our email_validator, and our desc_validator at the top
of the try block.  If all of these pass, then we'll just echo our data
like we normally would.  However, if an exception is thrown for any of
those three custom validators, we're going to want to catch those errors.
Once we catch it, we'll just loop through the errors right then and
get all of our messages for each of the validators.
Let's take a look back at what we've learned in this section.
We've learned how to use a try/catch block.
We've learned how to work with exceptions and to import a custom exception.
We've learned about the getMessages method for validation errors
inside the Validator class.  We've learned how to return errors as an array.
And we've refactored our code using a single try/catch block.
Congratulations on making it this far.  Before you go, let's do a few
challenges, and then I'll see you in the wrap-up video.
Thing.  (Laughing)
You saw me going, and I was like la, la, la, la.
Custom function.  (Laughing).
That's a wrap.
Drop the mic.
Yeah, drop it.