Hey, let’s give C# a try and keep it classy.
Our variables and methods will make things very jazzy.
Oh, we'll compile that code and make our apps real smart, as we orchestrate
and riff on the smooth sounds of C#.
Welcome back to Keeping it Classy with C#.  My name is Eric Fisher.
In this level we're going to learn about groups of objects.
our bands will need to be able to contain our musicians in order to store
and retrieve them.  To accomplish this, we're going to create a list of
musicians as well as we're going to create a method to add musicians to our list.
We've created a simple Musician class to store our band's musician information.
This Musician class will have a string for the musician's name, a string
for the musician's instrument, as well as it will have its own Announce
method, which will respond with the name of the musician "on the"
and the instrument that musician plays.  Before we tackle groups of objects,
we'll cover a shorthand way to instantiate an object.
The Object Initializer allows us to instantiate and set our object's
variables in a single line.  As you can see here, we create our new
Musician object, we then set the Name variable to Robert, then the
Instrument variable to Guitar.  When we instantiate Musician with the
object initializer, we create a new instance of Musician, followed by
curly braces, which allows us to set the name and the instrument variables
between those curly braces all within one line.
To add a group of objects to our Band class, we're first going to need to know
how to group objects.
In C# we have several choices for grouping objects, but for right now
we're just going to focus on these two, arrays and lists.
Arrays are best used for a group of strongly typed objects of a fixed number.
In this line we'll instantiate a new array of Musician by using square brackets
and then providing the number of musicians we want.
In order to assign to a specific index on an array, we can use the same
square bracket notation.  On the second line we create a new Musician,
Robert on the Guitar, and set it to index 0.
On the third line we create a new Musician, Sarah on the Keyboard,
and we set it to index 1.  But what happens if Thomas wants to join
we need to change the size of our band.  To change the size of an array
we need to recreate the entire array.  This means we'll need to instantiate
an entirely new array with a size of 3.  With that done, we need to reassign
our indexes 0 and 1 to Robert and Sarah and we'll now be able to set
our index 2 to our new musician, Thomas on the Drums.
This is going to be a real pain to manage with bands constantly changing members.
This brings us to lists.  Lists are great for handling a group of
strongly-typed objects of a varying or unknown number.
We can create a list of musicians by using the List type, angle bracket,
and then whatever data type we want to put in our list.
In our example, this first line will create a musician's variable
and will instantiate a new list of musician.
On the second line, we'll instantiate a new Musician, Robert on the Guitar,
and we can add it to our musicians list by using the Add method.
On the third line, we'll add a new Musician, Sarah on the Keyboard,
using the Add method as well.  If Thomas joins the band, we don’t need
to re-instantiate the list or change anything about the list, we just
add Thomas and the list will resize automatically.
We go ahead and call the Add method on Musicians and provide our new
musician, Thomas on the Drums.  This will be much nicer for handling
bands constantly changing members and won't break if we expand musician later.
In order to add a list of musician to our Band class, the first thing
we're going to have to do is create a using statement for
System.Collections.Generic because that's where our list data type lives.
From here we'll change our Musicians variable from an integer to being
a List of Musician.  Now we have our List of Musician, we should create
a method to add to it.
We will create our new AddMusician method.  The first thing we're going to do
inside of this method is we're going to instantiate a new Musician.
One thing I would like to note is instead of providing the data type
before the variable, you may also use the var keyword, which will infer
the variable's data type based on whatever is after the equals character.
The compiled results with or without the var will be exactly the same,
so it is entirely up to preference what you use.
Next we'll ask the name of the musician to be added.
We'll then set the Name variable using Console.ReadLine.
After that, we'll ask what instrument the musician plays.
We'll then store the result on the Instrument variable.
Finally we'll call the Add method on the musician's list and provide
it the Musician object we created.  When we actually run the code though,
we're going to get a null exception error.
The error will say Object reference is not set to an instance of an object.
And if we were to look at a debugger and put our mouse over the Musicians object,
we would see that it is null.  Why is Musician null?
Shouldn’t it be a list of Musician?
Null is the absence of a value, not to be mistaken for 0, which is
a value of nothing.  When we look at our code, we'll first see that we have
our public list of musicians.  What we're telling the application is
you will be given a list of Musician, call it Musicians.
Next, we have our line of code that says Musicians.Add musician.
What we're telling the computer now is okay add a musician to musicians.
And the computer is responding, I don’t understand, you told me you were
going to give me a list, but you never actually gave it to me.
we can set the Musicians variable to have a default value of a list
of Musician.  This provides Musicians with an initial empty list of Musician.
Musicians is now working.  We've added all the underlying code we need for it.
Our code now works.  Our application now contains a list of musicians
per band as well as a method to add a musician to the list.
If we were to run the Add Musician method right now, we would see,
What is the name of the musician to be added?
The user would then provide a name, in this case Robert, What instrument
does Robert play?  In this case, Guitar, and that's it.
In the next level we'll cover wiring it up using loops.
A recap on groups of objects.  We have arrays, which are best suited
for a group of strongly typed objects of a fixed number.
We have lists, which are best suited for a group of strongly typed objects
of a varying or unknown number and in order to use lists, we must reference
the System.Collections.Generic namespace.
That's it for this level.  Now it's your turn to use groups of objects
in the challenges.  I'll see you in the next level.
Goes back to us, and I looked Carlos.
It's not name, it's band name.
Ahh.  That's a lot of band.  It is a lot of band.
Take a breath.  Well I'm sitting there, it's like…