Welcome back to Keeping it Classy with C#.
My name is Eric Fisher.  In this level we are going to cover classes.
For this level we're going to expand on the concept of band.
We're going to create a Band class to store musicians for our band.
Our band needs to be able to store the information about its musicians
as well as announce them.  In order to do this, we're going to create a
Band class that we can share methods between our Band class and our
Program class.
When we look at what makes up a band, a band has several properties.
This includes the name of the band as well as the musicians within the band,
but how exactly do we make this in code?
The class defines the structure of our band, while an object is an actual
instance of our band.  Think of a class like a blueprint and think of an object
as an example of what that blueprint describes.
So here in the left we have a Band class, here on the right we have an
example of an instance of the Band class.
To declare a class we use the class keyword followed by whatever name
we would like to provide that class.  It's standard practice in C#
to name our files whatever class they're going to contain.
So in this example, Band.cs would contain our Band class.
From here we can declare the variables that are going to make up our class.
In this case we're going to have the string Name and the integer Musicians
to represent the number of musicians we have in our band.
One thing of note is these are what's known as instance variables,
what that means is every instance of our Band class can have its own values.
Okay, so where exactly does object come into play with a class?
In this example we can see several instances of our Band class.
Each of these has their own values.  For example, the first band has
the name C Sharps with 4 musicians, the second band has the name The F Sharps
with 2 musicians, and the third band has the name The VB Nets with 1 musician.
Let's refactor our AnnounceBand method to put it inside of our Band class.
This way we can take advantage of our name variable in our Band class
instead of accepting an outside parameter for AnnounceBand.
So first let's just go ahead and move AnnounceBand into our Band class.
Next, when we look at the name AnnounceBand, it's kind of redundant having
AnnounceBand inside of Band, so we're going to knock the Band off of that.
We're also going to go ahead and just not use an input parameter, but
instead use our string variable in our Band class.
At this point we rename our method from AnnounceBand to just Announce.
We completely remove the parameter in its entirety and we just change
where we were using bandName in our Console.WriteLine to just using
our Name variable.  Well what happens when we attempt to compile this code?
When we attempt to compile this code, we're getting an error because
Console is not part of our Band class.  So the error message we will see is
The name 'Console' doesn’t exist in the current context.
This brings us to the concept of namespaces which are used to organize
our code in such a way that we can reuse our class names.
For example, our Program and our Band class live inside what's known as
the Global Namespace that is available in your application.
Whereas Console.WriteLine lives in a separate namespace called System.
Namespaces can be accessed using the following format.
Firs the namespace itself, in this case System, followed by the class name,
in this case Console, and then finally the method, in this case WriteLine.
Rewriting that every time can get really annoying, is there a shorter way
we can write this?
The answer is yes.  You can reference a namespace throughout a file
with a using directive.  At the top of our file we can add using space
and the namespace we want to make available throughout that file.
Now in order to call a method from an outside namespace, we only have to
use the class and then the method name, in this example that would be
Console.WriteLine.  We didn’t get an error doing this in the program.cs
file because we already had a using directive for usingSystem in it.
This allows us to use our Console class throughout a file and only
reference System once.
Adding a using directive for System resolves our error.
This gives Band access to our System namespace, letting our compiler know
where to find Console.  How do we create a Band object using our Band class?
We can use the statement new Band to create a new instance of a Band object.
We'll create a new variable of type Band, which we will set to a new
instance of the Band class, then we'll set the Band's name variable using
Console.ReadLine.
When we attempt to compile this code though, we are going to get an error
'Band' is inaccessible due to its protection level.
What is a protection level and why can't we access Band here?
Protection levels are set by what's known as access modifiers and they
control where we can and cannot access our code throughout our application.
There are many access modifiers, but we're only going to focus on public
and private for the time being.  The Public Access Modifier makes our code
effectively accessible anywhere we might want to get it.
Versus the Private Access Modifier only allows us to access code
within the same class.  Access modifiers default to private anytime
one isn’t provided.
By adding public in front of our class name, our method name, and our
variable names, we make that code accessible anywhere throughout our application.
Now we can finish calling announcement from our Program class.
From here we'll put public in front of our class Band, as well as
in front of our variables Name and Musicians and finally we'll put
public in front of our Announce method.  Now we can finish calling our
Announce method from our program class's Main method.
Inside Main, we're going to call the Announce method on band, which will
then use the name variable we just set to announce the band.
When we execute this code we will see, what is the name of your band?
The user will provide a name, in this case The C Sharps, and then our
application will respond with Welcome, the name of the band, to the stage!
Before we wrap up, a quick recap on classes.
C# is an object-oriented programming language based around classes.
Classes define what an object look like.  An object is an actual instance
of a class.  The default access-modifier is private, restricting code
to only be used within the same class.  To use something from a
different namespace, you can use the full namespace.class.methodname
or a using directive.
This is the end of level 2.  Now it's your turn to create and reference classes
in the challenges.  I'll see you in level 3.