Hey, let’s give C# a try and keep it classy.
Our variables and methods will make things very jazzy.
Oh, we'll compile that code and make our apps real smart, as we orchestrate
and riff on the smooth sounds of C#.
Welcome back to Keeping it Classy with C#.
My name is Eric Fisher.  In this level we are going to cover method overloads.
Let's expand on our Add command.  As you recall, our Add command was set up
so we would choose add and it would be very verbose, step by step,
on how to add a musician.  For people who have used your application
for any length, they probably just want to be able to add the musician
in a single command and be done with it.  So let's make both options available.
We can have Add go through the step by step or we can have Add the name
of the musician, the instrument they play, just add the musician all at once.
To accomplish this we're going to add a second method named AddMusician.
This method will accept two strings.  As you can see, our first AddMusician
method will accept the first parameter for the name of the musician
and then the second parameter will be the instrument that musician plays.
Using this, we will instantiate a new Musician, set its name to the
provided name, set its instrument to the provided instrument, and then
add that musician to our list of musicians.
Hang on a second, won't having two methods named AddMusician in the same class
cause us problems?
Actually no.  In C# we can reuse method names in the same class, so long as
our method signatures are different.  Reusing a method name with a
different method signature is called a method overload.
We're also going to add a line that announces the name of musician
was added.  What exactly is a method signature?
A method signature consists of the method name as well as the parameter's
types.  In this example we have a method named Add that returns a data type
integer and accepts two parameters, integer a and integer b.
When we look at the method signature this would produce, we will see
the name Add and then two integers.  We call methods using their signature,
which is why signatures must be unique.  Let's give some example of
non-conflicting and conflicting signatures.
Method signatures are what we use to call methods as well as determine
duplication.  Let's look at some code.  Here on the left we have an example
of four different methods, all these methods have the same name
but accept different parameters.  We have one that has no parameter,
one that accepts two integers, one that accepts three integers, and one
that accepts two decimals.  Looking in the right, we can see that all of these
will result in a different signature.  Now if we were to create a new method
that has a return type of decimal, has that same Add name and accepts
two decimals, this would be a problem because it will create a conflicting
signature as both the fourth and the fifth method have the signature
Add and two decimals.  This is a conflict because the return type is not
part of the method signature, only the name and the parameter types.
Okay let's get back to our code.
Looking at our AddMusician methods, there's a lot of duplication here
and duplication stinks.  If we look at our AddMusician method that doesn’t
accept any parameters compared to our AddMusician method that accepts
the two strings, both methods begin with our instantiation of a musician.
Very quickly we'll get to the part where we will set the Name variable
based on either the input parameter or user input.
The instrument will be the same way where we will set it, and in both cases
we will add the musician to our list of musicians.
These four lines are effectively doing the same thing.
In the event we were to change a parameter name or make a change to our
musician's list itself, we would have to change this in two different
places.  How can we clean up this code to reduce duplication?
Let's refactor our AddMusician method that doesn’t accept any parameters
to utilize our AddMusician that accepts the two strings.
Our other method instantiates a Musician object, so let's get rid of this one.
Since we no longer have the Musician variable, we're no longer going to
be able to set its name and instrument since it doesn’t exist.
Instead let's create a new Name variable and a new Instrument variable
to take their place.
With our Musician variable gone, let's go ahead and instead of setting
the variables on Musician, let's create a Name variable and set it
and an Instrument variable and set it.
We've created two new variables, our Name variable and our Instrument
variable to take place where we were setting the musician's name and instrument.
Now instead of using our Add method, we're instead going to use the
AddMusician method that accepts two strings.
From within our AddMusician method that collects the name and instrument,
we'll call our AddMusician method that accepts two strings.
The AddMusician method that accepts two strings will then take that data
to add the musician to our musicians list.
Now we'll create our new Add command to call our new AddMusician method.
We now need to add the logic that'll allow the user to use the command
Add the musician and the instrument they play to call the AddMusician method.
We'll accomplish this by adding an else if statement immediately after
our first if statement.  This else if statement will check to see
if the action the user provided starts with the string Add.
The next thing we're going to do is set the arguments variable using
the Split method.  We'll provide the Split method the space character.
This will create an array of separate strings split where the provided
character is used.
So here's what this would look like, if we had the string Add John Drums,
and then we called the Split method on the character space, what would happen
is the Split method would see the two spaces between Add and John and
John and Drums, and then split that string into three separate strings,
Add, John, and Drums, that would be returned as an array of strings.
Immediately after we run our Split method, we will add an if statement
to check if the argument's length is 3.  In the event the argument's length
is 3, we will run the AddMusician method providing it with the second
and third value in our arguments.  This will be the name and the instrument.
In the event our arguments does not equal 3, we will have an else statement
that will simply call our old AddMusician method, that way if our user
were to happen to type in an Add command that either had too many words
or too few words, we would fall back on our step by step guide.
Our direct Add command now works.  The user can still type in Add
to get a step by step guide in adding a musician, or they can skip
right to adding musicians by simply saying Add, the name of the musician,
and the instrument for their command.
When the user uses our step by step route we will ask them Add, Announce,
or Quit?  They will type Add to get into the step by step.
We will ask them What is the name of the musician to be added?
They'll provide us a name.  We will ask them what instrument does that
musician play?  They'll provide us an instrument and then we'll respond with
the name of the musician was added.
In the direct AddMusician route, we will ask the user Add, Announce,
or Quit?  They'll provide, Add, the name of the musician, and the instrument
and we'll cut directly to the name of the musician was added.
A quick recap on method overloads and signatures.
A method signature consists of the name and the parameter types of the method.
The method signature does not include the return type and you may reuse
method names so long as their signatures are different.
That's the end of this level and it's the end of the course.
Now it's your turn to use method overloads and identify method signatures
in the challenges.  I'll see you in the wrap up video.
Sorry, I'm stretching.
I've got to hang on for a second.
Sorry, I have an itch that must be dealt with.
That's it.  That's it?  Okay.