Welcome back to Keeping it Classy with C#.  My name is Eric Fisher.
In this level we're going to cover loops.
Our bands now contain musicians, but we're going to need to use loops
to utilize them.  In this level we'll create a loop to add musicians per band
as well as create a loop to announce the musicians.
So let's look at the flow of what we're actually looking at our application doing.
We're going to start by getting the band name, then we're going to ask
the user do they want to add a musician, announce the band, or quit
the application?  If they choose to Add a musician or Announce the band,
we'll perform that function and then we'll ask them again.
Up until the point where they choose Quit, at which point we'll exit
the application.  How do we implement repeating to ask until Quit is used?
Before we create our loop, let's notify the user of what commands are available.
As you can see here, we're going to add messages to the user, type Add
to add a musician, type Announce to announce the band, type Quit to
quit the application.  Now we can start implementing our loop.
Here we'll use a while loop.  A while loop will continue to run until
whatever condition is provided is false or we use the break keyword.
In our Main method, we'll create a new variable, repeat, and we'll set that
to true.  We'll use this as the condition for our while loop.
This while loop will run forever until repeat is false or the break keyword
is used.  So looking at the execution of this code, we'll check while,
it'll see that repeat is true, it'll run it's code, then we'll check while,
we'll see repeat is true, then we'll run its code, then we'll check while,
then we'll hit see that repeat is true, as you can see we have a problem here.
There is no way to break out of our while loop.
Be careful using loops to make sure you always have a way to break out of them
or you can get yourself stuck in a situation known as an infinite loop.
Let's add conditions for handling our commands, add musician, announce
the band, and quit the application.  Inside our while loop, first we'll
ask the user do they want to Add, Announce, or Quit.
We will then read the response and set it to the action variable.
We will be checking to see if the action variable is Add, else is the
action variable Announce, else is the action variable Quit, and in the
event that whatever they have entered is not any of these three, we will
simply respond with whatever they have typed is not a valid command.
We'll use this to handle when input doesn’t match any of our commands.
After our condition action equals Add, we will call the AddMusician method.
After our condition that checks to see if action equals Announce,
we will call our band's Announce method.
When the user uses the Quit command, the break keyword will exit the loop
immediately without running any additional code.
What would this look like if we changed the while condition instead of
using break?
If instead of using the break we were to set repeat to false, the while loop
would continue to run until it reached the end of its loop.
It would check the condition to see that it's false and then exit the
execution of the while loop.  With that done, we need to update our
Announce method to be able to announce our musicians.
In our Announce method we're going to use a foreach loop.
A foreach loop will iterate through a group of objects one by one
and run code against each of those objects.
Our foreach loop will grab each object out of the Musicians one by one
and set them to our Musician variable.  We will then call the Announce method
on each one of those objects.  A foreach loop will run until it has
either run against every single object in the group, has run into an
unhandled exception, or hits a break keyword.
Our application is now capable of doing everything we intended when we
started out this course.  It is capable of getting a band name, collecting
musician's information, announcing that band, and announcing the band's
musicians.
Our loops will allow users to repeat actions until they use the Quit command.
In this example you'll see we ask Add, Announce, or Quit?
The user can then use the Add command.  It'll ask them what the name
of the musician to be added is, they'll provide that, what instrument
does that musician play?  They'll provide the instrument, at which point
it will then again ask Add, Announce, or Quit?
And if they type Quit, the application will end.
Loops allow us to repeat code logically without rewriting it again and again.
Anytime a loop hits a break command, it will end what it's doing immediately.
All loops escape immediately when a break keyword is used.
Always make sure there is a way to escape the loop.
Infinite loops can be really bad.  While loops will escape before running
the first line in their block of code when their condition is false.
Foreach loops will escape when they have run their code against every item
in the collection.
That's the end of this level, now it's your turn to use loops in the challenges.
Have fun.