Hey, let’s give C# a try and keep it classy.
Our variables and methods will make things very jazzy.
Oh, we'll compile that code and make our apps real smart, as we orchestrate
and riff on the smooth sounds of C#.
Welcome to Keeping it Classy with C#.  My name is Eric Fisher.
In this course we're going to learn about the C# programming language.
In this level we are going to learn about methods.
Using C# we're going to create an application to store and retrieve band
information.  We're going to be able to store the name of the band,
the musicians in the band, as well as be able to announce those back
to the user.  In this level though we're only going to worry about storing
the name of the band and announcing that band name back to the user.
As you can see here, when we run our program, the program is going to
first ask the user what is the name of your band?
The user will then type the name, in this case The C Sharps, and the
application will respond with Welcome The C Sharps to the stage!
This might look familiar if you've taken our Try C# course.
All C# console applications have a csproj file as well as a program.cs file.
The program.cs file is the entry point for our application, so we will
start there.
When we open the program.cs file we'll see some pre-generated code for us.
This will include a Program class and a Main method.
With the way this code is written right now, our Main method has
Console.WriteLine Hello World!, which will present Hello World! to the console
when we run our application.  Methods allow us to break up our code into
logical blocks.  So what we're going to go ahead and do is take our announce
functionality and create a separate method for it.
But how exactly do we make a method?
To create a method we need to provide a name for our method as well as parameters.
The name of our method is just what we're going to use to call that method
in our places in our application.  The parameter will hold whatever values
we plan to pass into our method.  Some conventions to note is typically
our method's name will use what's known as PascalCase, that is the first
letter will be capitalized and every word within the method name will be
also capitalized.  Like we see here, AnnounceBand, the A in announce
and the B in Band are capitalized.  When it comes to parameters we prefix
the variable with its data type.  Like we see here, string followed by bandName.
Parameter names typically use the camelCase convention, that is you start
with a lowercase letter, but every word after that first one will be capitalized.
So in this example band is lowercase, while Name has a capital N.
This covers what our methods take in as parameters, but how do we get data
back out of our methods?
Methods also require a return type and a return statement.
The return type lets our application know what type of data we're expecting
to get back out of our method.  The return statement is how we actually get
our data out of the method.  In this example our return type is a string,
which means our application knows no matter where this method is called
we're going to get a string out of it.  The return statement returns
Welcome followed by the bandName.  Now that we've written our method,
how exactly do we call it?
To call a method we use its name, followed by the values we intend on passing
into our parameters.  In this example we're going to call the AnnounceBand
method by using its name followed by the string "The C Sharps" and are
going to set our announce variable using it.
When we call Console.WriteLine using the announcement variable, we're going
to get the response Welcome The C Sharps.  This is because AnnounceBand
prepends welcome to whatever band name we provide and we provided
the band name The C Sharps.
Method calls can also be used as arguments for other method calls.
Instead of using the temporary variable announcement, we can actually just
add our AnnounceBand method call inside of our Console.WriteLine
method call and just skip dealing a variable entirely.
At this point we should probably just go ahead and move our Console.WriteLine
into our Announce method since we're ultimately going to be doing that
anyways.
Unfortunately once we move the Console.WriteLine method into our
AnnounceBand method we're getting an error.
The error we're getting is not all code paths return a value.
This is because Console.WriteLine doesn’t return a string, it just
interacts with the console.  Well we have a return type of string,
so our method is saying we're not giving it what we said we're going to
give it.  How exactly do we write a method that doesn’t return anything?
Methods that don’t return anything should use the void return type.
In our example we're just going to swap out string for void.
If we run our code again, we can see that we get the expected results.
Also notice when we change our return type to void, we no longer require
a return statement because this method isn’t returning anything.
Now that our method is working, let's go ahead and append the string
to the stage to the end of our string in our Console.WriteLine.
When we run our code again, we'll get the results Welcome The C Sharps
to the stage!
We can now set up our Main method to call our AnnounceBand method and provide
it a band name from user input.  We'll use Console.WriteLine "What is
the name of your band?" string name = Console.ReadLine, which will get
the user input and set it to our name variable, and then AnnounceBand name.
So let us review how this program is actually going to run this code.
The first line that we'll execute will be our Console.WriteLine "What is
the name of your band?".  From here we'll accept user input using the
Console.ReadLine, which will set our name variable.
Next we'll see our AnnounceBand method call, this is going to jump us down
inside the AnnounceBand method and run our Console.WriteLine "Welcome",
the band name that the user provided, to the stage!
Once AnnounceBand finishes executing, we're going to jump back up into
our Main method, but since there is no more code inside our Main method,
it is going to finish execution.
Our working application now performs the functions we set out to accomplish
at the beginning of this level.  We're capable of storing a band name
and announcing that band name back to the user.
A quick recap on methods.  We use method names to break up our executable code
into logical blocks.  Methods contain our application's executable code.
Method names are case sensitive and to call a method we use its name
followed by the values we would like to pass into its parameters.
That's it for this level, now it's your turn to create and call methods
in the challenges.  I'll see you in the next level.