Turn up the volume and let's get deep as we all swim down into the sea.
We'll imagine a whale and underwater creatures who will be there while we learn Docker's very best features.
You'll learn a whole lot - this isn't a shocker.  Now contain your excitement as you Try Docker.
Welcome back.  So far we've learned how to run containers from the command line and create images with Dockerfiles
and in this last level we'll learn how to work with data in volumes.
If the image you're building a container with doesn’t already contain your application's files, you'll need
an extra step to get those files into your container.  There's a few different ways that you can do this,
but we're going to show you two of them right now.  The first is by copying files into the container
from the command line and like it sounds you'll just run a single command, it'll copy a file from your local
file system into the running container.  The second way is by copying files as part of the instructions
in a Dockerfile.  Doing this will make the files part of the image, so they'll be there every time you start
a new container with that image.
Now if you're already got the files then including them in the container from the start works fine, but
what about files that aren’t created yet or files that are going to change after the container's already
been started?  The problem with just copying files in is the containers won't persist data.
As soon as you stop that container from running, all of the data inside of it is gone too and won't be there
when you start it up again.  This is definitely a problem if you're writing code while you're developing,
having it disappear every time the container stops.  But imagine another situation where you have a database
in a container that resets its data each time the container is started again.
That won't be very useful.  One solution is to create a data volume.
Data volumes are a way to expose a file on your local machine to a container.
That way whenever you stop the container, none of your data is lost.
But you can still access that data from inside the container when you start it up again.
This is a great option for local development when you want a container to have access to files that you're
working in and that are actively changing.
Good luck practicing copying files and creating data volumes in the challenges and I'll see you back here
in the wrap up video where I'll talk about some next steps for learning Docker at Code School, Pluralsight
and beyond.
To get out of a lot of value.
That coffee.
I'm underwater man I can't breathe.
Is that water or is that coffee?
No I'm underwater.
Docker is like coding underwater.