Turn up the volume and let's get deep as we all swim down into the sea.
We'll imagine a whale and underwater creatures who will be there while we learn Docker's very best features.
You'll learn a whole lot - this isn't a shocker.  Now contain your excitement as you Try Docker.
Welcome to Try Docker.  I'm Jon Friskics and in this course we'll learn about the basics of working with Docker.
We'll start out by talking about containers and images before moving on to Docker files and volumes.
At the beginning of each level you'll watch a short video and then you'll dive into some interactive challenges
where you'll get to write and run real Docker commands in your browser without having to worry about
setting up your computer.  Then once you’ve got a handle on the basics, you can follow along with our
watch us build series and get your local development environment all set up.
So let's get started.
In this first level you'll learn about containers and images.  But before we do that it'll be helpful
to understand what a Linux container is.
So Linux containers are a way to create isolated environments that run code while sharing a single base
operating system.  It works like this, you've got a physical computer or a server somewhere, this might be
a server you're paying for from a hosting company or it might even be the laptop or desktop computer
that you're currently watching this video on.  That physical server runs an operating system, for now
let's assume it's running some version of Linux.  Containers will live on top of that base operating system
and they can have their own code dependencies and application code inside of them, but each one of those
containers will be completely isolated from any of the other ones that are running and by default they won't
even know anything about each other.  These containers have their own file system and useful parts of the
operating system that you can customize and control while still sharing the largest parts of the operating system
with your host.  That means the containers are really small and therefore really fast.
That said, creating Linux containers isn’t easy and requires a lot of specialized knowledge of Unix
operating systems, and that's where Docker comes in.
Docker is a tool that makes it really easy to work with Linux containers, easy enough that you don’t have to
have all that specialized Linux knowledge to get a lot of value out of working with containers.
When you install Docker on your computer or server it starts a process called the Docker Engine that
will be responsible for managing everything to do with your containers.
You might be asking yourself, how can Docker help me as a developer or a system administrator?
Well Docker has a lot of different use cases like creating a contained, controlled development environment,
creating a reproducible environment that can be shared across your entire team, or even isolating
the state of an application to help with debugging and bug reporting.
There's also use cases where Docker helps out a lot for IT and Dev Ops scenarios too, like testing
and deployment.  But in this course, to help you learn the basics, we're just going to focus on one of
those use cases, creating a containerized local development environment.
At the time of the filming of this course there's two version of Docker available, Community Edition
and Enterprise Edition.  Enterprise Edition contains features that large enterprise companies might expect,
like role-based access control and end to end security model and certified containers.
Now it's an awesome set of tools if that's what you and your company need, but in this course we're assuming
that you're just learning Docker for the first time, so Community Edition will be more than enough for us
to get started.  One of the simplest ways to install Docker is by downloading one of the official applications
that Docker the company provides.  When you download and run these applications, a Docker Engine and machine
will be automatically created and run for you and right away you'll be able to jump into the command line
and start writing Docker commands.  Of course you can always download and install Docker right from the
command line too, and Docker's installation page contains instructions for a variety of scenarios,
like installing on Linux machines, Amazon Web Server, Azure, and Windows Server.
You can visit this link here to see all of the installation options that are available.
So we know now that containers are this light weight isolated section of a Linux operating system that can be
filled up with code, like libraries and application code.  Well images are prepackaged sets of instructions,
kind of like blueprints, that can be used to build and run containers.
The reason images are so useful is that you can create a custom container and save the state of it as an image
that can then be used to recreate the container exactly as described.
You can even share images with other developers so that you can easily recreate an exact development
environment across multiple people and computers on your team.  Docker publishes a bunch of pre-built images
in the Docker Store and by default that's where Docker will look when you try to start a new container
based on one of those images.
Now it's time for you to jump into some challenges where you'll learn about how to create a container
from a preexisting image and run some commands on that container after it's running.
Have fun.