Turn up the volume and let's get deep as we all swim down into the sea.
We'll imagine a whale and underwater creatures who will be there while we learn Docker's very best features.
You'll learn a whole lot - this isn't a shocker.  Now contain your excitement as you Try Docker.
Welcome back.  In this level we're going to learn about a configuration tool called a Dockerfile.
In the last level we learned how to create containers from pre-built images on the command line, and then
how to modify those containers once they're running, but right now that's a pretty clunky process.
For example, we first had to run a container and then we had to execute multiple other commands in exactly
the right order to configure parts of that container in the way that we wanted.
A Dockerfile is a way to make that process a little bit less manual.
A Dockerfile is just a text file that contains multiple instructions that you can run with a single command
and when you run that command, the result is a brand new image that can then be used to make a container.
Before we created a container from an image and then wrote commands to modify that container.
But now we're going to write those commands in a Dockerfile and use those to create a brand new image
and then we'll make a new container from that image.  Just like at the end of level 1, you're going to learn about
some of the most important Dockerfile commands by playing through a few challenges.
Have fun and I'll see you in level 3.