(Music)
Hi everyone.  I'm Jon Friskics,
and I'm Sarah Holderness,
and in this Watch Us Build episode we're going to take the app that we
built in the Try Django course Watch Us Build, which is that Team
Directory app with Django, and we're going to expand upon that using
some of the topics that Sarah taught in the Digging Into Django course.
So what are we going to be building today?
Yeah, exactly, so we're going to continue building that Team Directory
app by adding some more features.  So if we take a look at our
internal Team Directory app that was already built in Rails,
so we've already had this for Code School, you can click on each user
and see the detail page, so we're going to add a detail page.
And then you can see here I can't edit this page, but I can edit my
own, so we're going to add some authentication that checks for that,
and then we're going to also add an edit form where we can edit our
own profile and add some different responsibilities, bio,
our birthday, and things like that.  And then the way we're going to
do authentication is using social authentication, which if we go to an
incognito window, I can show you what that looks like.
So it prompts us to log in with our Google account, so we're going to
use social authentication with Google so that it's going to check
whether we're a Code School employee or not.
Gotcha.  Very cool.  Awesome.  So let's get started.
Okay.  So what we're going to do is start with the project we created last time.
So we got to the point where we were displaying all the employees,
so we're going to clone that down and start from there.
Awesome.
So I'm going to grab the repo link there and do git clone and pull that down.
Cool.
Okay, and so last time we created a virtual environment where we could
install the packages we need, so I'm going to go ahead and do that as
well, so virtualenv.  And this just allows you to install packages
specific to a certain project so you can have different versions of
Django for different projects and different packages.
Cool.  And we didn't commit our virtualenv stuff to GitHub.
We just are going to recreate it now whenever we pull that repo down.
Right, uh-huh, yeah.  Okay, and so I did the command virtualenv -p
python3 because I'm using Python 3, and we can see that created the venv directory.
And I'm just going to activate that with source venv/bin/activate,
and now you can see there's this venv in front of my terminal,
so I know it's activated.  And then from there what we would normally
do is install whatever we need for our project, but we have an
existing project, and we already created that requirements.txt file.
Oh yeah, I remember that.
So if I look at that, so we can see we had Django, Gunicorn,
which allowed us to run a server on Heroku because we deployed our app
to Heroku last time, and the WhiteNoise was also needed for Heroku to
collect our static files.
Gotcha.
So we're just going to install everything we had for that app.
Okay.
So we're going to do pip install -r, which says we're going to give it
this file, and so it's installing Django, Gunicorn, and WhiteNoise.
Nice, so it kind of like lists our dependencies, and rather than
install them all by hand, we can just pull them out of that file and
have them install from there.
Uh-huh.
Cool.
And so that'll be helpful as well because we'll install Python Social
Auth for the social authentication, and then we can add that to our
requirements file if we wanted to play to Heroku, so that'll come in
handy later too.
Great, great.
So to get started, we'll open this project.
I actually want to open it from the level above.
Sorry.  So I'll do atom . to open it from this directory, and then now
I can see Directory, which is the outer project with my settings and
URLs, and then my current app, which is www.
Cool.
And so we can see where we left off by running our server, so we'll do
python manage.py runserver and see where we left off there.
So it says this is running at localhost port 8000, so we'll go see
what we have there.  Okay, we see it.  So yeah, so where we left off
was we're displaying all of our employees that we loaded into the
database, but we can't click on the detail page.
So we can't click on individual employees, we can't edit them,
so we're going to add that functionality now.
Awesome.
So we're going to start with adding a new detail page, and so the
process for that is a URL, a view, and a template.
Right, that sounds familiar.
Yeah, so we'll need to do all of that.  And just to look at our
example again, we'll see what link they use for their detail page.
It's at /members and then the name of the user in this special format.
And this is called a slug, so basically it makes a URL that will work,
a working URL out of the name.
Gotcha.
So it replaces spaces with dashes and makes everything lowercase.
Gotcha.  Just trying to find like a unique identifier somehow.
Yeah.  And so I think that we should do that as well, so we'll kind of
copy their model, and we'll create a slug-filled inner model that will
store this slug.
Nice, okay.
But before we get there, let's create our URL that would match,
members and then a slug.  So r and then a string, and we're going to
do start of the regex and then members/.  And then we're going to
capture the slug, so that's going to be in parentheses, and then we're
going to want to match any characters, so a-z.
Zero through 9 is also okay, and dash is okay.
And then we put that all in square brackets, so that's going to be one expression.
And then if we put the plus on there, that can be repeated multiple times.
Right, it's like more than one letter is basically is what it's saying.
Yeah, more than one letter, more than one dash, all that stuff.
Yeah, cool.
Yep.  And then if that's matched, we'll go to our detail view,
so we'll create that in a second.  And we'll also get in the habit of
naming our URLs, and that'll make it easier to link to them later,
so we'll see that later.
Okay.
So we'll use the detail name, and then while we're at it, we'll add a
name for our index URL.  Okay, so next up we would create our view.
Okay.
So in our views.py file we'll define detail, and it's going to take in
a request and that slug we were talking about, so that's going to be,
for instance, sarah-holderness, and that's going to tell us which
employee we want to look up.
Gotcha.  Yeah, yeah.
So right now I'm just going to fill in pass right now and not fill
this in yet until we've created that slug field, so I'll just come
back to this in a second.
Okay.
And then in models.py we're going to add our slug field to our model.
So we can do models.SlugField, and we'll just give it the same
max_length as the name.  And what that's going to do is Django is
going to help verify that that's actually a slug and in that format
that is a viable URL.
Nice.
Yeah.  So now that we've added that, we need to do a couple things.
We need to run migrations, and we'll do that now with python manage.py makemigrations.
Because we've changed the database, we need to ---.
Uh-huh.  And it says provide a one-off default now.
So that's fine.  We'll just enter the number 1.
And so that'll be the default for everyone, but we'll replace that in a second.
Okay.
So we've added the field slug to person is what is in our second
migration file, and now we can run python manage.py migrate to
actually apply that.
Cool.
Yeah.  So another thing is last time we used this fixture to load all
of our data into the database, each employee's name and everything,
and I went ahead and created another one for the slug field.
Oh, nice.
Yeah, because we don't want them all to have the same default value.
Sure.
Yeah, so we just want to start that out with some working slug fields.
Cool.
So let me go grab that.  (Working)
Okay, so now that we have that field, we can run our loaddata command,
and this is just if you have one of those fixtures.
And it's all one word, loaddata, and then wherever that file is.
And so it says installed 43 objects.  And so now if we go and look at
our admin, it should have that slug field.
Nice.  Can we check out that slug-added file and see what that looks like too?
Yeah.  So basically, it's the exact same as the file we had before.
We just added this slug field for each employee.
Oh, nice.
Yeah.
Very cool.
So now if we, since we're running our server, we can go into the admin.  (Working)
Okay, so you have a slug field there.  And then if you wanted to edit
it to something like ---, so it checks whether it's valid, and it says
it has to be letters, numbers, or hyphens.
Nice.  It's just like built-in validation into that slug field type.
Yeah.
Cool.
And then we can even take that a step further and override the save
method here and so that for each new employee that we want to create,
once it saves to the database, it'll automatically create the slug
field from their name.
Oh, nice, yeah.
Yeah, so that's really helpful to kind of automate things.
Cool.
So we're going to do def save, and this takes in *args and **kwargs.
And what we're doing is we're overriding the default save value so it
takes these arguments by default.  And what this is is this would be
if you had an ordered list of these things in that order or if you had
a dictionary where you specified name equals this, email equals this.
So that's what that means.
Gotcha.
And here we're just going to --- or I think this also has to take in self.
Oh yeah, probably because if we're going to check like the state of the model.
Yeah, yeah.  Okay, so one check we can do is if not self.pk.
So that's saying basically has this been already created?
If it has a primary key, it has, so we don't want to override the save
thing and create a slug.
Gotcha.
So we're just checking that.  Otherwise, we're going to set slug equal
to, and here we're going to use a built-in Django function.
So we're going to do from django.utils.text import slugify.
Yeah.  So it's going to slugify our name.  And then once that's done,
we'll call the super save method, which is super, takes in the model
name, self, the *args, and the **kwargs again.
Okay, so yeah, so we'll give that a try and see if that works.
Okay.
I'm not sure if we have to run a migration for that, so ---
Because we changed the model.
Right.  So let me just see what happens here.
Oh, another thing that we'll need to do, and this will require a
migration, is we want to allow blanks because basically we don't want
anybody to fill in the slug.  We want to do it for them.
So we want the blank to be True, so we will have to run a migration for that.
Gotcha.
So we'll just run a migration again and then apply that and run our server.
Okay, so now if we go into Persons, and let's add a new person,
so we will leave the Slug blank.
Okay.
So now if we --- oh, I thought I'd see it here, but oh.
Oh, it looks like maybe our save method didn't work because it's not here.
So let's see what happened there.
Oh, so I think what's happening is in super ---
We're not calling save.
--- we're not calling save ever, right, so just probably call super on
the first two and then like .save I guess with like parentheses.
Yeah, exactly.
Cool.  Yeah, that makes sense.
Alright, so let's give that a try.  Oops!
Oh, we turned the server off maybe.
Alright.  Okay, so we'll go ahead and create new person.
Okay, so we'll save it without a slug, and if we go back in,
it generated a slug for us.
Very cool.  Yeah, so we don't really have to worry about ever making
one now because it's always going to be there.
Uh-huh.  It's really helpful.
Nice.
And it makes it a little less error prone too because you're doing it
for them, so it's not going to be some random name.
It's actually going to be based on their name.
Nice.
So now that that's set up, we actually have a slug to work with in our detail view.
So we can look for the person that matches that slug field, so we can
say person is equal to People.  Or sorry.  Sorry.
I forgot the name of the model.  Okay, person is equal to the Person
model .objects.get, and we'll do slug=slug.
And so that's saying we want the person slug field equal to this slug
field we passed in.
Oh, from the URL, right?
Right.
Cool.
And then we will return render of the detail template that we still
need to create.  So we'll pass the request detail.html and the person
we just looked up.  And we have to pass a person in this dictionary.
Sure.
So now we can go ahead and create that detail template.
So that goes in our templates directory folder, and we'll call it detail.html.
And just to get some stuff in there, I'm going to copy from index.
Yeah, it makes sense to not have to do all the boilerplate.
Yeah, I don't have to do all the boilerplate.
I'm just going to display these four things for now, the image, name,
title, and email, and I'm going to take out the for loop.
Right, because there's just one now that we're passing in, not multiple.
And the nice thing is I used the variable name person, so this should
still all work.
Oh, great.
So we're just going to display that for now.
And remember our goal is to get to something like this, so we'll have
to add some more fields, but right now we're just going to see if we
can get this basic information displayed.
Sure.
So, yeah, so that should work.  So I'll go ahead and see if that's working.
So we don't have a link set up, so I'll have to manually type in
/members/adam-fortuna, and that will go here.
So it seems like it's working.
Definitely.
Yeah, and so now we can just link there from the home page to make it
easier for ourselves.  So we can make the whole image a link and do href=.
Here is where we can use that URL naming that we talked about earlier.
So we named this URL detail, so in here, sorry, in the index template,
sorry, I'll close all the other ones just to make it better,
we can use this url tag, the name of our template, and then any
parameters it needs, and it needs the slug.
Oh, right.
So we can do person.slug.
Right, because it's in there in that person object.
Oh, actually I don't think I need the double brackets because we're
already inside this tag.
Gotcha, gotcha.
Okay, so let's see if that's working on this page.
Oops, I had forgot to close some stuff.  Okay, so I have the anchor tag.
Does it close the anchor maybe?
Yes.  Okay, so close that, and then the image will go inside,
and then I can close the anchor tag.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Okay, and hopefully that doesn't ---.  Okay, so now we can click on
the image, and it'll take us to the detail page for everybody hopefully.
Yeah, yeah.  Awesome.
Okay, so we have the detail, URL, view, and template set up right now.
So the next thing we wanted to do was if we look at our example app
that we're aiming for again is add some of these details.
So we've got RESPONSIBILITIES, BIO, Twitter, GitHub, Website, and Birthday.
Maybe that's what we'll start with there.
Okay, yeah, sounds good.
Okay, so ---
So are these going to be --- we're just going to be able to kind of
copy the same fields, maybe make them different data types and
everything to get all that, right?
Right.
Just sort of change the names and stuff?
Right.  So responsibilities will be a CharField, bio will be a
CharField, same for Twitter, GitHub, and then the only thing that's
probably different is we can make the birthday a date time field,
and the phone number we could make a CharField, or we could actually
do some phone number validation on that and use a regex validator.
Cool.  So we'll fast forward as we're typing all this ---
Yeah.
--- starting now.  (Working)
So now that we have all of these fields that we want to display in our
detail page, we'll go ahead and edit our detail template.
Cool, yeah.  Good idea to show them all in there.
And we'll just add them as paragraphs for now.
We probably won't cover too much CSS style in this Watch Us Build,
and we'll just get the data on the page and add that at a future time.
Yep.
Okay, so we'll display the Twitter, GitHub, and then their birthday.
Okay, so now that we've added those fields, we have to do a migration.
Sure, yeah.  It's a lot of new data.
Yeah, so python manage.py makemigrations.  And so it says all the
fields we've added, which looks correct.  And to apply those to the
database we run migrate, and then we can take a look at what that looks like.
If we go to our Directory site and click on --- oops, let me refresh that.
What did I do?  Oh, maybe ---
Oh, was it because we didn't have any data in it so it just made like
empty --- maybe?
Let's look at our views.  So if we go to the detail view and we have person ---
Right.  Is it just that like person.bio, person.twitter has no data
yet because our fixture didn't have that data, right?
Oh, right.  Yeah, sorry.
So it is showing it.  It just doesn't look like anything.
But the birthday was like auto-calculated or whatever.
Yeah, sorry, so yeah.  So let's go ahead and add some fake stuff.
So I have lots of responsibilities.  I do a lot of stuff with Python.
Okay, sarahbtalk, sarahbees.  Okay, so I'll save that, and if we go back, okay.
Alright, so yeah.  So we have our detail page working.
So what we'd like to be able to add now is the ability for users to
edit their own profile.
Yeah, that's a good call because we're doing all this through the
admin right now, but like eventually we don't want to like give
everyone an admin login ---
Right.
--- so we need an edit page somewhere.
And so if we look at that, if I go to the example app and go to my
profile and press the Edit button, I see a form here.
So that's what we want to create.
Cool.
So to do that, we can create a forms.py file.
So that's in our www app forms.py, and from here we'll do from django
import forms, and that's where we'll create our new form,
which is going to be a model form so that it can directly get all the
fields from our model and make things a little easier.
Oh, right.  So we don't have to like manually create all the fields.
We can just sort of run a command that says look at the model,
find all this data, look at all the data types, and just try to build
the appropriate inputs for us.  That'd be convenient.
Yeah, and it does a lot of stuff for us like validation and saving to
the model, so yeah.
Nice.  Are we going to also have to import the model then if we do that?
Yes.
Cool.
So from .models import Person.  Okay, so now we can go ahead and
define class PersonForm.  That is a forms.ModelForm.
And then here we'll say --- I'm kind of forgetting what goes in here,
but I think what we have to start is say this is a Meta class so it's
based off a model, and so we define our model as Person and then our fields.
Right.  So this is going to be like all the different fields in our model, right?
Right.  So basically we're going to want everything except for the
slug because we don't want people to edit that.
Gotcha.
So I'm just going to copy that in and try and get rid of all this.  (Working)
Alright, so now that we have all those fields entered, we can go ahead
and create the edit page, so we'll want to go through creating the
URL, view, and template again.
Awesome.
Yeah.  So the URL is basically going to be the exact same as the
detail, but with edit on the end, so /edit here.
And then we'll go to the edit view, and we'll name this edit.
Cool.
Yep.  And then we can go to views and create our edit view,
and that is going to again take in a request and a slug so we know
which person we're editing.  And then this is going to instantiate
the person form that we just created and then pass that to the
template for displaying.
Okay.
So we can do form = PersonForm, and I'm going to need to import that
so it knows what I'm talking about.  And then I can display that in a
template, so return render, pass the request and edit.html,
and then we're going to pass the form.  Now in our template,
so we're going to create an edit template, and this is going to be
pretty simple just displaying the form.
Okay.
But now what we have is we have a couple of templates now that we're
going to want to have the same like look and feel for, so we can use
template inheritance here to kind of make all of our pages inherit
from the same template and then have the same look without having to
change it in each template.
Gotcha.
So it's kind of like a parent template.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.  We'll call it on the comment base.html.
I'm guessing probably the stuff that goes in there is like the head
tag and that kind of stuff, right?
Right.
Cool.
So we will go ahead and copy all this stuff up to main and put that in base.
And then I'm just copying this from index.html.
And then this is going to be where we tell it to put the content from
our child templates, so we'll create something called a block here,
and we can name it content.  And then we need to end our block.
Okay, so that's going to be our base template, and then in index what
we can do is delete all that stuff, but add our block tag, so we'll add one ---
Gotcha.
--- at the bottom.
And it's going to try to match that up so when it loads base and it
sees the block content it's going to like look at everything in index
and kind of like put that inside of it, right?
Right.
Cool.
And we're going to instead of loading static files, we don't need any
static files in here anymore since the CSS is being loaded in the
base.html file, we're just going to put extends base.html.
Nice.
I think that needs to be in quotes.  Okay, so let's just make sure
that's working before we move on with the detail page and everything.
Probably need to run my server or --- forms.py line 6 we have in here.
So model is Person.  So it looks like I accidentally used a colon
instead of equal here.
Oh yeah, that makes sense.
Yeah.  So that's in our forms.  Okay, so if we go back here,
we can see no more errors.  The server is running.
Cool.
We can look at our home page, and it looks the same now that we've
added that template inheritance.  So we can go ahead and add that to
our detail and edit pages.
Nice.
Yeah.  So we'll just replace that here.  Need an endblock tag.
Okay, so now when we go into our edit template, we'll start with the
block content and extend from base.html.  Okay, so we're going to want
a form, an HTML form with the action as the URL back to this edit page.
Okay.
So we'll just put action as dot so it just goes back to this page.
And we could have a separate URL to handle this, but we're just going
to handle it in the same view and check whether it was a post or not,
and so that's what we'll do here.
Cool.
And so we'll add method equal to post.  Okay, so then also in here,
since it is a post, we talked about this in the course, you need a STS  RF token.
Oh, right.
And so you use the Django tag csrf_token, and that's just something
Django provides to prevent against cross-site request forgeries.
So as long as you have that token, your app should know you're not
coming from like a malicious site.
Cool.  It's like inject, like a hidden input field or something with a
token in it.  Cool.
And then now we can display our form, so we'll do form.as_p.
So that will display the form as a paragraph with each field on a separate line.
Okay.
And then we'll want a button there, so we can do input type.  (Typing)
Okay, so we have all the basic building blocks for displaying the form right now.
It's not going to process it, but at least we want to check that it's displaying correctly.
Sure.
So if we go back here, and then we can click on a person and then go
to /edit, and that should display the form.
So let me just check because that doesn't seem to be working here.
So /edit goes to edit.
Is it the extra slash on the end maybe?  Like do you need to put slash
after edit on the URL?
I think that's optional, so I don't think it should hurt anything that
it's there, but we can take it out and see.
What about is it because the second URL isn't terminated, the detail, views.detail?
Oh yeah, that's exactly what it is.
Cool.
Yeah, good catch.
Yeah, so what was happening was because it wasn't terminated with a
dollar sign, it was saying like just look for any URL with that
beginning, and then just like if you see anything with that beginning
at all, then that means that's the one we're looking for.
So even /edit would've continued on or whatever past that.
Right, exactly.  So don't forget the dollar sign.
So yeah, caret starts it, dollar sign ends it.
So it looks like we have all those now.
Cool.
So if we go back over here, now we can see the form to edit,
and we're on this user Adam Fortuna.
Nice.
Okay, so one thing we want to add is if we take a look back at our
example app again, see how all my data is already there,
all the existing data so I can add to it?
Yeah.
So we like that to show up instead of just blank.
Okay, cool.
So we can do that in our view, and then we'll also want to handle the submitted form.
Okay.
So to do that, we can set up where we'll handle processing the form,
and what we'll do is we'll check if request is a post, and we can do
that with request.method is equal to POST.
And right now we'll just put pass, but this is where we'll process the form.
Gotcha.
And then otherwise we'll just display the form, which is what we did before.
And then we'll also want the person to pass into the form that we're editing.
Okay.
So again, just like we looked up the person here by the slug field in
the detail page, we'll do the exact same thing, and then we can pass
that into the form.
Okay.
And then when we go and edit that, it should look good.
Cool.
I think there is something I'm forgetting though is this person needs
to be in a dictionary format actually for that to work, so we need to
do --- we're going to use this special function from forms.models,
so from forms.models import model_to_dict.
So we can do person_dict = model_to_dict, so that function on the
person that we looked up.
That's pretty neat.  So that's just going to take all the fields and
stuff and map it to dictionaries probably with keys equal to the model
field names, right?
Right, yeah.  If we printed that out, that's exactly what it would be.
Nice.
And so that's what we need to add the initial data to our form.
Cool.
So if we go look at that, and let's check that our server is still running.
Okay, no module named forms.
Oh, just probably django.forms.
Yeah.  From django.forms.  Okay.  Let's make sure our server is running.
That's really neat.  I didn't know that Django and the server would do that.
I've noticed that a couple of times where there was an error and you
just made one change in the file, and then you didn't have to like
quit the server and start it again.
Yeah, it's really nice.  It auto updates.
Just picks it up.  Yeah, that's really cool.
So whoops.  I don't know if I need to or if I --- and then go here and then edit.
Okay, NameError.
POST is not defined.
Oh, that is probably my bad.  Does need to be a string.
Oh, yeah.
Okay, yeah, so ---
Cool.
Okay, so then if we look at our form, it is populated with the initial
data we had for Adam.
Yeah, and that's the data from the database basically, right?
Uh-huh.
Cool.
So we can submit this, but it's still not going to do anything yet.
Right, it's just going to pass that method.
Right, so we need to process the form.
Okay.
So as we saw in the course, we can create the form from the
PersonForm, and what we're going to do is pass it data=request.POST,
so all of the POST's data.  And then we're also going to pass it,
we didn't do this in the course, instance=person, and that's that
person we looked up by the slug field.  And the reason we want to do
that is because when we do, which we're going to eventually do
form.save, that would create a brand new person.
So basically we're saying we want to update this existing person.
Oh, interesting.  So that's how you do an update.
Yeah.
Very cool.
So we're going to check if form.is_valid.  Then we're going to do
form.save, and this is a function is_valid.
And for save, you can set commit equal to True here,
and that'll commit it straight to the database.
If we had extra stuff we wanted to save on top of it, we would set
that to false, but so that's good.
Cool.
And then once we edit, I guess we'll just redirect back to the detail page.
Yeah, that makes sense.
So then you can visualize what you just edited.
Cool.
So to do that, we can use the redirect shortcut function and do return redirect.
And then this is where we can again use the URL name.
And so what we can do is use this function called reverse,
so that's from django.core.urlresolvers.  And so what this does is it
will look up the URL for you based upon the name.
So the detail is the name of the URL and then any arguments it needs,
which here is going to be the slug because that's the argument the
detail URL needs if we look back over here.
Gotcha.
So it's expecting this slug value.
But the reason you want to do that is because you could just hard code
a string in there.  We could just say go to this string/member/slug.
But then if we update the URL here, it'll break.
So it's a way to make it point to this one place where we define the URL.
Cool.
Okay, so that should process the form and save it to the database.
Okay.
So if we go back and refresh, okay, so Adam let's say supervises
product planning or something as his responsibilities, and his bio is
he loves Orlando.  And then we submit that.
Okay, and so we can say supervises product planning and he loves Orlando.
Very cool.
So we have the edit form working now, so that's awesome.
Yeah, that's awesome.  It was some work to get there, but now it's
really cool to just kind of see how it all fits together because one
of the things I noticed about this was that there was only one place
where you even defined any of the fields, and that was in the person form, right?
Right.
And everything else, just because it was defined that way,
you didn't have to constantly say set name equal to this,
set responsibilities equal to this.  It's just sort of inferring all
of that stuff as you go through the different views and templates.
And we can just do form, not save, yeah.
Yeah, very cool.
Yeah, so we added a couple extra things that weren't in the course.
We added initial data to the form, we updated a user instead of saving
a new user by passing the instance, and then we've added this slug
field that we haven't seen before.
Yeah, neat.
So a couple new things we've gone over.  And then the next new thing
we want to do is social authentication.
Nice, yeah, right because anybody can still just hit that /edit URL
right now ---
And edit anybody.
--- edit anybody else's stuff, which is probably really fun,
but maybe not good for the team morale.
Yeah.  And then another reason you might want to have authentication
is this could be your company's directory, and so you don't want
everybody to see it, so we'll just have Code School people viewing our directory.
Sure.  Cool.  So how do we do that?
So basically we're going to use a Python package called Python Social
Auth, and that takes care of a lot of the setup for dealing with
Google, Facebook, Twitter, and passing the tokens and saving them to users.
So it does a lot of the work for you.
Nice.
So to do that, we're going to do pip install python-social-auth.
And it had some dependencies with it like requests, oauthlib, and some other things.
So if we look at pip freeze again to see what we have installed ---
There's a bunch in there now.
Yeah.  What we had before was just Django, Gunicorn, and WhiteNoise,
so everything else was a dependency of Python Social Auth.
Cool.
Yeah.  So now the first step to get that started using that is we have
to add some settings, and one of those is telling Django that we've
now installed this app.
Okay.
So we can add that to INSTALLED_APPS with social.apps.django_app.default.
Okay, we're going to need to add some context processors to our
template's variable, and that's just going to help to know which page
we should be displaying.  So it kind of takes care of some default
URLs and telling us what page we should be on.
Cool.
Social.apps.django_app.  (Typing)
Okay, and then the next variable we're going to add I'm going to add
towards the end.  I'm just kind of picking where I want to add these
variables for social authentication.  I'm going to add right above the
static files variables we have and just comment this as social authentication.
And then we're going to override the variable called
AUTHENTICATION_BACKENDS, and we're going to add Google to this.
So that's going to be a list.  (Typing)
Okay, so what we just added was Google OAuth2 as a social backend,
and then we still have the default Django backend that's going to go with it.
Cool.
And then the next two variables we need are the social Google OAuth2
key and secret.  And so what we need to do to get those is to log into
the Google developer console.
Okay, so Google gives us those two key and secret tokens, and then we
can use that in our app.
Exactly, and then they'll know what app we're coming from and all that.
Cool.
So we go to console.developers.google.com.
And so I was already playing around with this, so I should already
have a few here.  Yeah, so I'm going to go to Credentials,
Create credentials, and then OAuth client ID.
Web application, so I'll just say Team Directory, and then the URL here.
So this right now is just our localhost, so 127.0.0.1 port 8000.
And then for the Authorize redirect, oops, sorry, I'm having trouble
copying and pasting.  Delete that.  Okay, and then /complete/google-
oauth2, and that's where the Python Social Auth is going to take us
after they log in.
Okay.
So we'll go ahead and create that, and it's going to give us our key
and our secret.  So we can go and copy that into our app.
And does the variable for that have to be a specific thing?
Yeah, so SOCIAL_AUTH_GOOGLE_OAUTH2_KEY.  And so you can look all of
these up in Python Social Auth's docs.  But yeah, so Twitter doesn't
have this OAUTH2 extension, but since Google has different versions of
things, you need that.
Gotcha.
Okay, so that's the key.  Then we're going to create a variable for
the secret and get the secret.
Cool.
Okay, so we have that created.  So now when we go to the URL
localhost/login/google-oauth2, it should make us log in, so we'll just
give that a try.
Cool.
I think I'm forgetting one thing is we have to add some special URLs,
and we could do that in our app since we only have one app or in our project.
So I think I'll add it to our project just because then it's available
to all apps.  And that's --- I forget what that is.
Okay, so that is an empty string.  We're going to include.  (Typing)
Okay, so this is just making all of the URLs available within our app.
And then if we go to login/google-oauth2, it'll know what to present us with.
Gotcha.
So we don't have to handle anything.  We don't have to create a view
or a template because that's already created within this package we installed.
Nice.
Yeah.  So that should work, so we'll give that a try.
Make sure our server is still running.  Nope.
Okay, so I'll run our server.  Oh, I forgot, so basically the package
that we installed has some migrations that we have to apply because it
creates its own models for the database.
Gotcha.  Do we have to make migrations too, or does it just do that for us?
No.  Yeah, so if we try to run that, it should tell us.
There's nothing to do, but I'm ---.  Yeah, okay.
So then we can migrate.  Okay, so you can see it applied a few that
just came preinstalled with the package.
Cool.
So then we can run our server, and it looks good.
So now we'll go to localhost/login/google-oauth2, and that's going to
prompt us to log in, and I'll log in with my Code School email address.
It says Django Project would like to have offline access.
And we're going to allow that.  And whoops, what did I do?
It looks like it's looking for accounts/profile.
Okay, so I realize what this error is for is we forgot some redirect
URLs that we have to define in settings, so it's trying to find
something that we don't have.
Cool.
So if we go back to settings.py, and we can add this right before our
key and secret.  (Typing)
Okay, so now we have all of those URLs entered, so let's give that a try again.
Make sure our server is running and try and log back in.
Okay, and so that brings us back to our home page.
Nice.
And so what this has done is if we go and look at our models,
you can see with our migrations there are some models that were added
with the package, and we don't really need to worry about those.
But by default it edits our user model.  Okay, so if we look at our
users, we have that sholderness username that I just logged in with
from Code School.
Nice.
So what is interesting is by default Python Social Auth just helps you
with adding new users to this user model, and then what our example
app does is actually check if those are Code School employees.
So that's kind of something extra, but we can add that functionality.
So yeah, so that's probably what we'll do next.
Cool.
So just so we know if we look up Python Social Auth and go to the
third link down, which is python-social-auth.readthedocs, you can look
at all of the docs here.  And there's something called the Pipeline,
and what we can do is see that there are some --- by default,
the Pipeline runs all of these functions in order.
And what we're going to do is kind of interrupt with our own function,
so it's nice you can add that into the pipeline.
Yeah, definitely.
So you could do like save a user's profile.
You could send a verification email.  What we're going to do is just
make sure this person has a Code School email address.
Okay.
So we're going to override this variable in settings, so in settings
we're going to add that, and then we're going to put this in our view
so we can do the app name.views, and we'll do verify_email.
Okay.
And then in our views we'll go ahead and add that function.  (Typing)
So if we look at the example they had again, this takes in certain
parameters, which are the backend, user, response, *args,
and **kwargs, so we're going to need the same.
Okay.
We can check if the backend name is Google, and that's going to be google-oauth2.
Okay, and then this is where we'll check the email.
Okay, so we can do --- so basically we want to see if there's an
existing person in our Person database that has an email that matches
this person's email.
Gotcha.
So we'll look up existing_person will be the variable name,
and that'll be Person.objects.get(email=, and this is where we need to
look up the email in the response, so we can do kwargs.get('detail')).
And I already printed this out.  If we look at the docs page again,
we can see from Facebook kwargs looks like this.
It's a dictionary.  We could, if this was Facebook, look up the email
and just do get email, and that would give us the email.
But in Google's data it has a details dictionary within this,
and then we get the email, so we're going to do .get('detail').get('email')).
And I printed that out to see that before, but we'll just skip that for now.
So now if those emails are the same, we know that we have an existing
person and we can allow this person to log in.
Okay.
So if not existing_person, then we'll show like an error message.
So we will import HttpResponse and just show a text message for now.  (Typing)
So from django.http we're g got get HttpResponse and return that here.
You don't have access is what we'll say.  Okay, so that should be all
we need to get that working, so we'll give that a try and see if it
kicks me out if I try to log in with my other email address that's not
a Code School email address.
Okay.
So we'll make sure it's working and running.
I'll just open an incognito tab since I'm already logged in over there.
Oh, another thing is we want the home page to actually go to that login page.
Oh, right, we're just like manually typing it right now.
Right.
We kind of want that to show up.
Okay.
So we can do that in our view.  So in our index view we can check if
the user's authenticated and then show them the home page.
But if they're not, we're going to bring them to this Google login page.
Gotcha.
So if request.user.is_authenticated, then we'll display the page as we
were doing before; otherwise, we'll redirect, and we'll redirect to
/login/google-oauth2.
Do you have to return a redirect or just?
Yes, return.
Alright, cool.
Thanks.  I always forget that.  And I'm not sure if we have to import
this function is_autheticated.  I think it might be built in.
It's a method on the request.user, so we probably don't.
So I'll give that a try.  It seems like the server is still working.
So again, I just want to open an incognito window since I'm already
logged in, and I'm going to try to go to the home page now,
which is at localhost port 8000.  And now it's going to ask me to log
in, which is exactly what we wanted.
Cool.
So I'm going to use a non-Code School email address, and it should
tell me that I don't have access.  (Typing)
Okay, let's see what happened here.
What was the error again?
Usually I go to the last one to see what it was here.
Oh, is it --- I don't think it's Person.objects.get.
It's a filter, right?  It's not objects.filter?
Oh, yeah.  Right, because if we use get and there isn't a person,
it's going to give us an error, whereas filter, if it doesn't find
anything, it'll give us an empty list, and then we can do if not existing_person.
Gotcha.
So yeah, so something to keep in mind with get is you have to know
there's an existing person there.
Gotcha.
Okay, so let's try that again.  And we're going to go to localhost.  (Typing)
Okay, so it should tell us we don't have access.
Same error.
Oh, kwargs.get.
Oh, it's details also, not detail.  I don't know if that matters.
Okay.
Okay, let's try that again with details.  (Typing)
Okay, so it said you don't have access.
Cool, so that means it got into that verify email,
it correctly identified that you're not in that response,
and then gave you that message.
Uh-huh.
Cool.
And so one last thing we want to do is we want to add the ability to
check if you are the person editing to allow you to edit.
So what we'll do is we'll add a link on the detail page for editing,
so we'll just do a link or tag linking to the edit page, so we'll do
url 'edit' and pass it person.slug, and that will display the URL to edit.  (Typing)
But what we'll do around that is we'll check if the user's authenticated.
So we can use a Django template tag and do user.is_authenticated.
Do you have to do it like as a conditional, or is it just?
Yeah.
Okay, cool.
So if user is authenticated, and then we have to end our if statement
in the template.  So it'll only show that edit button that'll take you
to the edit page if you're authenticated.
Gotcha.
So I can't remember if I'm authenticated or not here, so I'll just go
to the home page.  Yeah, so I'm authenticated.
If I try to go to Adam's page --- oh, if user is authenticated.
Oh, right because you are authenticated.
Right.
But you want to check if you're Adam or if you're Sarah.
So never mind.  That's actually not what we want to do.
We can do if user.email == person.email.
Gotcha, see if you're like the same user.
Yeah, to check if I'm the same user.  Okay, let's try that again.
So refresh that.  I tried to go to Adam's page, but there's no edit link.
And then if I try to go to my page, there should be.
Yes, and then I can edit.
Nice.
So cool.  So we added the Python Social Auth, which was kind of a lot
of work, but I think it's really cool because that's what a lot of
websites use, and it makes it a lot easier on your users because it
just grabs your email address, username, and all that stuff.
Yeah, and even though it was a lot of work to get set up right and
test, like it still adds so many features that we didn't have to write
ourselves too, right?  Like there's so much built-in functionality.
And you can pretty much be sure like a lot of people are going to have
a Google or Facebook login even if they don't make a login for your
site, so it can be a way to get users that already have a way to log
in into your product quicker.
Right.  And then we added that extra step to check that their email is
a Code School email and then the other step to make sure you are
editing your own page.
Nice.
So I guess that's where we want to leave off ---
Yeah.
--- unless you want to, I don't know, do anything else.
No, I think that's good.  I think we hit a lot of cool stuff in this
screencast and definitely a lot of even like new things that we didn't
necessarily show in this level of detail in the course, so it could be
a great companion to go through this.  And if you haven't been trying
along on your own as we're going through this stuff, it's probably a
good time to jump in and try to do some of this stuff yourself and
even deploy to Heroku at the end like we did in the first screencast.
Yeah, that's what I was going to say is because we set it all up and
cloned that repo, we could just go ahead and push this to Heroku
really easily, so ---
Yeah, yeah, awesome.
--- you can try that as well.
Yeah, so thanks for watching.
Thanks, bye.
Bye.
(Music)