You're watching On Fire With Phoenix.  I'm Carlos Souza, and in this
section we'll learn how to use contexts to create new videos.
This is the current code for the new action in our VideoController.
As you can see in this example, the controller needs to explicitly
import Ecto.Changeset and then call the change function in order to
create a changeset.  This illustrates how the controller is tightly
coupled to the Ecto library for generating new video forms.
This is bad design.  Let's see how we can fix this.
We'll start by moving the changeset code over to the Video schema.
Notice the Video module is now part of the Screencasts namespace.
In other words, Video is a submodule of Screencasts.
We'll slightly change the code for creating a changeset.
Instead of using the change function, we'll now use cast.
We've used this function previously for creating new videos before
adding them to the database, but it's also valid for creating
changesets to be used in forms.  By doing it this way, we can later
reuse the changeset function.
In order to call cast and reference Video as just video, we need these
two lines as well, import Ecto.Changeset and alias FireStarter.Screencasts.Video.
In the Screencasts module, we'll define a change_video function taking
a Video schema as an argument.  Inside this function we'll call
Video.changeset, the function we've just created in the Schema module.
We'll give it the video and an empty map as arguments.
This change_video function will be called from the VideoController.
Inside the new action of VideoController, we now call
Screencasts.change_video in order to create a changeset, giving it the
Video schema as argument.  In this example, it's fine to reference the
schema as an argument like this.  As you can see, the index action no
longer relies on Ecto for creating a changeset.
Lastly, let's decouple the code that creates new videos.
Here in the create action we can see the code is highly coupled with
Ecto by calling the cast function and Repo by calling the insert function.
That's one example of VideoController knowing too many details about
how new videos are created.  Let's fix this.
Inside the Screencasts context, we'll define the create_video function.
This function takes a map with the user submitted attributes as its single argument.
Inside its body, it uses the Video schema along with the user data to
create the changeset and then pipes that into the Repo.insert
function, returning a tuple expected by the case statement in the controller.
As we can see in this example, it's okay to call Repo from the context module.
Back to the controller, we can replace the old code in the create
action with a single call to the Screencasts.create_video function.
That's the only thing that needs to change in the create action.
Calling create_video still returns a tuple expected by the case statement.
As you can see, the create_video function is all VideoController needs
to know in order to create a new video.  The code in the controller is
now shorter and fully decoupled from Repo and Schema.
We've reached the end of the course.  It's your turn to practice some
more context in the challenges, and I'll see you back in the wrap-up video.
The list rexis, bleh.
Rexis.  Oh my gosh.  Rex.
Some relationship code.  Relationship code.
That sounds so deep.