Yeah, cruise down that strip and take in the neon lights baby,
as we get well equipped to take our apps to new heights, yeah!
We'll create records, take in the view — our route is surely scenic too.
We'll use Elixir as we travel through On Fire With Phoenix,
On Fire With Phoenix, On Fire With Phoenix, yeah!
You're watching On Fire With Phoenix.  I'm Carlos Souza, and in this
section we'll learn how to write Phoenix code that outputs HTML forms.
So far we've written code to read from the database and list videos on a page.
Now we need a new page so users can type data in a form,
submit the form, and then see the newly created video listed on the page.
In this level, we'll learn how to do just that.
This will involve three major steps.  First we'll add two new routes,
one to render the form page and one that will receive the form
submission and create a new record.  Next, we'll learn how to use
Phoenix's form helpers to generate HTML forms more efficiently.
Finally, we'll learn how a typical create action looks in a controller.
This is where we read user submitted data and create new records in the database.
This is how the workflow looks from another perspective.
First, to render the form, we make a get request to /videos/new.
For example, by typing the URL in a browser.
The router routes the request to the VideoController.new function or
action, which then renders the form.  When the form is submitted,
then a post request is made to /videos.  The router routes the request
to the VideoController.create function, which reads user data,
creates the new video, and redirects back to the video listing page
where we see the newly created video.
Let's start with the entry point to our application, the router.
Using the router DSL, we can use the get and post functions.
Both take the URL path, controller, and action as arguments.
On get requests to /videos/new, we'll use the VideoController module
in the new function.  For post requests to /videos, we'll use the
VideoController module in the create function.
By parsing the router, Phoenix dynamically creates helper functions we
can use in controllers and templates that return URL paths.
These functions are called path helpers, and they are dynamically
generated, derived from each controller in the router.
As we can see in this example, our controller is VideoController,
hence we can use the video_path function to return each one of these URL paths.
The first argument to the path helper functions is the connection,
which is available from the controller, as we'll see in just a moment.
The second argument to the function is the action we want to generate
the URL path for.  This can be either index, new, or create.
Back to VideoController, we define a function called new.
Requests to videos/new will be routed to this function.
All controller functions invoked by the router will always take the
connection as the first argument.  We'll call it conn.
There's a second argument, but since we don't need it for now,
we'll use an underscore and ignore it.
Next, we create a changeset.  A changeset is a struct representing
changes made to the underlying scheme.  In this example, video.
We create a changeset using the change function from the Ecto.Changeset module.
To use functions from this module inside VideoController,
we must import the module.  With the empty changeset in hand,
we call the render function, passing it the connection as the first
argument in a keyword list, including the changeset as the last
argument, which will be made available to the template.
From the new action in the VideoController, we render this template
right here, new.html.eex under the folder lib/fire_starter_web/templates/video.
In the template, we can use the form_for function to create the form.
This function takes three arguments.  The first one is the changeset
available via @changeset.  The second argument is the path we'll
submit the form to.  Better than hard coding a string value,
we call the path helper function, video_path, passing the connection
and the action we want to submit to, create.
This function returns the string /videos.  The third argument is an
anonymous function that takes one argument.
Inside this anonymous function is where we'll define the body of our form.
As you can see, we have an h3 for New Video.
Now let's learn how to create input fields.
One of the form helper functions available in Phoenix for creating
HTML inputs is called text_input.  As the name implies,
this function creates an HTML input of type text.
The first argument to this function and to all other helper functions
available in Phoenix is the argument we get from the anonymous function.
Phoenix parses the changeset given to form_for and passes the result
as the argument to the anonymous function, which is used by form
helper functions, like text_input, to generate the proper names for
the input fields.  In this example, we create an input for the title
property from our changeset.  The text_input function generates an
input of type text and with the name attribute set to video, brackets, title.
This is the exact format expected by VideoController once we submit the form.
The remaining two fields from the form are all of type text,
so we'll go ahead and add them now, one for Url and one for Duration.
Lastly, we use the submit function to create a button that submits the form.
This button will be set with the value Create.
Once the form is rendered, this is what it will look like.
Phoenix not only renders the form with the expected input fields and
their proper attributes, but it also gives us some added features.
Let's talk about them.  First one is protection against cross-site
request forgery attacks, also known as CSRF attacks.
This is when third party websites try and submit malicious forms to
our Phoenix app.  To prevent these attacks, Phoenix embeds a special
token in the form and uses that token to validate the form submission.
There's also another hidden input that forces browsers to use UTF-8 as
the charset, which is today's standard for modern applications.
And last, but not least, here's the name attribute for title,
known as the convention, which is used across all other inputs in the
form, and it'll help us read this data from our controller.
The first step is done.  Now when we visit /videos/new,
the request hits Phoenix, and we see the new video form properly generated.
That's it for this first section.  It's your turn to code some forms
in the challenges.