You're watching On Fire With Phoenix.  I'm Carlos Souza, and in this
section we'll learn how to read user submitted data and create new records.
Back in the previous section, we learned how to render the form.
Once the user fills in the form and hits the Submit button,
our Phoenix app will receive a post request to the /videos URL and
with the user submitted data.  This will route the request to the VideoController.create action.
That's where the magic happens.  We'll read the form data,
create the new record, and redirect back to the video listing page
where the user will be able to see the newly created record.
Now back to our VideoController, we define the create function.
This function takes two arguments.  First one is the connection,
which is always the first argument to control our actions,
and then the user data in the form of a map.
On the second argument, we use pattern matching to read the value from
the key we were interested in.  In this example, video.
The values assigned to video_params are all string, so we need to cast
them to the proper format according to the schema definition.
To do that, we use the cast function, available from Ecto.Changeset.
This function transforms user input data from string to their
corresponding types, and filters allow fields.
Cast takes three arguments.  First is a Video schema.
Next, the user submitted values assigned to the video_params variable.
Last is a list of the fields allowed to be populated on the schema.
In this example, title, url, and duration.
Any other field sent with a form submission will be completely ignored.
The return value from cast is assigned to the changeset variable.
With the changeset in hand, we can use Repo.insert to insert the new record.
The Repo.insert function takes a changeset as its single argument and
translates it to the appropriate insert SQL statement.
In this example, we insert new data into the videos table.
To determine whether or not the insert was successful, we can use the case statement.
We use case with a return value from Repo.insert.
Responses from calling this function are either a tuple with the ok
atom in the newly created record or a tuple with the error atom in a
new changeset, including validation errors that prevented the record
from being created.
For successful inserts, we pipe the connection to the put_flash
function, which we use to store an info-type message with a string,
Video created successfully, for display.  Then we pipe its returned
value to the redirect function, redirecting the request to the
video_path for index, which we know returns /videos.
When inserting a new record is not successful, then it's a similar
flow, but with a few tweaks.  Instead of an info-type flash, we use an
error-type flash in the message Error creating video.
And instead of redirecting the request, we render the new template,
passing the new changeset, including the errors, which prevented the
insert from being successful.
Here's all the code for the create action in the VideoController.
Now let's fill in the form and see this code in action.
On the form page, we fill in the Title with PHP 101,
Url with example.com/php-101, and Duration with 100.
When we submit the form, we can see the success message at the top and
the new video title, PHP 101, added to the bottom of the list.
Now let's look at an example of an unsuccessful submission.
Here we fill in the form with the Title PHP 101,
the Url example.com/php-101, and for the Duration, we use a string,
super quick, instead of a number.  When we submit the form,
indeed we see the error flash message at the top saying Error Creating Video.
However, it's unclear where the error is in the form, which field is
actually generating the error.
To facilitate spotting the error in form submissions,
Phoenix provides form error helpers, like the error_tag function.
This function generates an error tag for a specific field when an
error exists for that field or property.  We'll place a call to
error_tag below each one of the text_input fields, passing the form as
the first argument and the field name as the second argument.
Now when we try and submit the form again, we'll see the error message
at the top and a message below the Duration field saying is invalid,
and that helps us quickly identify the _____ field that's preventing
the record from being saved.  The reason for the error is that Phoenix
is not able to cast the string, super quick, to a valid integer value,
which is the data type for this field according to the video schema.
This is the essential that we need to know in order to create new videos.
We'll learn how to render the form with the proper fields,
how to handle form submission, create new records, and display errors
for invalid submissions.
This is the end of this level.  It's your turn to create new records
in the challenges.