Yeah, cruise down that strip and take in the neon lights baby,
as we get well equipped to take our apps to new heights, yeah!
We'll create records, take in the view — our route is surely scenic too.
We'll use Elixir as we travel through On Fire With Phoenix,
On Fire With Phoenix, On Fire With Phoenix, yeah!
You're watching On Fire With Phoenix.  I'm Carlos Souza, and in this
first level we'll learn the basics of Phoenix and dive right in on how
to work with a database.
Phoenix is a web development framework written in Elixir.
Like most other web frameworks, it uses the MVC pattern,
which facilitates separating concerns and structuring code files
inside of projects.  It improves developer's productivity by
leveraging conventions from Elixir and Erlang.
By running on top of the Erlang virtual machine,
Phoenix applications run fast, scale well, are fault tolerant,
and offer high availability.  Phoenix is a full stack framework,
meaning it comes with solutions to assist with backend code,
database access, and client-side programming with JavaScript.
Some knowledge of Elixir and SQL is required for this course.
If at any point you see syntax you are not familiar with,
then you should pause and check out our other courses on those topics.
In this course, we'll learn by doing.  Together we'll write features
for a Phoenix web app for watching videos called FireStarter.
Some of the things we'll learn include using the Ecto library to work
with the database, creating new HTTP routes, working with forms,
and validating user input.
Before we start coding, let's see what MVC in Phoenix looks like.
This is the big picture, and it's okay if this doesn't make sense yet.
Throughout the course, we'll touch on each and every one of these parts.
In this level, we'll start with the M of MVC, the model part,
looking at schema modules.  We'll do that by implementing the first
feature of our web app, listing records from an existing database.
The first thing we'll learn in Phoenix is how to read data from a database table.
For this course, we're going to assume there's a Postgres database
behind our app.  This is the default database used by Phoenix,
but others are supported as well.  In this section, we'll see how to
map Elixir code to a database table and then how to list all records
from this table.  Let's get to it.
Here's a simple database table called videos.
This table is where we'll fetch our data from.
It has four columns, id, title, url, and duration, and two records,
one for Elixir and one for JavaScript.  Now let's see how we can work
with this data from Phoenix.
In order to promote better code design, Phoenix adopts a particular folder structure.
Starting from the root folder named after our app, FireStarter,
most of the code we write will live in one of two folders inside lib.
The first folder is lib/name_of_our_app.  In this example, lib/fire_starter.
This folder is for the core business logic of our application.
Things that relate to core business logic include, for example,
calculating sales tax in a shopping cart or validations like enforcing
a max number of users in a chat room.  The second folder is lib/name_of_our_app_web.
This is for logic related to the web presentation of our app.
Examples of this type of logic include max number of records displayed
on a page and error messages displayed in form submissions.
In a Phoenix app, there are more folders than just these two for
things like configuration, library dependencies, tests, and whatnot,
but we won't have to worry about them for this course.
Now on to writing our very first Phoenix code.
Phoenix ships with a database library called Ecto, which uses the
concept of Schema module in order to communicate with database tables.
Schema modules are Elixir modules responsible for mapping data
sources, usually databases, to Elixir code.
Here's the Ecto schema that creates a mapping to the videos table.
This file lives under the lib/fire_starter folder, and it's named video.ex.
The top-level module must be named after our app name.
In this example, FireStarter.  The module itself can be named
anything, but it's a convention to use the singular version of the
database table, so we'll call it Video.
The first line after the module definition brings functions from the
Ecto.Schema module included in Phoenix into our FireStarter.Video
module so we can use them to define the mapping.
One of these functions is the schema function, which takes the name of
the database table as its argument and a block of code.
Inside the schema block, we use the field function, which takes the
name of a column of the database followed by the data type in Elixir
we want to use to store its data.  In this example, we're mapping the
title column and storing the data on a field of type string,
then mapping the url column to a field also of type string and a
duration column to a field of type integer.
Notice in our Schema module there's no explicit reference to the id
column in the database table.  The default behavior of Ecto expects a
column named id to exist on each table it maps to and automatically
uses that as the primary key.
One more thing that's commonly used in Ecto schemas is the timestamps function.
This function creates fields that help keep track of any record was
initially created and when he was last updated.
It does so by mapping Elixir code to the inserted_at and updated_at
columns in the database table.  Ecto automatically populates these
columns for us when a new record is created and every time it's updated.
Calling the timestamps function is a shorthand for these two calls to
field, one for the inserted_at column and one for the updated_at
column, both using the naive_datetime data type from Elixir.
With the mapping in place, now let's see how we can issue commands to
the database and list video records.  In Phoenix, all communication with
the database is done through the Repo module, a submodule of the
top-level FireStarter module.  Repo is a wrapper around the database.
It has access to the necessary credentials, and it's responsible for
establishing a connection with the database.
To list all records from the database, we use the all function from Repo.
This function takes a schema as argument, like the one we've just
created for Video, and returns all records from the table referenced
by the schema.  In this example, calling the all function will execute
a SQL statement similar to this one, SELECT * FROM "videos".
Now topping the FireStarter module every time you want to reference
Repo or Schema modules like Video can feel quite repetitive.
A technique commonly found in Phoenix apps which can address this
issue is using the alias directive.  In this example, we type alias
followed by FireStarter.Repo and then alias followed by FireStarter.Video.
Each one of these calls creates an alias named after the last part of
the module name.  Now, instead of having to reference the FireStarter
top-level module in all operations, we can simply use Repo and Video.
That's it for this section.  Now it's your turn to write Phoenix code
that lists records from the database in the challenges.