Yeah, cruise down that strip and take in the neon lights baby,
as we get well equipped to take our apps to new heights, yeah!
We'll create records, take in the view — our route is surely scenic too.
We'll use Elixir as we travel through On Fire With Phoenix,
On Fire With Phoenix, On Fire With Phoenix, yeah!
You're watching On Fire With Phoenix.  I'm Carlos Souza, and in this
section we'll learn how to send data back to the client and how to
render HTML pages.
We've learned how to use Ecto to read data from the database.
Now let's see how we can return data in a response so we can display
the list of videos on a page.
To do that, we'll need to write some code for the C of MVC, the controller part.
The controller part of MVC in Phoenix includes controller modules and the router.
We've seen how to code in the model part with schema modules.
Now let's see what we need to do in the router and controllers in
order to show data on a web page.
First thing we need is to create a route.  A route is composed of four
things, an HTTP method; URL path; a controller, or module,
that's associated with the route; and an action, or function,
from the module that should be called every time a client makes a
request for that URL path.  This is what a route will look like,
and the router file will add a new line inside the scope for forward slash.
This means that the route we add will be applied for every request
sent to the root path of our application.  We call the get function,
meaning we want to route requests using the get HTTP verb,
then add the /videos URL path.  We give it the module VideoController,
the controller module.  And finally, the action name as an atom,
which is the name of the function we expect to be called in our controller module.
Now that the request is being properly routed, let's see how we can
respond from the controller.  This is what our controller looks like.
It's a submodule of the FireStarterWeb module.
The simiplest way to respond with plain text from a controller is
using the text function.  Let's see what that looks like.
First, we define an index function, which takes two arguments.
First one in the connection, which we'll need to use to form the response.
The second argument to controller functions is composed of arguments
sent on the request set by the router.  In this particular case,
we don't need any of those arguments, so we'll use the underscore
character to ignore them.
From inside the index function, we call text.
Text is made available to the index function via the call to use,
commonly placed at the top of the controller module.
The call to use FireStarterWeb, :controller brings to VideoController
a couple of functions useful for rendering the response, including text.
The first argument to text is the connection.
From the connection, Phoenix can access request headers and other info
needed to craft the proper response to the client.
The second argument to text is the actual text we want to respond with.
In this example, Hello from VideoController.
When we run this code and make a request to /videos, we can see
Phoenix properly responds with the text Hello from VideoController.
That's a good first step, but what we want to display is a list of
videos in HTML.  Let's see how we can do that.
We're back to VideoController.  Let's see what we need to add to
change the response from plain text to HTML.
To render HTML with video data from the database, we can use the render function.
This function is made available to us from that same call to use and
expects three arguments, the connection, a template name, and the keyword list.
The template name will be index.html.  The keyword list will include
one key, videos, and we'll assign it to a variable also named videos.
This variable will be populated with a return value from calling
Repo.all, which, as we've learned, returns all records from the videos table.
The data set to the keyword list will be made available to the
template, and we'll use it to create the HTML.
The template is part of the V in MVC.
In Phoenix, controllers use schemas to fetch and set up data from the
database and then send this data to templates.
Now let's see how to read data from inside templates and generate HTML.
Here's an example of a simple template.  Templates receive data from
controllers and render HTML response.  Inside templates, we can write
regular HTML, like we see here, with an h2 header All Videos in the ul tags.
In order to generate li tags with the video titles, we'll write an Elixir expression.
This expression will read the data set by VideoController from @videos
and use a list comprehension to create a list of li tags.
List comprehensions are used to loop through enumerables and return collections.
Here's how this code works.  The for keyword tells the arrow to assign
each one of the elements from @videos to the video variable one at a time.
From inside the do end block, we have access to this variable,
which stores a video struct.  We read the title property from video.
Notice the equal sign next to the percent symbol on the left.
This tells Elixir that we want to print this expression,
which then becomes the content of the li tag.
Although they might look like for loops, they're not actually for loops.
Here's another simpler example of using a list comprehension.
In this code, we're looping through the list on the right of the
arrow, the list of strings, a, b, and c.  On each iteration,
one item from the list is assigned to the variable letter.
Then from inside the block, we can access this variable and return an
item to be added to a new empty list.  The list comprehension will
loop through each item and will keep adding the value returned from
the block to this new list until the end of the original list of
strings is reached.  Once that happens, we return the new list and
assign it to the variable output.  When we print the output to the
console, we can see Letter: a, Letter: b, and Letter: c.
With everything in place, we can now run our code again.
When a client makes a request to the /videos path of our application,
we'll read all videos from the database and respond with a formatted HTML page.
We've reached the end of this first section.
It's your turn to try rendering some HTML in the code challenges.