Yeah, cruise down that strip and take in the neon lights baby,
as we get well equipped to take our apps to new heights, yeah!
We'll create records, take in the view — our route is surely scenic too.
We'll use Elixir as we travel through On Fire With Phoenix,
On Fire With Phoenix, On Fire With Phoenix, yeah!
You're watching On Fire With Phoenix.  I'm Carlos Souza, and in this
section we'll learn how to use Phoenix to create a new database table.
We want to build a video show page.  On this page, we'll have the
title for video at the top followed by a list of comments left by
people who watched the video.  In order to do that, we need a place to
store and retrieve these comments, a new database table with columns
for id, body, author, and, most importantly, video_id, which will hold
a reference to the parent video each comment belongs to.
In this level, we'll learn how to make changes to the database and how
to create associations between schema modules.
First, we'll learn about migrations, what they are and how to use them
to create new tables.  Then we'll learn how to define foreign key
fields and relationships.  And then we'll learn how to load associated
records from the database in our Phoenix app.
In Phoenix, we use migration files in order to make changes to the
database, including creating a table.  In the big picture of our
Phoenix project structure, this is where migrations live.
Migrations are not involved in the request/response cycle,
so they're not really part of the MVC.  But as we'll see, they are an
essential part of Phoenix, and it can make our lives a whole lot easier.
Migrations allows us to define changes to the database structure using Elixir.
To run a migration, we start by writing code in Elixir that expresses
the changes we want to make to the database.
Then we run a mix task called ecto.migrate.
This task will read Elixir code, translate it to SQL, and execute that
on the target database.  Every change to the database is expressed in
a migration file, and it's not uncommon to find apps with dozens of them.
Let's see what this code looks like.
Migration modules in our application are submodules of the
FireStarter.Repo.Migrations module.  They live under the
priv/repo/migrations folder.  Each migration file name starts with the
date the file was created.  This is useful for sorting migrations and
figuring out the correct order in which to run them.
The change function is where we write code that will be translated to SQL statements.
The function must be named this way; otherwise, Phoenix and Ecto will
not know which code to execute.
In order to create a new table, we use two functions, create and table.
These two functions are part of the Ecto.Migration module.
First, we call create.  Then we call table with the name of the table
as an atom.  In this example, comments.  New tables created this way
default to a primary key of name id and type serial, a widely used
convention in database design.
Now that we have the table, let's create the columns.
To do that, we use the add function, also part of the Ecto.Migration module.
The add function requires the column name, in this example body and
author, and the data type for each column, both of which in this
example is text.  For the body column, we're also passing optional
fields, stating this column cannot be null.
Lastly, we use the timestamps function, similar to the one used on schema modules.
This function is a shorthand for creating inserted_at and updated_at
columns of type naive_datetime for keeping track of when records were
created and last updated.
Remember, each comment record will need to reference its parent video.
We add a third column called video_id and then use the references
function to define a foreign key to the videos table.
The second argument to references indicates that we want all comments
to be deleted when the parent video is also deleted.
This helps prevent ghost records, which are comments without apparent video.
Lastly, it's a good practice to create an index for a foreign key column.
This can make our database queries run faster.
To do that, we use the same create function.
Now, instead of following it with a call to the table function,
we call the index function, giving it the table name comments and a
list of columns we want to create the index for.
In this example, just the video_id column.
That's all we need to create the new table.
To run the migration, we run the mix task ecto.migrate, and we should
see an output that looks similar to this.  The last line should be a
success message saying Migrated followed by how long it took to run.
We only had one migration, so we ran in less than a second.
That's it for this section.  It's your turn to practice writing some
migrations in the challenges.