Welcome back.  You're watching On Fire With Phoenix, and in this
section we'll learn other ways to read data from the database.
In the previous section, we learned how to fetch all videos from the database.
In this section, we'll learn how to fetch a single video by its ID and
how to filter videos based on a condition.
In order to fetch a video by ID, we use the get function.
This function takes two arguments, a previously defined schema and an
integer, and returns a single record.  In this example, we call the
get function, passing it a Video and the number 2.
When we run this code, Ecto will run a SQL statement similar to this
one, SELECT * FROM "videos" WHERE id = 2.  It finds the record with ID 2,
maps it to Elixir, and what we'll receive back as a return value is a
struct that looks like this.  This is the first time that we mention
this data type, a struct.  Let's talk about it for a second before we move on.
The schema modules we learned about in the previous section are actually structs.
A struct is a data type in Elixir that is an extension built on top of
maps and provides a couple of nice features, most importantly compile-time checks.
Let's see a quick example comparing maps and structs.
First, here's a map.  In this example, we wanted to assign a value to
a key named title, but unfortunately we misspelled title.
Elixir is actually okay with that.  In a map, we can pretty much
create any keys we want.  When working with maps, errors like this
won't arise until we run the code and try and read from the key.
If we try and read a value from the title key, then we'll see a runtime error.
Using structs, on the other hand, Elixir is able to check whether a
key we're assigning to actually exists.  In this example, as soon as
we try and assign a value to a property that wasn't previously
defined, Elixir raises a compile-time error.
Then you might ask how does it know whether or not a property was previously defined?
Well, it does so by looking at the property or keys or fields that we
define in our Schema module using the field function.
Now let's look at what happens when an ID we're looking for doesn't
exist in the database.  When that happens using the get function,
what we get back is nil.  No error is raised; just nil is returned.
Sometimes we might want to raise an error, in which case we can use
the get function with an exclamation mark.
When we use this function and look for an ID that does not exist in
the database, then Ecto will raise an error.
We know how to fetch all videos and just learned how to fetch a video
by its ID.  Now let's learn how to filter videos based on a condition.
For example, say we want to list all records from the videos table
that have a duration that's less than 800 seconds.
If we were writing a SQL query for that, it would look something like
this:  SELECT * FROM "videos" WHERE duration is less than 800.
Let's see how we can do that by using Phoenix and Ecto.
Let's go back to the Schema module.  First thing we'll do is define a
new function called short_duration.  Then we'll import the Ecto.Query module.
This module provides a domain-specific language, or DSL, for querying data.
Importing this DSL means we'll have access to functions that create
queries straight from our Schema module.  One of these functions is called from.
The from function takes two arguments.  First one is called an in
expression, and the second one is a keyword list.
The in expression will be used to figure out which table we're
querying and will namespace the properties used in the keyword list argument.
In order to avoid duplicating the name of the module, we use the
__MODULE__ macro, which returns the name of the enclosing module.
Then we'll filter our records by passing the where key and saying we
only want videos whose duration property is less than 800.
And this is the Elixir code that translates to the WHERE SQL query we started with.
To run this query, we call Video.short_duration, which, as we've seen,
builds and returns a query, and then we pipe the result to the
Repo.all function, which executes the query.
We run this code, and the result we see is a list of structs.
Before we wrap up this section, let's do a quick recap on the
differences between alias, use, and import.
Alias was the first one we learned, and it helps us refer to modules
using shorter names.  We give it the full module,
like FireStarter.Repo or FireStarter.Video, and then we can refer to
these modules as Repo and Video.  Import allows easy access to
functions from other modules without using the fully-qualified name,
like we do here inside the short_duration function calling the from
function, part of the Ecto.Query module.  Finally, use is similar to
import, but it gives module authors more control over what's imported,
and it allows for injecting code, also known as metaprogramming,
a more advanced feature we won't cover in this course.
We've reached the end of this level.  It's time for you to get your
hands dirty and write some query code in the challenges.