Welcome back.  You're watching On Fire With Phoenix.
My name is Carlos Souza, and in this section we'll learn how to read
comments for a particular video and display them on a page.
Our app now has a comments table.  Let's suppose we have some data on
it, like these two rows, one comment from Brooke and one from Sam,
both associated to the video with ID 42.  Let's learn how to write
Phoenix code to read comments from a specific video.
With the table in place, the first thing we need to do is go back to
our Schema modules and define how a video is associated with comments.
We do this in the model layer of MVC.
In the video schema module, we call another function inside our schema definition, has_many.
This function indicates a one to many association with another schema.
It takes two arguments.  First one is the name of the property that
will be created on this module.  In this example, comments.
Next is the module that will be associated with the new property, FireStarter.Comment.
With that, we have an association between a video and its comments.
We say A video has many comments!
In order for this to work, we must also specify the reverse of this
association, getting to a parent video from its child comment.
In the Comment module, we use the belongs_to function.
Just like has_many, belongs_to takes the name of the property and the associated module.
We say A comment belongs to a video!
Before we run this code, here's what the data looks like.
In our comments table, there are two comments, very helpful and great
video, both with video_id set to 42.  This is the ID in primary key
for the Elixir video in the videos table.
To read video comments, we start by getting the video.
We use Repo.get, passing it the Video module and the ID 42.
We get the video back and store it in a variable video.
But if we try reading the comments property right away, we'll see an
error like this, a NotLoaded error saying association :comments is not loaded.
This error happens because Repo.get does not automatically load associations.
In order to load comments for a video, we must preload them.
We pipe the result of calling Repo.get to Repo.preload, which takes an
existing record as its first argument, in this example, Video,
and the name of an association as its second argument, comments.
Once we do that, we store the final results to the video variable.
Now we can call video.comments and see a list of comment records.
With the plumbing code in place, let's finish building the video show page.
To do this, we need three things.  First, we need a new route for
showing a single video record.  It's going to be /videos/ the ID of
the video we want to display.  Then we need to write code in the
controller to fetch this video, preload its comments, and finally,
render the page with the video title and its comments.
Let's go ahead and tackle these pending items.
Back to the router, we add a new route for the show action on VideoController.
The URL for this route will match requests for /videos/ a value
representing the ID for a video, and it will call the show function on the VideoController.
Now in our VideoController we create a show function that takes two
arguments, first the connection, as always, and then a map.
On the map, we use pattern matching to read the value from the id key,
which is set by the router from the value found in the URL.
Using pattern matching to read values passed by the router is a widely
used practice in Phoenix.  It's one of my personal favorite features
from Elixir, and it makes code shorter and much easier to read.
Inside the show function, we get the video, preload its comments,
and assign it to the variable video.  Finally, we render the show
template, passing it the video.
Now on the template we access the video with @video.
First, we read the title inside an h2 tag and then use a list
comprehension to loop through the comments, printing each comment
inside of an li tag.
That's it for the template, and our code is now complete.
When we visit /videos/42, we see a page with the video title and a
list of its associated comments.
That's it for this level.  It's your turn to write some association
code in Phoenix in the challenges.