Yeah, cruise down that strip and take in the neon lights baby,
as we get well equipped to take our apps to new heights, yeah!
We'll create records, take in the view — our route is surely scenic too.
We'll use Elixir as we travel through On Fire With Phoenix,
On Fire With Phoenix, On Fire With Phoenix, yeah!
You're watching On Fire With Phoenix.  My name is Carlos Souza.
In this level, we won't be learning any new syntax or adding any new
features to our app.  Instead, we'll learn a very important design
practice that will help us keep our code organized and will give us a
solid foundation to grow our application from.
We'll learn about contexts.
When parts of the application know too much about other parts,
it's called tight coupling.  Tight coupling indicates poor application
design and leads to bad code.  There are two signs of tight coupling
in Phoenix that we, as developers, should be aware of when starting our apps.
First is when we find ourselves writing too much code in controllers.
This results in controllers knowing too much about other parts of the
app and results in a popular MVC anti-pattern known as fat controllers.
Second is when we have references to the Repo module and functions
from schema modules from controller actions, usually when there's
communication with the database.  There are more examples of how one
might write code that leads to tight coupling, but these two tend to
be the most common, so we'll focus on these for now and on how to fix them.
One solution to these two problems endorsed by the Phoenix core team
is called context.  Context modules allows us to decouple and isolate
our code into manageable and independent parts.
We do this by having a clear division of responsibilities.
Instead of controllers directly reaching out to schemas,
like video and comment, in the Repo module, we should code our Phoenix
apps in a way that controllers only talk to contexts.
Controllers are responsible for reading user parameters from routes
and passing them over to context modules.  Context modules read the
data passed by the controller and execute the core business logic of our application.
Part of the business logic might involve communicating with the
database, and that's when the context module will reach out to Schema and Repo.
Let's refactor our existing code to use a new context we'll create called Screencasts.
The Screencasts context, or module, will be the entry point for all
video-related operations, listing and creating.
Here's what our project structure will look like now.
Inside the fire_starter folder, we'll have a new folder called screencasts.
Inside this folder, we'll have the screencasts.ex file representing
the context, which is simply an Elixir module.
Then we'll move the Video and Comment modules inside the screencasts folder.
They are now part of the new folder in the Screencasts namespace,
as we'll see in just a moment.
Let's go back to VideoController and look at the code that we have so far.
This is the code, and it works, but we can spot some of the tight
coupling issues we just talked about.  In order to list and get
videos, the controller needs to know about the Repo module and Video schema.
If for any reason we make changes to how videos are read from the
database, these changes will directly affect this code.
We don't want that.  To fix this issue, we'll move these two lines out
of the controller and into the newly created Screencasts context.
As you can see, the Screencasts context is a module part of the FireStarter namespace.
Inside this module, we'll create two functions, list_videos and get_video.
List_videos takes no argument and reads all videos from the database.
Get_video takes an id as an argument, reads a specific video by its
id, preloads its comments, and returns the results.
Reading videos from database is now part of the Screencasts context,
and it's decoupled and isolated from the controller.
In order for this code to work, we must also move over the necessary
aliases, which helps us use shorter references to Repo and Video.
Now back to VideoController, we'll create an alias for FireStarter.Screencasts.
Then we can replace the old code with a call to Screencasts.list_videos
on the index action and Screencasts.get_video on the show action
giving it the ID read from pattern matching in the show function.
As you can see, the code for reading videos is now shorter and
decoupled from Repo and Schema.
That's is for this first section.  It's your turn to write context
code for reading from the database in the challenges.