You're watching On Fire With Phoenix.  In this section,
we'll learn how to use view modules to format data for templates.
The current state of our application lists video titles on a web page.
What we want to do now is add to the duration for each video next to its title.
Let's see how we can do that.
We'll start by going back to the video/index template.
Next to the expression that prints the video title, we add the string
duration followed by another expression that prints the video's duration property.
If we run this code, we'll see the duration for each video; however,
we'll see the integer value exactly as it's stored in the database.
We need to make this easier to read, like showing it in minutes and seconds.
To do that, we'll write code in view modules.
View modules are also a part of V in MVC.  They provide helper
functions for templates.  The video view module is the perfect place
to write a helper function that converts seconds into minutes and seconds.
To do that, we declare a function called duration_in_mins that takes a
single argument, an integer representing the total number of seconds
for a video.  Inside this function, we call two functions, div and rem.
These functions are part of Elixir's kernel module,
automatically imported by Elixir.  Div performs a division and rounds
down to the closest integer.  We'll divide the number of seconds by 60
to get the minutes.  Rem returns the remainder of a division by its second argument.
In this example, 60, which returns the seconds portion of the duration.
With these two values assigned to the minutes and seconds variable,
we build a formatted string with a colon in the middle and return this
string from the function.
Now back to our video/index template, we can call our newly-defined
function, duration_in_mins, giving it the duration in seconds,
and then add the mins string to indicate the format of the duration.
When we run our code again and made a request to the video's path,
we can now see the list of videos, each with their corresponding
duration properly formatted.
This is the end of this level.  Now it's your turn to write some view
code in the challenges.