Our Candy Coded store sells sweet treats galore.
How do we get it on the map?
Let's build a sugar-coated Android app!
With tasty layouts and views,
full of delicious candy hues,
our users will be overjoyed by our super sweet apps powered with Android.
Hi, I'm Sarah Holderness, and welcome to Super Sweet Android Time.
This course is a continuation of the concepts taught in the Try Android course.
In that course we created a candy store app called Candy Coded,
and we learned how to create an activity layout, add images and an
ImageView, add data to a ListView with an adapter,
create an event listener, and display a toast.
Let's jump over to Android Studio to take a brief look at that
project as a refresher.
Our app starts by launching the main activity, which happens by
calling this onCreate method in the MainActivity class.
Then one of the first things it does is set the view to the
activity_main layout, which is where we designed what our user
interface was going to look like.  Then back in our Java code,
we created an ArrayList of candy names and an ArrayAdapter to
populate our ListView in our app.  We also displayed some pop-up
messages, or toasts, when the app started and when a ListItem was clicked.
The app we're going to build in this course is going to add more
features to our Candy Coded app, like launching other activities
with intents, network requests, using the constraint layout system,
and storing data in a database.  If you want to follow along on your
own computer you can download the finished project from the Try
Android course at the link listed here, or you can follow along with
our interactive challenges at the end of each section.
In level 1 we're going to start off creating a new activity and
launching it with an intent.  Right now in our app we show a list of candies.
We want to be able to click on a candy and see details about it.
To do that we're going to create a separate detail activity to show
an image, description, and price, and this activity will start when
an item is clicked.  To get started, let's jump over to Android
Studio to see how to create a new activity.
To create a new activity, we can right-click the java folder in the
project window and select New, Activity, Empty Activity.
We'll name our activity DetailActivity, and we want to generate a
layout file with the name activity_detail, and we can leave our
package name and click Finish.  This will generate our
DetailActivity.java file that looks very similar to the starting
code in MainActivity.java with just an onCreate method.
Then in the res/layout folder, we can see the activity_detail.xml
file that was created.  This has a constraint layout with nothing in it.
We'll go ahead and add a TextView that says Detail Activity for now
so that we'll know when we launch this Detail Activity screen in our app.
Let's also name this TextView text_view_name so we can find it and
use it to display the candy name later.
Now we want this screen to show whenever we click on an item in our ListView.
So if we go to our onItemClickListener method in MainActivity.java,
we're going to remove this code to display a toast and instead add
our code to display the detail activity.
Let's jump back over to the slides to see what code we'll put here
to launch our detail activity.
We need an intent to be able to launch our new detail activity.
An intent requests an action from another app component,
and there are two types of intents.  Explicit intents launch a
specific app component, like the detail activity in this case.
It's like the intent is saying, hey detail activity, it's time for you to start.
The other type of intents are implicit.  They just declare an action
they need, like sharing a website, and then the user can pick
which app to use.  I'm sure you've seen this happen when you try
to share something on your phone.
We'll use an explicit intent to start the detail activity.
When a user selects an item from our ListView, our item click listener
will create an intent to launch the detail activity.
Since we want the intent to start the activity after a click,
we'll add that code to the click listener at the bottom of the
onCreate method in MainActivity.java.  Previously we were showing a
toast here, but we've deleted that code and will only start our detail activity.
To create an intent, we use the new keyword with the Intent constructor
and pass it the context of where we are creating this intent,
which is inside this MainActivity class, and the component we want to
create, which is the DetailActivity class.
Then, the MainActivity can start another activity by calling the
startActivity method, which takes our intent as a parameter.
We'll put the code we just created inside our onItemClick callback method.
Let's jump over to Android Studio to see what that looks like.
In MainActivity.java, we have the code we just added at the bottom
of our onCreate method inside our ListView's OnItemClickListener event.
Let's watch this in action.  We click on a list item and we're
shown the new detail activity screen that shows the text Detail Activity.
Great!  Our intent is working.
That's it for this section.  Now it's time for you to practice
creating activities and intents in the challenges.
Good luck.