Welcome back.  In this section we're going to use the Picasso image
library to load our images into our ImageView.
Instead of writing this somewhat lengthy code to download images
into our app and cache them, Picasso is an Android library we can
use to do this for us.
We need caching because getting files from a distant web server
takes much longer than getting locally cached images from memory.
How caching works is, if the image exists in our local cache memory
from a recent request, we can load it from there.
Otherwise, we'll download the image from the web server,
but also save it in our local cache for next time.
Just like we did before with our async and GSON libraries,
to use Picasso we need to add it as a dependency to the bottom of
our app's build.gradle file.
Now that Picasso has been included in our project, we can use it in our code.
We use Picasso.with to set the context of where the image will be
used, which is this activity, then the load method sets the URL where
Picasso will download the image from, and then the into method sets
the ImageView where we're going to display the image.
Remember, by using Picasso, Android Studio should automatically add
the following import line to the top of your file, but if it doesn't,
you can add it yourself.  Now let's get Picasso into our detail activity.
Just like before, we first need to get the image URL passed in with
the intent and also find our ImageView by its ID.
Then we can use Picasso to load our image into our ImageView.
And that's it.  Now we can see our image loading from our image URL we passed in.
That's it for level 3.  Now it's time for you to give Picasso a try in the challenges.