Our Candy Coded store sells sweet treats galore.
How do we get it on the map?
Let's build a sugar-coated Android app!
With tasty layouts and views,
full of delicious candy hues,
our users will be overjoyed by our super sweet apps powered with Android.
Welcome back.  In level 3 we're going to finish creating our detail
activity by using the ConstraintLayout system and an image loading
library called Picasso.
Right now the detail activity is only showing the candy name,
but we want to add TextViews for the price and description and an
ImageView for the image.  We can use the ConstraintLayout system
to arrange all of these views relative to each other.
Let's jump over to Android Studio to see how to do that.
To create our detail activity's layout, we need to first open our
ActivityDetail.xml layout file.  We'll dock our project window to give
us some more room and zoom in just so we can see this preview a little better.
If we click on the Text tab to look at the XML code, you can see we
have only one TextView right now, and it actually has a warning that
it's missing constraints.  That's because we're using a constraint
layout, so it's expecting constraints.  Let's go into the design view
to set up our layout using constraints.  For our layout we want an
ImageView at the top followed by three TextViews arranged below.
Let's start fresh by deleting our existing TextView and then dragging
an ImageView over from our palette.  We can search for an ImageView
in the palette, and then drag it over.  And for the image source we'll
select this placeholder image for now.  You can create constraints
manually by dragging these circle anchors to where you want to
constrain the element to.  We want this image to take up the entire
width of the screen and be at the very top.
To do this, we'll first constrain the image to the top of the parent
view by dragging the circle until the arrow connects to the top of the screen.
And then we'll constrain the left and right anchors to the parent as well.
We can set the inner dimensions of this ImageView by clicking these
lines here, which change between Wrap Content, Fixed width or Match Constraints.
Since we want the width to match the constraints of the parent and
take up the entire width, we'll set that to Match Constraints.
You can see this set the layout_width to 0dp, which is equivalent to Match Constraint.
We'll also set the left and right margins to 0 with the drop-down
since we want it to touch the edge of the screen.
For the layout_height we can leave it as wrap_content so that the
image will fill as much of the ImageView height as it needs.
And we'll set the top margin to 0 so that it touches the top of the screen.
But we can see that it's not quite touching the top.
That's because the image isn't taking up the entire bounding box.
We can fix this by selecting adjustViewBounds to be true.
Now our image looks how we want it.  If we look at the generated
XML we can see there were several constraints created,
constraintTop, constraintLeft, and constraintRight were set to parent,
and marginLeft, marginRight, and marginTop were set to 0dp.
While we're here, let's set the id equal to image_view_candy.
The naming convention is the type of view, so ImageView,
and a description of what it does, which is display the candy.
Now let's go back to the design view to add the three TextViews we need.
The first one will come under the image on the left side and will
display the name of the candy.  We'll constrain it to the bottom
of the image and the left side of the parent view with margins of
16 to the left and below, and we want wrapped content so it can
expand to fit the text.  We'll also make the candy name's font size
slightly bigger at 18 and bold.  The next TextView is for the candy
price, which comes under the image on the right.
We'll constrain it to the bottom of the image, as well as the right
side of the parent view with a margin of 16.
We'll also make the width and height wrap_content, and the font size
will be bigger at 18.  The last TextView is for the description,
which comes below both of these TextViews and takes up the entire
width of the parent.  We'll constrain this under the name TextView,
and the left and right constraints are anchored to the parent view.
We want the layout_width, or the left and right inner dimensions,
set to Match Constraints since we want it to expand to the size of
the parent it's constrained to, and we'll add a margin of 16dp here.
The layout_height we want set to wrap_content so that the height can
expand with the content, and from the top we want a margin of 16.
Now that we have all of that set up, let's also add the TextView's IDs.
The first TextView is for the name, so we'll name it text_view_name.
The second TextView is for the price, so we'll name it text_view_price.
The last TextView is for the description, and we'll name it
text_view_desc, short for description.  And we can see that it's
constrained to the right and left of the parent, but the bottom
constraint has a red line.  That's because we renamed the TextViews
and it doesn't know what this is now.  We can fill in text_view_name
because that's what the description comes below.
Now let's run our app and see what it looks like in action.
If we select a candy we can see our detail view has the layout we just
created.
It's a great start and now we want to fill in the actual candy image,
price, and description.
Now that we have our new detail activity's layout in place,
let's edit the Java code to fill in the price and description
TextViews with the actual data.
In the DetailActivity class, after we set the candy's name,
we can set the text for the other TextView objects.
There's three steps that make this happen that we already did for the candy name.
First, we get the values sent in with the intent.
Second, we find the TextView we want to update.
And third, we set the TextView's text.  Let's do the same thing for
the description TextView.  We already got the description value sent
in with the intent in level 2, now we need to find the TextView by
using the ID TextView desc we just created, and then we can set that
TextView's text with the setText method to the description value we passed in.
And finally, we can do the same thing for the price TextView.
Now we have our price and description TextViews with live data,
and it's time for you to practice adding data to your activity
layout in the challenges.