Our Candy Coded store sells sweet treats galore.
How do we get it on the map?
Let's build a sugar-coated Android app!
With tasty layouts and views,
full of delicious candy hues,
our users will be overjoyed by our super sweet apps powered with Android.
Welcome back to level 5 where we'll put the data in our database into our app.
Now that we have our candies in our database, the next step is to use
them in our app by querying our candy table.
As a review, we can use the select command to see what's in our table.
Select * gets all of the columns and will return all of the candy rows,
which is what we want.  We can query a SQLiteDatabase object by
passing a raw SQL query as a string to the rawQuery method.
The result is a cursor object that will contain all of the candy
rows and will let us navigate the results.
Cursor store query result records in rows and have methods to
access and iterate through them.  In this example, our cursor starts
at position -1.  To get the first row, we can call cursor.moveToNext.
Then to get the value in the name column, we first need the index
of that column, so we use the getColumnIndexOrThrow method,
which will throw an exception if, for some reason, that column doesn't exist.
Then we can finally get the name of the candy by calling
cursor.getString and passing the index of the column.
The resulting candy name is now Much Minty.
Our goal is to get our candy names into our ListView, so how can we do that?
Instead of using an ArrayAdapter to populate our ListView with
strings in an array, we can use a CursorAdapter to directly pull
values from our database.
To use a CursorAdapter, we need to create a CursorAdapter subclass,
which we will name CandyCursorAdapter.
Since CandyCursorAdapter extends CursorAdapter, it has to have a
constructor and override the newView and bindView methods.
The constructor will call the super method, and that needs the context,
the cursor, and false for re-query.  The newView method inflates the
view and returns it so that it can be displayed.
We need to tell it which layout to use.  We'll use the
list_item_candy layout we created in the Try Android course,
which is a layout describing what each item in the ListView should look like.
In the bindView method, we set the elements of our view.
We need to get the TextView from our layout to fill, then we get the
column in our database to fill it with, and then we use the setText
method to connect the two.
Now we can use our CursorAdapter to get data directly from our
database into our ListView.  To use our new CandyCursorAdapter,
we need to refactor the code in MainActivity.java a bit.
We can remove the code that creates the ArrayList and the ArrayAdapter
since we'll be using our database and CandyCursorAdapter instead.
Then to use our database data, we'll first query for all of the candies.
Then we can create a CandyCursorAdapter from the results in the cursor.
We can also remove the code to update the ArrayAdapter after our
request since we're not using that anymore.
Instead, we'll update our CursorAdapter here with the latest database entries.
In the onItemClickListener method, we can remove the code that passes
all of the properties individually to the detail activity.
Instead, we'll pass the position of the item selected so that we can
use the index to look up that row in the database in the
DetailActivity.java file.
Before we jump into the detail activity, it's time for you to practice
using the CursorAdapter in the challenges.
Good luck.