Welcome back.  In this section we're going to pass data to an
activity through an intent.
We have the detail activity starting, but we need to pass data to it,
like the candy name, so we know what candy to show.
We can pass data in an intent with the putExtra method.
The putExtra method takes a key value pair, so we'll use the key
candy_name paired with a string containing the candy name.
But how do we know which candy item was selected from the list?
Remember that we created an ArrayList named candyList to store our
candy names, then the ItemClickListener callback method has a
parameter i that represents the position of the item selected in that list.
So we can get the selected candy item with candyList.get i.
That was how to send data through an intent from the main activity.
Now we can get the intent in the detail activity with the getIntent
method, and then get the data stored with the intent with the
getStringExtra method.  So if the user selected Berry Bouncer in
this list, the candy_name string would be Berry Bouncer.
In case that intent doesn't have that key for some reason,
it's good practice to check that it has that extra value first so
our program doesn't crash.  Finally, we have that candy name in the
detail activity, so we can set the TextView's text to that candy to display it.
First we'll find the TextView by its ID, then we can set its text
with the setText method.  Let's jump over to Android Studio to demo
the detail activity displaying the candy name.
In MainActivity.java we create our detail intent at the bottom of
the onCreate method in our event listener.
This is where we added the extra candy name data to our intent.
Then in DetailActivity.java we can get this extra data from the
intent by looking up its candy_name data, and then we set the text for the TextView.
If we run our app, we can see that the detail activity's text
changes to the name of the candy when we click on different candy items.
That's it for level 1.  Now it's time for you to practice passing data
through an intent in the challenges.  Good luck.