Welcome back.  In this section we're actually going to store candy
data in our database.
We want to save candies to the database after we get the candy array
from the API.  Remember the code we wrote for our network request?
The onSuccess callback method is where we'll add candies to our database.
We'll create a method, addCandiesToDatabase, to save each candy to
the database and call that at the bottom of the onSuccess method.
Before we create that method, we'll also add a candyDbHelper
variable to the top of the MainActivity class so that we can access
it throughout the main activity.  Now let's define that
addCandiesToDatabase method at the bottom of the MainActivity class.
The return type will be void since we don't need to return anything,
we're just adding to the database, and we need to pass in our array
of candy so that we can add each one to the database.
To access our database, we can use the getWritableDatabase method
from our candyDbHelper, and we'll store a reference to that database
in a SQLiteDatabase variable called db.
Since we'll need to access each candy individually to add it to the
database, we'll create a loop that accesses each candy one at a time
from the candies array.  The ContentValues class will help us insert
values into the database by doing some data validation and ensuring
data gets inserted in the correct format.
We then put each column name and value into the ContentValues object
with the put method, and we'll do this same thing for the rest of our candy's properties.
Finally, we can use the insert method to insert the new candy row
into our database.
Now that we have our candies in our database, the next step is to use
them in our app.  But first, it's time for you to practice adding
data to your database in the challenges.