Welcome back.  In this section we'll be getting our data from the
database into the detail activity.
Instead of passing each of these values, the candy name, price, image,
and description, individually to the detail activity, we're passing the
row that was selected in the ListView to use in a database query.
Before we were passing in each value to display, but now we need to
query the database instead, so we can remove this code.
First we'll make sure our intent has that extra position value we passed in.
We can then get the position value, which is the row that was selected,
in the ListView.  We can get the candy row we want by first querying
all candies using the rawQuery method with SELECT * FROM candy.
Then we can move our cursor to the selected position with the moveToPosition method.
We want the value in the name column so that we can display the candy's name.
We can use the getColumnIndexOrThrow method to get the index of our Name column.
The orThrow means it will throw an error if it's not there.
As a reminder, Android Studio should automatically import the
CandyEntry class when we try to use it, but if it doesn't,
you can manually import it yourself.  Then we can get the candy's
name with the getString method and pass the columnIndex.
We want to do the same thing for the price, image, and description values.
We can also combine getting the column index and getting the string
into one statement, like you see here.  Now that we have the values,
we need to find each view and set its value, but since we're just
refactoring code that was already in the detail activity,
we've already written the code to find the three TextViews and single
ImageView and set their values.  Since our variable names for the
candy properties haven't changed, all of this code should still work like before.
Now if we run our app, we can see our detail activity working with the
data we queried from our database.
That's it for Super Sweet Android Time.  Now it's time for you to
practice working with your database data in your detail activity.
And make sure to stick around for the wrap-up video.
Candy to database to save.
Auto manually importing.
Perfect.
Okay.
That's a wrap.
Cool.