Our Candy Coded store sells sweet treats galore.
How do we get it on the map?
Let's build a sugar-coated Android app!
With tasty layouts and views,
full of delicious candy hues,
our users will be overjoyed by our super sweet apps powered with Android.
Welcome back.  In this level we'll be storing our candy data in a database.
But first, why do we want to store our candy data?
Can't we always just do a network request?
Sometimes your users will want data offline, like if they're on an
airplane or they might have a slow connection and not want to wait
for the most up-to-date results.  For times like these,
you'll want to store the candy from the most recent network requests locally.
There are two common ways to store data in Android apps,
a SharedPreferences object or a SQL database.
SharedPreferences store small amounts of data in key value pairs.
For instance, storing your location in a weather app.
A SQL database stores structured data, like our candy data,
where each column is a property, like Name, Price, Description,
and Image, and each row is a different candy.
Since we have a lot of candies that can be easily organized into a
database, we'll use that instead of SharedPreferences.
To use a database we need to write some SQL commands to create a
table and eventually perform operations like inserting, reading, and deleting.
If you're not familiar with SQL databases, we'll cover everything you
need for this course.  But if you want to learn more database concepts,
check out our Try SQL course.
But where do we write this SQL?  When you're writing Android apps,
the convention is to create a Contract class to store information
about your database.  Just like defining a SQL database's organization
in a schema, you can do the same thing in a Contract class with Android.
We're going to create a Contract class to define constants like the
table and column names.
We can create a new class by right-clicking the Java folder and
selecting New, Java Class, and we'll name it CandyContract.
In that CandyContract Java file, we'll define our database name,
database version, table name, and column names.
A good rule is to put your definitions that are global to your whole
database in the root level of that class, then we'll have classes
inside that class for each table.  So right now, the CandyEntry
class for the candy table that lists its name and columns.
We'll define our column names by setting properties in that inner
CandyEntry class.  We also need to implement the BaseColumns
interface so that our CandyEntry class inherits a primary key field
called ID that we'll need later.  It's not required, but this can
help your database work seamlessly with the Android framework.
We're going to use our raw SQL code to create our candies table.
As a review, the create table command creates a table in our
database with the specified columns and data types.
So this SQL command would generate the following table structure.
We can take this create table SQL code and combine it with our static
CandyEntry class properties that represent our different table and
column names, and then store that command in a new string variable
named SQL_CREATE_ENTRIES.  Now whenever we need to create this table,
we can reference this variable.  We'll also create the variable
SQL_DELETE_ENTRIES, which we'll use to delete our table.
This is also how we'll update our table.
We'll just delete it and create a new one since we'll be pulling all
of the current candies from our Candy API.
Now that we have our contract set up, we want to actually create our database.
We'll use the SQLiteOpenHelper class to manage database creation.
It will take care of opening the database if it exists,
creating it if it doesn't, and upgrading it as necessary.
To use the SQLiteOpenHelper class, we need to create a new Java
class that inherits from it, which we'll call CandyDBHelper.
When we create the class we can select SQLiteOpenHelper as the superclass.
The CandyDBHelper needs a constructor and needs to override the
onCreate and onUpgrade methods.
Our constructor will call the super method, which just calls the
SQLiteOpenHelper's constructor.  The constructor takes in the
context, the database name, and the database version.
Remember we created those in the CandyContract class earlier,
so we can use those here.  Null is for the optional CursorFactory,
which we won't be using.
The onCreate method makes a handle to the database named db available,
then we can use that db object to call the exacSQL method,
which will take in a command as a string and run it against the database.
The command we're executing here is the SQL_CREATE_ENTRIES
statement we made earlier to create our table with the columns we defined.
To implement our onUpgrade method to upgrade our database,
we'll simply execute our statement to delete the table,
and then recreate our table.  Now we have everything in place to
begin using our database to store data, but first it's time for
you to practice setting up a database in the challenges.