Welcome back.  In the last section we got a response in the form
of JSON data.  Now we're going to work on parsing that JSON data.
Our JSON response has a lot of information about our candies in it.
So to start, let's look at a simple example when we have one candy
name inside of a JSON object.  When you're looking at JSON,
square brackets means it's a JSON array containing multiple objects.
Curly brackets means it's a JSON object, and each value has a corresponding key.
Here the key is name and the value is Tropical Wave.
So to parse this, we need to create a JSONArray object with the
entire response string.  Then we need to look up the first JSON object
in that array with getJSONObject at position 0.
Then inside that JSON object we can look up the key name.
Now after these three lines of code are run, candyName would be Tropical Wave.
If we look at the actual JSON the Candy API returns in detail,
it looks like this.  Inside of each JSON object we have keys for each
property; the id, name, image, price, and description.
So the response contains an array of multiple objects,
and each object has five keys.
Since eventually we want to pass the name, image, price,
and description to the detail activity, it makes sense to create a
separate Candy class with properties for each of those values.
Let's jump over to Android Studio to see how to create a new class.
To create a new class we can right-click the folder with our package
name, com.codeschool.candycoded, under the java folder and select New, Class.
The name for our class will be Candy, and we can keep the default
values and press OK.  This will generate a new public class called
Candy where we'll add our property's id, name, image URL, price, and description.
We could write Java code to loop over each JSON object in our JSON
array, and then map the properties to the properties in our Candy
class, but there's an easier way.  We can use the external library
GSON to automatically convert JSON objects into Java objects.
GSON will help us map JSON keys and values directly to our custom
candy objects without a lot of boilerplate code.
For GSON to work without any configuration, the properties in your
class need to match up exactly with the keys in your JSON file,
so we're leaving price as a string for now, but eventually we might
want to change it to a decimal or a long.
Just like before with our async library, to use the GSON library
we need to add it as a dependency in our build.gradle file.
Let's say we have this JSON response string that we want to convert
to a candy object.  First we'll create a GSON object by calling
GsonBuilder.create, and then we'll use the fromJson method with the
JSON string and the class we want to convert it to, which is the Candy class.
Then after we run this code we would have a Candy object with all of
its properties set.  For instance, candy.name would be Tropical
Wave and candy.price would be 5.99, and so on.
Remember, it's important that your properties in your class match
up exactly with the keys in your JSON file.
If they don't, the fromJson method will return an error because it
won't understand how to map the values into an object.
If our JSON has an array of objects, like the one we're looking at
now with our candy data, we can use GSON to handle an array of
objects by simply adding square brackets to the Candy class.
We'll add this GSON code to the end of our onSuccess method.
Now that we have all of our candy objects in the candies array,
let's update the adapter to use these candy names instead of those
hard coded values.  Back in our onSuccess method, we'll first clear
what's in the adapter now with the clear method, and then we'll use
a for loop to loop over each candy in the candies array and add
candy.name to the adapter.  Let's jump over to Android Studio to
see the ListView updating in the background.
In order to see our candy ListView updating in the background,
we're going to go into the MainActivity.java file to the top of the
onCreate method where we originally added candies to our ArrayList,
and remove all of the candies from our original ArrayList except one.
This way when there's more than one candy, we know those are from
our network request.  We can see the code we just added to our
onSuccess callback method that parses the JSON into a candy array,
and then adds the candies to our adapter.
Let's look at this in action by running our app.
Great, that's just what we wanted.  We can barely see our app
started with one candy because then it quickly updated to our full
candy list that we got from our network request.
That's it for this section.  It's time for you to practice using
GSON in the challenges.  Good luck.