Our Candy Coded store sells sweet treats galore.
How do we get it on the map?
Let's build a sugar-coated Android app!
With tasty layouts and views,
full of delicious candy hues,
our users will be overjoyed by our super sweet apps powered with Android.
Welcome back.  In level 2 we're going to use an HTTP request to get
dynamic data into our app.
It doesn't make sense to hard code our store's candy in our app.
If the candy ever changes, the user would have to update their app
to get the latest candy.  Instead, we want to fetch the latest candy
data with an HTTP request from our server.
Let's look at how to do this in our app.
First we need to understand that by default, all components of the
same app run in the same process and thread called the main thread.
This thread runs commands sequentially.  For example, ours right now
draws the layout to the screen, creates the ArrayList of candy names,
creates the ArrayAdapter, populates the ListView, and finally creates
the item click listener.  The only exception in this order of events
is the callback method that gets triggered when a list item is clicked,
and even then that still gets called on the main thread.
In Android the main thread is primarily responsible for drawing to
the screen and handling the user interaction, so it's also often
called the UI thread.  The problem is if we also do time consuming
operations like network access or database queries on that same
thread, the whole UI would be blocked until those finish.
Instead we can do network, access or database queries on a separate
background thread that runs at the same time in the background.
Then, once that background operation finishes, it returns the results
to the UI thread.  This way the UI can continue running smoothly.
There's actually a lot of boilerplate code that goes into creating an
HTTP request in the background thread using the async task class,
but we can use the external library AsyncHttpClient to do this for us.
AsyncHttpClient is a class that will do the HTTP request in the
background thread to get our current candy items.
That will return a response that contains the current candy items
to the UI thread.
To use an external library like AsyncHttpClient, we need to add it
as a dependency at the bottom of our app's build.gradle file.
To make an HTTP request, we can create a new object and make a request
with the get method.  Android Studio should automatically import the
correct library, but if it doesn't, we need this import line.
The get method takes in two parameters.  One is the URL of our
request, and the other is a response handler object.
The response handler we're using is the TextHttpResponseHandler,
which needs to implement two callback methods, the onSuccess callback
method and the onFailure callback method.
Inside the onSuccess callback method, we'll just log the JSON response
for now as a debug message with the Log.d method.
This is just a first step to see that this is working before we
actually build the code to display the candy.
In the onFailure callback method, we'll log the error with the Log.e method.
If we try to run our app now we'll get an error.
That's because we haven't given our app permission to access the internet.
We can do that in the AndroidManifest.xml file.
Every app has this file and it provides essential information about
your app like the icon image to use, the app name, and which activity
to launch when the app starts.  We'll add the internet permission
to the top of the manifest file with the uses-permission tag.
This will ask the user if they want to allow the app to access the
internet when they open the app.  Let's jump over to Android Studio
to see those log messages in action.
The log output in Android Studio can be viewed in the Android Monitor
window under the logcat tab.  It's blank right now, but when we run
our app we'll start to see the log update.
We can look for our debug message with the tag AsyncHttpClient,
and our message, response =.  Here it is, and we can see the response
is a JSON string that represents each candy and its information like
Tropical Wave, its image URL, price, and description, and the next
candy, Berry Bouncer, and so on.  Next we'll parse this JSON response
into something we can work with.
That's it for section 1.  Now it's time for you to practice requests
in the challenges.  Good luck.