Welcome back.  We've requested some JSON data, we've parsed it into
an array of candy objects, and now we'd like to pass some of that
data to the detail activity.
Right now our detail activity is only showing the candy name,
but we'd like it to also show the price, description, and image that
we got from our Candy API.  To do that, we can get the image, price,
and description from the array of candy objects and send it to the detail activity.
We can pass these properties to the detail activity with the intent
like we originally did with the name.  This would be in the onItemClick
callback method.  We'll also want to use the candies array we just
created, so we'll change it to a class variable by declaring it at the
top of the MainActivity class.  This will allow us to access the
candies array and all of the methods in this class, not just the
onSuccess callback method.  We can use the putExtra method to
pass the image, price, and description by referencing those properties
from the candies array, like this.
Back in the DetailActivity class, we can get the image,
price, and description we passed in after we display the candy
name in the TextView.  But before we display them to the screen in
our app, let's first log them to make sure they're coming in correctly.
We can get our passed in values from the intent with the same
getStringExtra method we used for the candy name, then we'll log
these properties with the Log.d method to make sure they look correct.
Like before, we also want to add some checks to make sure these
values actually exist to prevent errors.
Now we should have our values logging in the detail activity.
Let's jump over to Android Studio to see if those values are coming
into the detail activity.
If we look at our DetailActivity.java file in our onCreate method at
the bottom, we can see our log message logging the image, price, and description.
Let's see this working by running our app, then to start our
DetailActivity we need to click on a candy.
Now if we go into our Android monitor under the logcat tab,
we should see our log message.  There it is marked DetailActivity,
and it shows the Intent data with the image URL, price, and description.
Now we know that this data is being passed correctly to the detail
activity and we can work on actually displaying it in the user interface.
That's it for level 2.  Now it's time for you to practice passing your
response data to an activity.
Get it with the.
We need to write some.
To delete our tabrle.
Challenges.