Hey, let’s give C# a try and keep it classy.
Our variables and methods will make things very jazzy.
Oh, we'll compile the code and make our apps real smart, as we orchestrate
and riff on the smooth sounds of C#.
Welcome back to Try C#.  My name is Eric Fisher.
In this level we're going to learn about variables.
Let's make our console application a little bit more useful.
Let's collect band information, asking for the name of the band,
the number of members, and then responding with that information at the end.
Now one problem we're going to run into is we're asking for this information
in a different place than we're actually using that information.
In order to store this information we're going to use variables, which
will allow us to store this information in memory and then later retrieve it
when we need it.  We will ask for the name of the band, we'll then store
that information in our named variable.  This act of storing is known as
setting the variable.  We will then ask for the number of members in the
band, which we will then set to our numberOfMembers variable, and then
when we go to announce the band we will retrieve the information
from the name and the numberOfMembers variables for making our announcement.
This retrieving of variables is known as getting our variable.
Before we add our variables, let's ask for the information as well as
set up the announce message, so we can do a Console.WriteLine to ask
the name of the band, a Console.WriteLine to ask the number of members
of the band, and a Console.WriteLine that would give back the name
and number of band members.  We're going to leave two blanks in that
final message for where we're going to actually use our variables later.
In order to use a variable, we need to declare it.
To do this, we would provide the data type of our variable, as well as
the name of our variable.
In order to set our variable we need to use the equals character.
This will set whatever we provide in the right side of the equals
to whatever variable is on the left side of the equals.
In this case, we're going to declare our name variable to be a data type
string and then set it to whatever our user inputs into the Console.ReadLine
method call.  And as we mentioned before, we're going to use our variables
down here in the announcement message.  Now one thing you'll note is
we're going to need to use the double quotes and the plus to do string
concentration between our variable and our hard coded string.
At this point we're going to want to get our name variable in our announcement,
we can do this by going to our Console.WriteLine for our announcement
and where we have that first blank, we're instead going to use the name
variable plus and then our hard coded string.
For our numberOfMembers variable, since we're looking to actually
have a number of individuals in the band, we're going to use an integer,
which allows us to actually declare whole numbers.
We will then set our numberOfMembers variable using the Console.ReadLine
method call.  If we were to actually compile this code though, we would
receive a message - Cannot implicitly convert 'string' to 'int'.
Before we look into actually solving this problem, let's look into
C#'s different data types.
There are 15 built in data types in C#, however we're really only going to be
focusing on 3 of them right now, which is string, which is a collection
of characters, integer, which is whole numbers, which can be both positive
and negative, as well as boolean, which is simply true or false.
C# can convert between data types such as string to integer, but sometimes
we need to be a little bit more explicit about that.
We can convert string to integer using the int.Parse method call.
The int.Parse method call will accept a string parameter and then convert
that into an integer.  In our case we're going to use the int.Parse method call
and then provide it with a Console.ReadLine method call as its parameter,
which will finally assign our integer to our numberOfMembers variable.
Like we had to do with our name variable, we're going to have to go to our
announcements Console.WriteLine method call and replace our blank
with a numberOfMembers variable as well as we're going to have to add
the plus characters on either side to concatenate the string.
Something you'll also notice is while we had to explicitly convert
string to integer, we don’t have to explicitly convert integer to string.
This is because every possible value of integer is accepted by string
so it can be implicitly converted.  Now that we're finished with the code,
let's go back and run our application.  When we run our dotnet run command
at this point, our application will now be able to use our variables.
It will ask, what is the name of your band?  We can respond with Awesome Inc.
It will then ask, how many people are in your band?
We can respond with 3, and it will respond with Awesome Inc has 3 members.
Before we move on to the challenges, let's do a quick recap of variables
and data types.  Variables are used to store values in memory for later use.
The act of storing a variable is setting it.
The act of retrieving a variable is getting it.
To set a variable we use the equals character followed by the desired value.
To get a variable we can just use the variable's name.
Not all data types can be converted implicitly.
In many cases we'll have built in parse methods.
That's it for this level.  Now it's your turn to use variables and data types
in the challenges.  Have fun.
An integer, blahh.
To our number of methods vari.
Of our, the variable, the blah.
Blah, blah, blah.  I like where you're going with this.
(Burp), excuse me.  I can.
Need to be…