Hey, let’s give C# a try and keep it classy.
Our variables and methods will make things very jazzy.
Oh, we'll compile the code and make our apps real smart, as we orchestrate
and riff on the smooth sounds of C#.
Welcome to Try C#.  My name is Eric Fisher.
In this course we are going to learn about the C# programming language.
Exactly what is C#?  C# is a general purpose object oriented programming
language introduced by Microsoft in 2002.  Some notable characteristics
of C# is it is a compiled language, which means it can take it from
the source code that was as developers can understand and then translate it
into machine code, which our computers can understand.
It's also a strongly typed language in that anytime we set the data type
no something, it will always have that data type.
It also a .NET language.  A .NET language is a little bit different than
a regular complied language in the sense there is a middle step between
our source code and the machine code, that's what's known as byte code
or the common intermediate language.  What this lets us do is this lets us
use any .NET language together, whether that's C#, F#, VB.NET or
so on, where we can use these libraries together without needing to
convert.
The first thing we're going to do is create a new C# application.
We can do this by using the dotnet new command, which will create a new
C# application whatever directory we are currently in.
This will create a program.cs file, as well as a csproj file.
All modern .NET applications will start within the program.cs file,
so we're going to go ahead and go there to begin with.
When we open our program.cs file we'll see some code that has already
been generated for us.  There will be the program class as well as the
main method.  Classes allow us to separate our code into objects.
Methods contain the actual executable code of our objects.
We're not really going to delve into the object oriented side of things
right now, but we are going to go through the executable code.
When our application is run our execution will start in our main method.
This line of code will be the first line of code executed in our application.
What Console.WriteLine does is it'll take whatever we pass in as a parameter
and write that out to the console.  So let's see how we can run that.
Before we can run our application we need to use dotnet restore to restore
our dependencies.  Dotnet restore needs to be run before the first time
we run the application or any time we change our dependencies.
To run our application for the first time we can use the dotnet run command
and what we will see is we'll see that Hello World string appear in the console.
A string is a collection of characters, typically wrapped in double quotes,
like you see here.
Let's make our existing application be able to read user input and then
use that input as part of its output.  When we run our demo application,
we're going to want it to say type a message, we will then be prompted
to input a message at which point it will respond with you said, and whatever
message you input.  We're going to need two things to accomplish this.
We're going to need to be able to accept user input as well as we're going
to need to concentrate strings.
To read user input we can use the Console.ReadLine method, which will take
whatever is typed into the console and return it as a string.
We'll add a second Console.WriteLine method call, which will then take
a Console.ReadLine method call as its parameter.
At this point we want to take that you said string and put that in front of
whatever user input we've provided.  We can accomplish this by using
the plus character.  This will allow us to concatenate our two strings,
that is to combine them.  Let's run the application again using the dotnet run
command.  When we do this we will see Type a message, to which we can respond
Hello World, and then the application will respond You said Hello World.
So what's happening behind the scenes with the string concatenation?
What's actually happening is when the user types in their input, it's
effectively like they're replacing that input with the string they provided.
At that point we would have our two strings with our plus between, after which
it will combine those strings into a single string, which is then provided
to our Console.WriteLine method call.
Before we move on to the challenges, let's do a quick recap of the two
dotnet commands we've learned - dotnet new, which creates a new C# application
and dotnet run which will compile and run our application.
And that's it for this first level.  Now it's your turn to try some C#
in the challenges.
Without having to go through a bunch of conversions.
You said havting.
Havting.
Or not, that's wrong entirely.  Yeah.
Run, we will.
Line of code, thaaaa.
When our application, it's always the simple ones that get you.