Hey, let’s give C# a try and keep it classy.
Our variables and methods will make things very jazzy.
Oh, we'll compile the code and make our apps real smart, as we orchestrate
and riff on the smooth sounds of C#.
Welcome to Try C#.  My name is Eric Fisher.
In this level we're going to learn about conditions.
So we have a problem, when users enter something that we can't parse,
we get an error.  For example, when we ask how many people are in your band?
And the user responds with duck, we will get the error Unhandled Exception:
System.FormatException: Input string was not the correct format.
This is because our app is expecting a number here, not a string.
Now let's go back to code and see where this error is coming from.
This is the parse method throwing an error because it cannot convert
our string into an integer.  When calling int.parse and then providing
something it cannot convert into an int, you'll get an error along the lines
of input string was not in correct format.  To fix this issue we can use
the TryParse method.  The TryParse method will return true or false
if it was capable of converting the string into an integer.
To accomplish this let's go ahead and move our number of members declaration
to being in its own line by having int numberOfMembers = 0.
Next we'll add the int.TryParse method call, the first parameter is the value
we intend on converting, in this case our Console.ReadLine method,
and then the second parameter is where we're going to actually output
what we've converted.  So here we're going to use what's known as
an output parameter.  They're not super common in C#, but you will end up
using them here and there, for example, in our TryParse method,
but what this allows us to do is as one of our parameters we can output
values from our method to variables.  Number of variables will be set
in the event our int.TryParse is successful in parsing the string.
In this case we're going to want to change the behavior of our application
depending on the success or fail of TryParse.
We can accomplish this using conditions.  For example, we can use the if
condition.  Anytime whatever is in the parenthesis of our if condition
is true, we will run the code within that if block.
If whatever is in the parenthesis is not true, we will not run whatever
is in the if block.  Whatever comes after the if block will be run
regardless of whether or not the if condition was true or false.
Examples of the results of our if condition, in the event that ready is true,
we will run the method DoIfTrue.  We will also run DoNoMatterWhat.
In the event that ready is false, we will only do DoNoMatterWhat.
Since our int.TryParse returns true or false, depending on whether or not
it was successful in parsing the string into an integer, we can use it
as our condition for our if block.  Realistically we're probably only
going to want to be changing our behavior in the event that we actually
fail to parse the input value.  So in this case, instead of looking for when
we are successful in parsing, let's look for the times that we are not successful.
We can do this by adding the not character, the exclamation mark, before
our condition, which tells us we're looking for it to be not true.
From here, in the event we are unable to parse our string into an integer,
we should provide a message back to the user using Console.WriteLine
input was not valid, and then we can use the Environment.Exit method call
providing it a parameter of 0, which just means we were successful
in completing the application, to stop the program where it's at.
At this point our invalid input is handled.
Now if the user were to enter something invalid, we would provide a
simple user friendly error message.  So when the application is run,
it would go what is the name of your band?  We could respond with Awesome Inc.
How many people are in your band?  We could respond with duck, at which point
the application would say input was not valid and the application would end.
There are many cases in our applications where we want to compare two things.
We might see if these two things are equal, if they are not equal to each other
or they're less than and greater than each other.
For example, do we have 1 band member?  We're going to check to see if we have
exactly 1 band member using the equals equals to establish equality.
Do we have more than 0 band members?  we can just use 1 greater than 0.
Is our band not named "Awesome"?  We can just check exclamation mark equal
"Awesome".
The next thing we might want to use when changing the behavior of our
application is the else condition.  The else condition will only execute
code within the else block in the event the if condition before it is not
true.  So if whatever is in our if block's parenthesis is false, we will
then run the code in our else condition instead.
We can take this a step farther by using else and if together to create
series of conditions, that way we can check if something is true, in the event
it is not, we can check to see if something else is true before proceeding
to our else.  So if ready was true we would execute the DoIfTrue method call.
However, if ready was false, but our name was Awesome, we would run
our DoFalseAndAwesome method call.  In the event that we weren’t ready
and our band was also not named Awesome, we would run our else code block
resulting in the DoIfFalseAndNotAwesome method call.
We can use the if, else if, and else conditions to declare the type of our band
based on what was input.  So the first thing we'll do is check to make sure
they had at least 1 band member, we can't have a band with less than 1 member.
We can accomplish this by using the if condition, checking our
numberOfMembers variable is less than 1.  Inside that if code block,
we can do Console.WriteLine and then for its parameter have a string,
you must have at least 1 member, and then do an Environment.Exit with the
code 0.  That way we will end our application in the event they have put
less than 1 band member.  In the event the if block is not executed,
we can use else if to check if our number of members is equal to 1.
If it is, we can write to the console the name of the band and then add
the string is a solo.  In the event our number of members is not less than 1
and is not equal to 1, we can check to see if the number of members is
equal to 2 and if it is we can write to the console the name of the band
followed by is a duo.  And in the event that none of the previous conditions
were true, we can just use the else block to write out to the console
the name of the band has the numberOfMembers variable members.
You'll notice all of the code blocks that were only a single line of code
do not have the curly braces around them.  Curly braces are optional
in code blocks with only one line of code.
Our application is now complete.  It is more robust and able to handle
different information.  We've also added two new features.
We now print the type of band - solo, duo, et cetera, based on the number
of members.  We also can handle invalid user input.
Before we you begin the challenges let's take a quick recap of conditions
and expressions.  We can change the flow of our application using conditions
and expressions.  The if statement only executes its block when the condition
is true.  The else statement only executes its block when the if condition
is false.  Some expressions to remember are these three, two equals
characters means is equal to.  An exclamation mark and an equals character
is not equal to.  An exclamation mark before a condition will only pass
the condition in the event it is not true.
That's the end of level 3.  Now it's your turn to use conditions and expressions
in the challenges and I'll see you in the wrap up video.
Variable, blah, blah.
They have a problem.  Problem?
Much better, blah.
That made no sense grammatically.
Oh crap.
The plus..