Our Candy Coded store sells sweet treats galore.
How do we get it on the map?  Let's build a sugar-coated Android app!
With tasty layouts and views full of delicious candy hues,
our users will be overjoyed by our super sweet apps powered with Android.
Welcome back to Level 3 where we'll be covering ListViews and adapters.
Now that we've added a TextView and an ImageView to our layout,
we also want a ListView to show our store's available candy.
A ListView is a subclass of AdapterView, which means it needs an
adapter to get its data.  Unlike a TextView and an ImageView,
we can't set the contents of a ListView in the layout file.
We actually need an adapter to populate the ListView with data.
We'll use an ArrayAdapter since we have our candy list stored as an ArrayList.
But you may be wondering why we can't just send a list directly to our ListView.
By moving the data from the ListView into the adapter, we can do
things like scroll through a list of many items without having to
store them all in memory.  So the adapter only needs a reference to
the raw data and instructions on how to build each item in the list,
and then the ListView can just request items from the adapter.
Let's look at how adapters improve performance and save memory.
The ListView starts by requesting a view for every visible item and
has a few above and below so those are ready as the user scrolls.
But as the user scrolls, if the ListView continued to create new views
in a list with thousands of records, we would quickly run out of
memory, and performance would suffer.
Instead, as the view scrolls off screen, the adapter recycles it by
populating it with new data and queuing it up for it to be displayed
as the user keeps scrolling.
Now that we know how adapters work, let's add a ListView and an
adapter to populate it with data.  The steps for doing this are first
add a ListView to our main_activity layout.
Then we need to create a separate layout to describe what each item in
our list will look like.  Then in the Java code we need to get the raw
data we want to display, create the ArrayAdapter,
and finally connect that ArrayAdapter to the ListView.
To add a ListView to our activity_main layout, we can drag it over in
the design view, which will generate the following code in XML.
If we look at the generated XML code, we can see the layout_width and
layout_height were set to default values for us.
They were both set to match_parent, which means the view will try to
be as big as its parent by expanding to take up the remaining space in the layout.
We also went ahead and set the id property to be list_view_candy.
Match_parent as the layout_height means the list will take up the
available height left after the ImageView and the TextView.
And if we have more contents in our ListView than can show on screen,
the ListView will automatically scroll.  Match_parent as the
layout_width means it'll be as wide as the screen.
That's because there's nothing on the left or right of our ListView
fighting for space in the layout.
Step number 2 is to create a layout to tell the ArrayAdapter how to
create each item in our ListView.  It will have a single TextView with
a width and height of match_parent since we want each list item to
fill the ListView.  And we'll also add an id of text_view_candy so we
can find it later.  Let's jump into Android Studio so we can see how
to create this layout file.
To create a new layout for our list item, we can right-click the
layout directory and select New, Layout resource file.
In the pop-up, we want to name our file list_item_candy.
The root element is TextView since all we want for each item in our
list is a TextView.  If we look at the raw XML that was generated,
we have a TextView with the width and height set to match_parent.
We'll also add an ID, text_view_candy, so we can find this TextView later.
Now that we have all the pieces in place for our layout, it's time for
us to write some Java code.  We'll write this code at the bottom of
our onCreate method in MainActivity.java.
For step 3, we'll create an ArrayList to store the names of our candy.
Then we can add each candy string with the add method.
Just like before with the TextView, as soon as we type ArrayList,
Android Studio automatically imports the ArrayList library for us.
Next we need to create an ArrayAdapter from our candy_list.
We need a few things in the ArrayAdapter constructor, so let's look at
those things in detail.  First, we need the context of where the
ArrayAdapter will be used, which is this activity, so we use the this keyword.
Second, we need a reference to the layout file we created to build
each item in the ListView.  Then we need a reference to that specific
TextView inside the layout file that we named text_view_candy previously.
And finally, we need the ArrayList of our candies.
Step 5 is connecting the ArrayAdapter to the ListView, but before we
can do that, we need to get a reference to that ListView.
Like before, we can use the findViewById method with the ID we created
for the ListView previously.
If you forgot, we created the id property for the ListView in our
activity_main layout, so we can reference that ID, list_view_candy.
Now that we've found the ListView by its ID, we can set its adapter
with the setAdapter method.  Let's jump over to Android Studio to see
all of this code together and to demo our ListView in action.
If we look at all the code we added in MainActivity.java, we can see
the ArrayList, candy_list, and all of the candy strings we added.
Then the ArrayAdapter we created with a reference to this
MainActivity, our layout, list_item_candy, which we can go to directly
by right-clicking and selecting Go To, Declaration.
That brings us to that layout file, which defines a TextView for each
item in our list.  We also have a reference to that specific
TextView's ID, which we can go to by using Go To, Declaration again.
And the last thing in the adapter is a reference to the candy_list.
Then we created the ListView variable by finding the ListView by its
ID, and if we use Go To, Declaration here, we're taken to the
activity_main layout to the ListView with the ID list_view_candy.
And finally, we attach the adapter to the ListView.
Now if we run our app, we see our ListView working and displaying all
of our candy.
That's it for Level 3.  Now it's time for you to practice writing
ListViews and adapters in the challenges.