Our Candy Coded store sells sweet treats galore.
How do we get it on the map?  Let's build a sugar-coated Android app!
With tasty layouts and views full of delicious candy hues,
our users will be overjoyed by our super sweet apps powered with Android.
Welcome back to Level 2 where we'll be covering layouts, views, and images.
Now that we have some experience working on our layout by adjusting
the text in our TextView to say Products, let's also add an image in
an ImageView and add a ListView.
Now that we have some experience working in our layout by updating the
TextView to say Products, let's add our Candy Coded logo image as an ImageView.
For our ImageView, we'll need to add an image resource.
Image resources either live in the drawable or mipmap folder under the res directory.
Images that are not affected by changes in scale can go in the
drawable folder, but images that are affected by scale,
like your app's icons, which will resize differently on different
devices, should go in the mipmap folder.  Let's jump back into Android
Studio to see how to add our ImageView.
One way to easily add images to your project is to copy and paste the
image directly, so we'll copy this candy_coded logo from our desktop
and then paste it into the res drawable folder.
We then get a pop-up confirming we want to copy that file to this
directory, and we can hit OK.  Then we can view it to make sure it looks alright.
Then, back in our layout design, we're going to drag and drop an ImageView.
To find the ImageView, you can start typing ImageView in the palette to search.
And now that we've found an ImageView, we can drag it over.
You can see there are some guidelines that pop up.
We'll center the image above the TextView.
Then we get asked to choose the image's source, and we'll choose the
image we just added.  Now we see our image in our layout,
but there are a few problems.  We need to drag it to the center,
and the aspect ratio is off on the bounding box, so we'll fix that by
selecting adjustViewBounds.  This resizes the width and height of the
ImageView object to exactly match the width and height of the image it displays.
If we look at the raw XML that was generated, we can see the
properties that are set.  The width and height are set to wrap_content
by default, which means the view will be just big enough to enclose the contents.
AdjustViewBounds is set to true.  The source is set to @drawable/candy_coded.
And it also has layout_editor_absoluteX and absoluteY set to 0dp.
This is because we're using a ConstraintLayout and how we positioned
the image in the editor by dragging it to the very top.
With a ConstraintLayout, we can rearrange elements by dragging things
around in the design view like this.  But if we know we just want
items to flow from top to bottom or left to right, there's a better way.
Let's go back to the slides to talk about the different types of
layouts in Android.
The commonly used layouts in Android are LinearLayout,
which arranges child objects in a horizontal or vertical row,
ConstraintLayout, which we are currently using, where view objects are
arranged relative to each other with constraints, and a Web Layout,
which displays a web page.  Since we want our title, image,
and list to come one after the other vertically, it sounds like a
vertical LinearLayout is what we want.
We'll start by replacing the default relative layout in the
activity_main.xml file with a LinearLayout.
We also need to add the orientation property set to vertical.
Let's jump back to Android Studio to see how to do that.
To change our activity's layout from a ConstraintLayout to a
LinearLayout, we can go into the TextView and edit the XML directly.
Notice the ConstraintLayout is from the support library.
That's because ConstraintLayout is a new feature of Android,
so the support library allows it to be backwards compatible.
We'll just replace the ConstraintLayout tag with LinearLayout.
Notice the closing tag was also updated.  We'll also set the
LinearLayout's orientation property to vertical since we want a vertical LinearLayout.
Since we're using a LinearLayout now, we don't need these relative
properties that are used with a ConstraintLayout, so we can delete those.
If we look at the design preview, our LinearLayout is working nicely.
But we actually want the Products TextView below our ImageView.
To do this, we can drag and drop the TextView in the Component Tree or
in the preview window.  Now our layout is looking like we wanted with
the ImageView above the TextView.
Our app is starting to look pretty good, but we want to make a few, small adjustments.
We also want to center the Products TextView and add some padding to
the top of that under the image.  Let's go do that back in Android Studio.
We want to center the Products TextView and add padding to the top
under the image.  In the Properties window, we need to click View all
properties to find Padding.  We'll set its paddingTop to 16dp,
which is the standard padding value according to the Android design
guidelines, and we'll also center it by setting layout_gravity to center_horizontal.
This looks a lot better already in the preview.
We can also see in the XML that the TextView has the properties
paddingTop and layout_gravity set.  While we're here, we'll also add
16dp as a dimension value so it's not hardcoded like we did before,
and we'll name it activity_padding.  Now if we run our app,
it looks much better with the Products TextView centered and some
padding on the top.  We still need to add an image for our app icon so
users can find it.  To add an app icon, right-click the res folder and
select New, Image Asset.  Then Icon Type is Launcher Icons,
Asset Type is Image, and then we'll navigate to wherever your icon image is.
I have mine save to the Desktop as candy_coded_icon.
We'll set Shape to None to get rid of the white background and click Next.
Now we can see the different resolutions for the icon that will be generated.
Which one is used depends on the resolution of the device running the app.
Finally, click Finish.  Under the mipmap folder under ic_launcher,
we can see all of the different resolution images that were created
from low resolution to high resolution.  Apps can also now define
round launcher icons, which are used on devices that support them,
so we'll want to do that as well.  We'll do the same thing again,
except set the Name to ic_launcher_round, find our same icon image,
set the Shape to Circle instead of None, click Next, and click Finish.
Now if we run our app, we can see our app icon in our listed apps,
and if we look at the overview, we also see our app and its icon in
the top left.
That's it for Level 2 - Section 1.  Now it's time for you to practice
what you learned in the challenges.