Welcome back.  In this section, we'll be editing the layout with Java code.
Previously, we set properties like text and images in the layout file,
but we can also change them while the app is running in Java code.
Let's see how to do this by setting the TextView's text in MainActivity.java.
In order to see that we've actually updated the TextViews's text
property, we'll set it to say Temporary Text now and then update it to
say Products in the Java code.
Let's get familiar with what's already in our MainActivity.java file.
First we have our package name, then other packages we need to import,
and then our class MainActivity that extends from AppCompatActivity,
which is the base class for all activities and provides standard functionality.
If you're not a Java expert and this code looks weird to you, don't worry.
We're going to provide you with all of the Java code you need to build this app.
The next code you see is a method called onCreate, which gets called
when our activity is starting.  The first line of that method calls
super.onCreate, which calls the base class' onCreate method to take
care of some basic activity setup.  Then the second line calls
setContentView, which sets the activity's content to what's already in
our activity's layout file.  If you're wondering how the layout just
magically appeared on the screen, that line of code is how it was done.
So all of the code that was there is going to stay there,
but we're going to add code to the bottom of the onCreate method.
That's where we'll update the text for our TextView.
First we need to find our TextView.  To find a view in Java,
you use the findViewById method.  We'll call the method from this
activity using the this keyword, and we also need to pass an ID as a parameter.
But we actually never defined an ID for our TextView, so let's do that now.
In our layout file, we'll set the TextView's id property equal to @+id/text_view_title.
The @+id means this ID will be added as an ID resource at runtime,
and the text_view_title is the name we chose for the actual ID.
Then in our findViewById method we can reference this ID with R.id.text_view_title.
The R.id means we're looking up the ID in the app's resources.
Now we have findViewById returning a general view, but we want to save
it to a TextView variable, so we also need to cast it as a TextView.
Something to notice is that as soon as we type TextView,
Android Studio automatically imports TextView from the widget's
library for us.  This is a nice timesaving feature that Android does for us.
Now that we have our TextView in a variable, we can set its text to
say Products with the setText method.  If we run our app, we can see
our TextView says Products, not Temporary Text, so our program actually worked.
But remember the best practice we covered in Level 1 that we don't
want a hardcode strings?  Let's remove the product string here and
instead reference that products_title string we created in Level 1.
We can do that by replacing the string with R.string.products_title.
If we run our app again, we can see this is still working because our
TextView says Products.
That's it for Level 2.  Now it's time for you to write some Java code
in the challenges.
Is that good?  I don't know.
Sweeter and sweeter.  I don't know.
Utensils.
You want to maybe say ---