Welcome back to Section 2 where we'll be covering activities, layouts, and resources.
Each screen in our app is called an activity and is controlled by a
Java file and a layout file.  The first screen in our app is launched
by the MainActivity.java file, and it displays the layout defined in activity_main.xml.
It's important to note that files have different naming conventions.
Java files use PascalCase where each word starts with a capital
letter, and layout files use snake_case where separate words are
separated by underscores and everything is lowercase and the first
word is the type of layout.  So the Java file is called MainActivty,
and the layout that goes with it is called activity_main.
A layout describes the visual structure of everything you'll see on this screen.
A layout can contain things like buttons, text, and images to display,
but how do we get those things to actually do something?
That's where the Java file comes in.
The activity is a Java file that controls behaviors for things like
managing layouts, event handling, putting data in lists, and opening other activities.
Let's jump over to Android Studio and edit our layout to adjust the
text in the TextView.
An activity is a Java file where you can write code to control behaviors.
Our activity is in MainActivity.java, which we'll update later.
A layout is an XML file where you configure what's displayed in the activity.
Our layout is in activity_main.xml.  Layouts have a design view,
which shows a preview, and a TextView that shows the raw XML code.
Now we want to update the text Hello World to say Products.
To do this, we select the TextView.  You can see it's also selected in
the Component Tree.  Then go to its properties and find the text property.
Then we just type in Products.  The text property with the wrench is
for changes to the preview only, not in our app, so we won't be using that.
We could've also updated the text property in the raw XML code,
which we can see has changed to Products now as well.
While we're here, we'll also update the textSize to 24sp.
Now we can apply these new changes to our running emulator using the
Apply Changes button that looks like a lightning bolt next to the Run button.
This allows you to apply changes to your running app without building
a new APK file, so it's faster than the Run button alone.
You can still use the Run button if you want to push your changes and
force an app restart.  We can see our TextView's text now says
Products and is larger.
We just set our text size to 24sp, but what does that mean?
Android supports a lot of different dimension units.
We'll use dp and sp in our app.  Dp stands for density-independent
pixels, which means that for phones with different pixel densities or
sizes, like the Moto X and Google Pixel shown here,
the view dimensions in your layout will resize properly for both.
Sp, or scale-independent pixels, is the same as dp, but also scaled by
the user's font size preference, so we'll use sp for fonts.
Looking at the TextView code in detail, we see that the layout_width
and layout_height are set to wrap_content by default.
Wrap_content means the view will only be large enough to enclose its
content, so the TextView will only be wide enough and tall enough to
hold the string, Products.
Looking at the text property that contains the string, Products,
we can see it's actually highlighted in yellow and shows a warning,
that hardcoded strings should use a string resource.
So instead of hardcoding the string, we'll create a variable called
products_title to store the string, Products, in a string resource file.
Let's jump over to Android Studio to see how that works.
If we hover over the text, Products, it's highlighted yellow,
and we see a warning that it's a hardcoded value.
To fix this, we can open our strings.xml file.
This is under the res, values directory.  And now we can add a new string value.
We'll add a string with the name products_title and value Products and
then update our layout XML code to use @string/products_title to
reference that variable.  We also hardcoded the textSize to 24sp,
so we can add a new value to dimens.xml, which stands for dimensions,
but there's a shortcut for that.  We can click on the quick-fix light
bulb and select Extract dimension resource.
Then it will help us enter the resource name as title_size, and we hit
OK, and that's it.  Then if we look in dimens.xml, we can see the
title_size resource we just added.
That's it for Level 1.  It's time for you to practice what you learned
in the challenges.  Good luck!