Our Candy Coded store sells sweet treats galore.
How do we get it on the map?  Let's build a sugar-coated Android app!
With tasty layouts and views full of delicious candy hues,
our users will be overjoyed by our super sweet apps powered with Android.
Hello, and welcome to Try Android.  I'm Sarah Holderness, and in this
course we'll be building our first Android app with Android Studio.
Android is a mobile operating system created by Google primarily for
phones and tablets, but has expanded into TVs and wearables.
Android had its first release in 2008 and has released a new version
at least every other year after that.  After alpha and beta,
new versions were named after desserts in alphabetical order from
Cupcake to the current version Oreo.  You could say making apps for
Android is getting sweeter and sweeter.
In this course, we're going to built a simple candy store app that's
going to show a list of all the candy in our store.
We'll build the app from scratch and show you all the steps along the way.
Android Studio is the official IDE for building Android apps,
and you can download it for free at this link, or you can just follow
along in the interactive challenges at the end of each level.
Now in Level 1 we'll cover the basics for cooking up your first Android app.
Apps are like cupcakes.  What I mean is there are some requirements
for creating a cupcake, like ingredients, cooking utensils, a recipe,
and an oven, that are kind of like the requirements for creating an app.
The Android Studio SDK provides standard ways of displaying data in
your app, like buttons, text, images, and lists, and those are like
the ingredients for your app.
Android Studio is an IDE, which stands for Integrated Development
Environment, and is filled with tools for creating your app,
and is kind of like the cooking utensils.
Inside Android Studio, you'll write Java code to control your app
behaviors, which is like the recipe.
And just like the oven pops out your final cupcake, Gradle is the
build system in Android Studio that creates your final APK file that
contains your app and can be loaded on any Android device.
Let's jump over to Android Studio and create and set up a new project.
To create a new project, first open Android Studio.
We'll see a welcome screen where you can select Start a new Android Studio project.
Then we'll configure our new project.  The app name will be Candy Coded.
The company domain will be codeschool.com.
If you don't have a company domain, that's okay.
This is a way for Android to name the package name as a reverse of the
domain, which ensures a unique name so no two apps in the app store
have the same package name, but you can always change it later.
Project location is a folder that I created on the desktop.
Now you choose the minimum SDK.  You can see if we selected the older
API, IceCreamSandwich, our app will run on 100% of devices.
But if we select a newer API like Oreo, the percent drops down to 1%.
So we're going to stick with IceCreamSandwich for our app since it
won't be leveraging any of the newest API features.
Next we'll choose Empty Activity, but you could choose from these starter templates.
And finally, we'll stick with the default activity name, MainActivity,
and generate a related layout file.  Once your project is created,
you can see it's being built by Gradle, which is the build system used with Android.
Android Studio has a lot going on, but don't be overwhelmed.
In this course, we're only going to need to access a few of these menu
and toolbar options to make our first Android app.
You can see the files that were created for you in the Project window
on the left.  The files we're most concerned with are the
MainActivity.java file and activity_main.xml.
But we'll look at those in more detail later.
First, we'll run our app by clicking the Run button, which is this
green triangle that looks like a play icon in the toolbar.
We'll then be asked to choose an emulator.
You can see there are no emulators in the list that pops up.
This will happen the very first time you try to run an app with
Android Studio, so we're going to walk through the process of creating an emulator.
But don't worry.  Once you have one created, you can simply select it
from the list each time you build and run your app.
To create a new one, press the Create New Virtual Device button.
Then select Phone.  We're going to use a Nexus 6P phone,
and we're going to use the newest Oreo API, which will make sure our
our app is forward compatible.  If you haven't already downloaded this
API, you'll need to click the Download link to download it first.  (Working)
And once our emulator is up and running, we can see our app.
Right now it shows the name of our app and text that says Hello World!
Now it's time to practice what you've learned.
See you in the challenges.