Our Candy Coded store sells sweet treats galore.
How do we get it on the map?  Let's build a sugar-coated Android app!
With tasty layouts and views full of delicious candy hues,
our users will be overjoyed by our super sweet apps powered with Android.
Welcome back.  In Level 4, we'll be covering event listeners and toasts.
Before we get started with event listeners, let's improve the
appearance of our ListView first.  We'd like to add some padding to
our ListView and update the font and text size.
Let's jump over to Android Studio to see how to do that.
To add padding to our ListView, we'll go into the design view for
activity_main and select the ListView.  Then we'll find the padding
property and add padding around the whole view by using this general padding property.
We could type in 16dp for the padding value, but we'll use our saved
activity_padding dimension we used before.
Then we can see the list changed in the preview, but let's run our app
to see how it actually looks with our list items.
It looks better on the sides, but we still need some padding between
list items, and let's also update the font and text size while we're here.
We'll go into list_item_candy layout and add paddingTop set to
activity_padding and the same for paddingBottom.
We'll set the fontFamily to casual, the textSize to 18dp, and select Bold.
If we run our app again, that looks much better and like the final app
we wanted to create.
Now that we have our layout looking nice, let's get back to making our
list items actually do something.  You've probably seen this in apps
where you click on an item in the list and it opens another screen
with some details.  We'd like to do that eventually, but as a first
step, when a user clicks on an item in our list, we're going to show a
pop-up message with the position of that item in the list.
We're going to display a toast, which is a small pop-up message that
leaves the activity beneath it interactive and visible.
First, let's create a simple toast when the app loads, and then we'll
create one for clicks on the list items.  We'll add our toast code to
the bottom of the onCreate method after we set our adapter.
To create a toast, we need to know the context, text, and duration.
The context is where this toast will run, which for us is the
MainActivity, so we can just use the keyword this since we're in the MainActivity class.
The text is whatever message you want to display.
For us, we'll say Hello toast!  And the duration is either
Toast.LENGTH_SHORT or Toast.LENGTH_LONG.  We'll use Toast.LENGTH_SHORT.
Then the method Toast.makeText takes in those parameters,
and toast.show displays the toast.
If we demo our app, we can see our Hello toast comes up when the app starts.
Now we want to show a toast when a list item is clicked.
To trigger a toast on a click event, we can use an event listener.
An event listener contains a single callback method, which gets called
when a user triggers the event.  What happens is a user clicks on an
item in the list, the listener receives the click event, and then the
listener calls the callback method.  Inside of that callback method is
where we'll put our code to display our toast.
To do this in code, it looks somewhat complex, so let's break it down
step by step.  We have our ListView, and the first thing we need to do
is called the setOnItemClickListener method.
That method accepts one argument of type ClickListener,
so we'll create that with the new keyword.
Then inside that we'll create the onItemClick callback method,
which is where we'll trigger our toast.  One of the parameters for
onItemClick is int i, and that's the position of the item.
So when we create our toast, we're going to display i to show that's
the position of that item in the list.  You can see that for the
context for the toast we used MainActivity.this and not just this as
we did before, and that's because we're inside of the ClickListener,
so we need to tell it to display the toast in our MainActivity.
If we demo our app, we can see that our toast pops up showing the
position of each item in our list.
Thanks for trying Android with us.  Good luck in the final challenges,
and I'll see you in the wrap-up video.
I'm like let's jump over.  Let's jump over.
Add a little pot --- padding to the top of my potting.
Probably --- I can't talk.
Thanks.  I don't know.